<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<items totalitems="183" termsofuse="http://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse" pubdate="Thu, 31 Dec 2015 16:23:16 +0000">
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="7865" subtype="boardgame" collid="9746980">
	<name sortindex="1">10 Days in Africa</name>
		<yearpublished>2003</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1229634.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1229634_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="25"																	maxplaytime="25"																	playingtime="25"																	numowned="1851" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="1634" />			<average value="6.56405" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.22327" />			<stddev value="1.17007" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-11-10 10:51:51" />
	<numplays>5</numplays>			<comment>This game is hard to rate, because I like the educational aspect of learning all the countries, and I really love how the trip planning mechanic and transportation methods work.  My partner is fascinated with trip planning, so this is one of her favourites.  That said, it is heavily luck based, in some games I have drawn and assembled a starting hand that is only 1 or 2 cards away from winning.  Additionally, as a colourblind gamer, I did have some frustrations playing this game as the colours on the cards are not bold enough to easily differentiate.

Update: After further plays I&#039;m lowering my rating further.  Too many of the decisions you must make in the game are arbitrary, where they have equal chance of helping you or not working out at all.  It&#039;s more like a trial and error puzzle solving exercise than a game.  It&#039;s still an enjoyable exercise though!
Update 2: I thought I could deal with it but the colourblind issue continues to frustrate me.  It really sucks when you&#039;ve assembled your whole trip only to find out you used the wrong plane for one connection.
Update 3: We finally just applied some pencil crayon to the green tiles, this helped.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="94246" subtype="boardgame" collid="15239649">
	<name sortindex="1">1812: The Invasion of Canada</name>
		<yearpublished>2012</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1107292.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1107292_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="1946" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="1518" />			<average value="7.41529" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.79519" />			<stddev value="1.2149" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-05-16 11:49:15" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Really like this one, but I don&#039;t get to play it as often as I like. The theme is somewhat unattractive to most of my friends. Need to make an effort to convince folks to play this with me!</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="36522" subtype="boardgame" collid="10065993">
	<name sortindex="1">2 de Mayo</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic335314.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic335314_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="20"																	maxplaytime="20"																	playingtime="20"																	numowned="2227" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="1611" />			<average value="6.99314" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.52345" />			<stddev value="1.23439" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="1" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-05-16 11:36:43" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>A very interesting game.  I really like the simple and elegant way that the movement and combat mechanics work.  This rating is based on 3 plays so far.  At this point, the one downside is that some of the cards are very situational, or don&#039;t seem to lend themselves to good strategies.  The cards definitely seem more clunky than the rest of the game.  It is possible that it may take further plays to find the effectiveness of some of the cards.  Looking forward to further plays. </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="73369" subtype="boardgame" collid="10680251">
	<name sortindex="1">51st State</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1149172.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1149172_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="40"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="3045" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="2209" />			<average value="6.97935" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.59834" />			<stddev value="1.47444" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-01-27 23:30:01" />
	<numplays>15</numplays>			<comment>This is an engine building game with minimal player interaction, just a victory point race.  The rulebook definitely leaves something to be desired, but the game is actually not that complex once you understand the icons and card types.  It seems like a nice step up from the gameplay style and complexity level of San Juan.  There is a learning curve, and the game leaves you with a feeling that there is more depth to explore.  There is some luck based on what cards you get in your opening hand, but there is a significant amount of both strategy and tactics as well.  The theme is there but somewhat thin, the actual functions of the cards are complex enough that you don&#039;t usually spend the extra effort to focus on the theme of the card. So far, the intricacy of the card combos, the number of different cards, and the possibilities of different strategies based on the assymetric factions all provide this game with some serious replay value.  Looking forward to exploring the strategies further.
</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="68448" subtype="boardgame" collid="10645962">
	<name sortindex="1">7 Wonders</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic860217.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic860217_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="7"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="48276" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="39077" />			<average value="7.862" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.78286" />			<stddev value="1.26868" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="1" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-26 22:27:15" />
	<numplays>15</numplays>			<comment>Easy to teach, plays fast and quick, and gives you interesting decisions to make.  It&#039;s a solid game but not mind-blowing.  The box and insert certainly suck though.  This game would be perfect to carry around to a gathering of friends if they had just put it into an appropriately sized box!  It seems this box size was only chosen to justify the over-priced tag.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="38343" subtype="boardgame" collid="10206933">
	<name sortindex="1">Ad Astra</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic383353.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic383353_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="2418" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="2358" />			<average value="6.92054" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.58282" />			<stddev value="1.25705" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-26 22:23:00" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>I&#039;ve played once so far and it was very interesting.  It seems like the type of game that you need to play a few times to try out different strategies and figure out what works the best.  I like that it is a resource collection and expansion game like Settlers, but more strategic, and a better theme.  I also like that it adds a more interesting travel and exploration element than Settlers.  Looking forward to future plays.

Update: After a few more plays, I still enjoy this, but there are a few fiddly rules that can cause problems if you overlook them.  Also, the unpredictability of other players&#039; choices can make it frustrating at times.  I want to try again though. </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="48726" subtype="boardgame" collid="13231296">
	<name sortindex="1">Alien Frontiers</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1657833.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1657833_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="9714" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="9751" />			<average value="7.53908" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.3779" />			<stddev value="1.30853" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-01-09 14:06:36" />
	<numplays>7</numplays>			<comment>solid game, intuitive to learn, and nice colours and components. It makes a great gateway game if you want something a little more challenging than Settlers, as the decisions are often more difficult. There is a lot of bashing the leader though, and the end game can be anti-climactic as it often comes down to who gets the right roll at the right time to end the game. But then again there is a fair amount of skill involved as more experienced players seem to have an advantage, and the more I&#039;ve played this, the more tricky end game moves I&#039;ve seen with cards and switching control of territories. It will still be seeing lots of play I&#039;m sure.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="74" subtype="boardgame" collid="10292067">
	<name sortindex="1">Apples to Apples</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1667682.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1667682_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="4"																	maxplayers="10"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="16748" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="13010" />			<average value="6.05999" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.96193" />			<stddev value="1.68216" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-04-21 18:36:31" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>Great fun for a party, very simple to learn, and bonus marks for the fact that I don&#039;t normally like party games at all.  It can be somewhat entertaining, but it gets boring really fast.

Update: Couldn&#039;t stand it anymore.  The last play was so boring.  Gave it away as a gift.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="92643" subtype="boardgame" collid="12565403">
	<name sortindex="1">Artus</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic947044.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic947044_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="1251" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="801" />			<average value="6.29454" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.92404" />			<stddev value="1.30129" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-10-23 00:03:05" />
	<numplays>12</numplays>			<comment>This game is really fairly abstract, but I prefer abstracts with a light theme like this one. It&#039;s interesting to play, easy to teach, and presents you with tough decisions to make. The spinning table is clever, yet the table position mechanic is reminiscent of other games. Overall it&#039;s fairly light, with a bit of randomness. It plays fairly quickly though, and you can teach it to new players very quickly as well. I would recommend with 2 and 3 as a filler or gateway game.  4 may be too chaotic but I haven&#039;t tried yet.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="72991" subtype="boardgame" collid="10844618">
	<name sortindex="1">Asara</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic745896.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic745896_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="2406" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="1864" />			<average value="7.06922" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.63961" />			<stddev value="1.09054" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-09-11 16:27:20" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>This was my favourite game played at Essen.  I was planning to wait and purchase it once it was released here, but after trying it out, I decided to re-arrange my luggage to fit one more game! I was surprised by how well this scaled to 2 players, it was really fun that way.  The artwork is very nice, and combined with the unusually shaped board it looks impressive when it is all setup.  I love the simple, intuitive ruleset, it is very easy to teach. Another bonus is that downtime between turns is very short, and the game plays fairly quickly.  I think the game is deeper than the simple rules make it seem (especially once the advanced mode is added), but further plays will allow me to judge this better.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="69789" subtype="boardgame" collid="10946045">
	<name sortindex="1">Ascension: Deckbuilding Game</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2382123.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2382123_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="7551" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="7277" />			<average value="7.0779" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.89342" />			<stddev value="1.39107" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="1" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-12-23 23:04:09" />
	<numplays>18</numplays>			<comment>I appreciate the streamlined design, and the quick setup and quick play.  This is one of the few card games that I really like that can fit into my lunch break (I&#039;m getting bored with San Juan so this is much appreciated). There is definitely a significant luck factor, but I feel like each game I discover new depth in the decision making, so it&#039;s too early for me to decide if the amount of luck is too much or just right. I know some people have complaints about the art, there are a few images I don&#039;t love, but overall I really like it, and appreciate the fact that the game has a unique style compared to most other games.

Update: I play this a lot more than my tracked plays indicate, because I don&#039;t track iOS games. Over time, I&#039;ve grown to appreciate the game more, and I think that there is more skill required than some people initially thought, as I seem to have quite an edge over newer players. I&#039;m not crazy about some of the stuff in the expansion sets though. I don&#039;t think more than 1 expansion was needed really, it&#039;s fine with just the original set.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="8051" subtype="boardgame" collid="10275366">
	<name sortindex="1">Attika</name>
		<yearpublished>2003</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic33096.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic33096_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="5216" >
				<rating value="8.5">			<usersrated value="5699" />			<average value="7.0414" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.85014" />			<stddev value="1.23419" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-06-10 10:48:03" />
	<numplays>7</numplays>			<comment>very interesting game.  it&#039;s quite abstract and has some cool puzzle elements to it.  I&#039;ve only tried 2 player so far but it seems like it will scale really well. It&#039;s really helpful to use some beads to keep track of which buildings have been completed on your player board. It would have been nice if they had included some counters for this purpose with the game.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="110" subtype="boardgame" collid="10639540">
	<name sortindex="1">Auf Achse</name>
		<yearpublished>1987</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic348799.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic348799_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="1634" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="1171" />			<average value="6.28658" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.97808" />			<stddev value="1.29914" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="1" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-26 22:29:15" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Played once with 2 players, and it was a little unexciting.  I could see it being a bit better with more players, but it still seems like it will be a bit too simple for me. I would imagine it would be great for families or kids though.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="494" subtype="boardgame" collid="11871634">
	<name sortindex="1">Ave Caesar</name>
		<yearpublished>1989</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic193766.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic193766_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="3336" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="3530" />			<average value="6.64642" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.44496" />			<stddev value="1.38072" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-05-10 09:43:33" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>Not quite as many opportunities for clever plays as I had hoped, and it is fairly luck based compared to Snow Tails which is my favourite racing game. However this game plays quicker and is much easier to teach, which means it is more accessible for non-gamers.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="42444" subtype="boardgame" collid="9659534">
	<name sortindex="1">Batt&#039;l Kha&#039;os</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic474383.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic474383_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="1043" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="575" />			<average value="6.40961" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.89518" />			<stddev value="1.25332" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-07-25 10:22:36" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>I initially rated this an 8, but have lowered the rating slightly after a few games that seemed to be too much determined by luck.  Sometimes one player can get many tiles with 3 or 4 warriors in one corner and the other player will not get any of these tiles.  I still really like this game though!  A really neat, clever design.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="760" subtype="boardgame" collid="9603711">
	<name sortindex="1">Battle Line</name>
		<yearpublished>2000</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic149717.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic149717_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="12399" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="10458" />			<average value="7.42409" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.28626" />			<stddev value="1.2287" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-02-24 15:31:05" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>A fun game, it reminds me a lot of Lost Cities (same designer).  The box is oversized for the amount of components you get, but if you take them out of the box, the game is very portable. The cards are not normal card stock, they&#039;re thicker and much more difficult to riffle shuffle.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="93538" subtype="boardgame" collid="13147714">
	<name sortindex="1">Battleship Galaxies: The Saturn Offensive Game Set</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1692484.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1692484_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="70"																	maxplaytime="70"																	playingtime="70"																	numowned="2193" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="1003" />			<average value="6.75909" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.21929" />			<stddev value="1.38195" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-05-26 14:35:56" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>There are certainly some things I love about this game but overall there is something lacking. Also, the selection and customization of your fleet is a bit fiddly and increases the playtime as well. Perhaps this game will improve with expansions, but I&#039;m not sure if I&#039;ll bother expanding it. I have other games of this style that I love more so it&#039;s hard to imagine playing this enough to justify an expansion.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="10547" subtype="boardgame" collid="11762509">
	<name sortindex="1">Betrayal at House on the Hill</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic289668.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic289668_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="20899" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="15162" />			<average value="7.09916" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.94068" />			<stddev value="1.49287" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-05-16 11:45:08" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Not really my style of game but Kelsey loves the story and traitor aspects of the game. For me the limited decision making and tedious set up and reading scenarios and checking the rule book means the fun to work ratio is not quite right.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="2453" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548568">
	<name sortindex="1">Blokus</name>
		<yearpublished>2000</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic153979.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic153979_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="20"																	maxplaytime="20"																	playingtime="20"																	numowned="17162" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="14578" />			<average value="6.97952" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.88307" />			<stddev value="1.22436" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-03-17 09:36:15" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>I previously had this rated lower than Ingenious as I&#039;ve been playing Ingenious more often lately at the request of my family.  But I recently played Blokus Duo which reminded me how fun this game is.  I like thinking about the best way to use the different pieces, and the decision making is more interesting and requires more thought and strategy than Ingenious.  So I&#039;ve bumped the rating up a bit and am looking forward to getting the 4 player version to the table again. </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="16395" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548814">
	<name sortindex="1">Blokus Duo</name>
		<yearpublished>2005</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1086904.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1086904_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="15"																	maxplaytime="15"																	playingtime="15"																	numowned="5262" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="3833" />			<average value="6.90698" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.66751" />			<stddev value="1.18809" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2010-02-25 15:11:22" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>I don&#039;t like this as much as the 4 player game, but it&#039;s still a fun game, in a portable size.  Lately I&#039;ve been playing this with my partner to help her get better at Blokus in general.  It&#039;s better than I remembered, and it&#039;s rekindled my interest in the 4 player game, so I&#039;ve bumped up both ratings a little bit.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="1293" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548839">
	<name sortindex="1">Boggle</name>
		<yearpublished>1987</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic152911.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic152911_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="8"																	minplaytime="10"																	maxplaytime="10"																	playingtime="10"																	numowned="6294" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="4693" />			<average value="6.18178" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.04775" />			<stddev value="1.59275" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="1" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-02-06 12:08:59" />
	<numplays>5</numplays>			<comment>I played this addictively in grade school and it has been a favourite ever since.  For now I&#039;m a bit bored of it, but it will always serve as a useful filler on a game night with casual gamer types.

My partner learned it recently and she really likes it, so Boggle might be seeing some more frequent plays again.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="11" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548441">
	<name sortindex="1">Bohnanza</name>
		<yearpublished>1997</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic69366.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic69366_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="7"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="32827" >
				<rating value="5.5">			<usersrated value="24448" />			<average value="7.08837" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.0075" />			<stddev value="1.27755" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-04-24 16:27:22" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>This was another early Eurogame purchase for me, back when the cards were still in german.  Affectionately known as &quot;the bean game&quot; amongst my family and friends, this gets requested and played often, and some of my friends have gone on to buy their own copy.  Easy to teach to non-gamers, and very very portable!

Overall though, I feel this game hasn&#039;t aged well, I rarely want to play it in comparison to other card games.  I would rather play Citadels or No Thanks.

Update: gave it to my sister as a gift.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="10997" subtype="boardgame" collid="10643703">
	<name sortindex="1">Boomtown</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic49310.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic49310_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="2755" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="2336" />			<average value="6.58517" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.32718" />			<stddev value="1.1995" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-10-08 00:20:15" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>A fun game, with an unusual bid mechanic. Not sure if it is exciting enough to see repeat plays though. Interested in trying this again.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="69120" subtype="boardgame" collid="12314059">
	<name sortindex="1">Cadwallon: City of Thieves</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1247236.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1247236_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="2158" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="1233" />			<average value="6.36495" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.00718" />			<stddev value="1.44398" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-06-19 17:06:34" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>Based on first impressions after one play, this was surprisingly good.  The ruleset is simple, and the play is more tactical than strategic. The dice rolls mean that there is some luck involved but it usually created some fun or tense moments. The board artwork is gorgeous and the different abilities of each team member are interesting. My first play was with 2 players and I thought the board would be too big and open, and that we would be able to easily avoid each other.  That wasn&#039;t the case at all, there were enough opportunities for us to block and mess with each other, and opportunities for clever or surprising plays too. Both of us felt that it would be even more fun with more players though. I&#039;m definitely going to be upgrading to the pre-painted minis, and I&#039;ll probably upgrade the action tokens to glass beads in each team colour. </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="822" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548260">
	<name sortindex="1">Carcassonne</name>
		<yearpublished>2000</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2337577.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2337577_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="72625" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="54722" />			<average value="7.43656" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.34126" />			<stddev value="1.29817" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-02-17 15:56:28" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>I have a fond spot for this game, since it was one of, if not the, first Eurogame I ever played, and helped introduce me to the world of board games, boardgamegeek, and Meeples!  I like Hunters and Gatherers a bit better, but they are very similar. There is always discussion about confusion over the farming rules, I didn&#039;t mind them myself but I did find it caused some confusion when teaching the game.

Update: I got this for my iPod, and playing it after having played Hunters and Gatherers more lately, the original just hasn&#039;t held up as well in comparison.  A friend of mine has borrowed my copy for a long time so I think I&#039;ll just let her keep it.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="4390" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548264">
	<name sortindex="1">Carcassonne: Hunters and Gatherers</name>
		<yearpublished>2002</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2428656.png</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2428656_t.png</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="10727" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="8899" />			<average value="7.15587" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.99986" />			<stddev value="1.25102" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-12-23 23:06:44" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>This game is very close to the original Carcassonne, but I rate it just slightly higher because I like the theme better, and the hunting rules are much easier to explain to new players than the farming rules.  Also, I really enjoyed how the fish, rivers and lakes worked, it&#039;s much more interesting than building roads.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="655" subtype="boardgame" collid="9679522">
	<name sortindex="1">Castle</name>
		<yearpublished>2000</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic9642.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic9642_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="1983" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="1468" />			<average value="6.12283" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.90746" />			<stddev value="1.33544" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-11-30 10:05:17" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>The mechanic is clever, and reminds me of Magic the Gathering a bit in its concepts (bounce effects, analyzing card advantage, noticing combos).  Also, the card effects are often tied to the theme in a clever or funny way.  But the main problem I noticed was that many times, you could not find a beneficial way to use the card effect, so you spend a lot of time reading different card effects only to play them with no effect.  This leaves the game feeling a bit boring at times.  This is based only on playing with 2 players, it may play a bit better with more players. </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="84876" subtype="boardgame" collid="12850377">
	<name sortindex="5">The Castles of Burgundy</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1176894.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1176894_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="22891" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="17037" />			<average value="8.08941" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.96454" />			<stddev value="1.23255" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-26 22:08:17" />
	<numplays>10</numplays>			<comment>I really enjoy the mechanics on this one, but the components and graphic design do leave something to be desired. Some of the colours are a bit tricky for colourblind players, and with no draw bags included, there are a lot of tiny hexes that need to be shuffled in order to set this one up. The graphics seem the worst out of the recent Feld games, but I think the gameplay is up there with his best games.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="2807" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548428">
	<name sortindex="1">Catan: 5-6 Player Extension</name>
		<yearpublished>1996</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2420287.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2420287_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="5"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="22505" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="9875" />			<average value="7.03423" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.84097" />			<stddev value="1.55955" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-04-02 13:00:51" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>I&#039;ve played this a couple of times. I&#039;m not a big fan of Settlers, but it seems better with 4 than with 5 or 6.  That said, I&#039;ll hang onto this for those rare occasions when I need to accomodate a large number of casual gamers who like Settlers.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="21293" subtype="boardgame" collid="11399731">
	<name sortindex="1">Celtica</name>
		<yearpublished>2006</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic643670.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic643670_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="719" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="621" />			<average value="5.55711" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.51921" />			<stddev value="1.48938" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-01-09 14:18:31" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>pretty simple game, yet still pretty interesting. I think there is a lot of luck involved. This rating takes into account the beautiful artwork and the family/kid friendly nature of the game.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="171" subtype="boardgame" collid="9552747">
	<name sortindex="1">Chess</name>
		<yearpublished>1475</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic260745.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic260745_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="22352" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="17387" />			<average value="7.09514" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.9419" />			<stddev value="1.84305" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-12-23 23:33:53" />
	<numplays>26</numplays>			<comment>A great game, nothing really wrong with it, aside from the fact that most players take it quite seriously and it requires too much time investment to play it really well.  I recently read a good book that definitely improved my play skills, but I would rather devote further time to the many board games out there.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="2386" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548833">
	<name sortindex="1">Chinese Checkers</name>
		<yearpublished>1893</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic113974.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic113974_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="2989" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="2762" />			<average value="5.10655" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.15812" />			<stddev value="1.49296" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-11-11 21:46:05" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>A very simple abstract that scales well from 2 to 6 players, although with more players it gets more chaotic.  It&#039;s not especially exciting or deep but it&#039;s still enjoyable to play, and definitely better than standard checkers.  Useful for gaming with non-gamers or kids, the rules are very easy to teach.  I definitely wouldn&#039;t pay much money for this game but it is easy to find for a few dollars.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="478" subtype="boardgame" collid="9554237">
	<name sortindex="1">Citadels</name>
		<yearpublished>2000</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic636868.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic636868_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="8"																	minplaytime="20"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="41315" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="32247" />			<average value="7.17753" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.09772" />			<stddev value="1.23974" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2010-04-26 09:26:48" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>This is not the usual type of game I like (I&#039;m not very good at it!), so I might normally rate it lower, however the portability, combined with the ability to accomodate up to 8 players, and the fact that it is easy to teach to new players, definitely makes this a handy game to have in my collection, and certainly increases the rating for me.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="36932" subtype="boardgame" collid="9604772">
	<name sortindex="1">Claustrophobia</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic570518.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic570518_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="6598" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="4755" />			<average value="7.67426" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.35562" />			<stddev value="1.36296" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-06-10 10:46:57" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>This is a very solid, interesting, unique, challenging, and attractive game.  It has more replayability than you would expect as well, because the random tile draws make each scenario play very differently every time.  I also love the components, and the box stores everything well. Read my review for more details.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="100527" subtype="boardgame" collid="13520747">
	<name sortindex="1">Claustrophobia: De Profundis</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2244827.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2244827_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="2286" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="497" />			<average value="8.18112" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.57347" />			<stddev value="1.19332" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-02-25 10:49:20" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>Great expansion! See my comments in the main game entry for more details.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="1294" subtype="boardgame" collid="9547991">
	<name sortindex="1">Clue</name>
		<yearpublished>1949</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic884234.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic884234_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="15976" >
				<rating value="5.5">			<usersrated value="10604" />			<average value="5.62309" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.54991" />			<stddev value="1.47459" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2010-12-06 10:55:23" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>I like the deduction aspect of the game, and the theme is fun, but the roll and move mechanic is the weak spot.

Update: Traded away.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="5782" subtype="boardgame" collid="11546492">
	<name sortindex="1">Coloretto</name>
		<yearpublished>2003</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic149765.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic149765_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="14458" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="12017" />			<average value="6.98477" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.88561" />			<stddev value="1.11931" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-02-24 15:42:07" />
	<numplays>17</numplays>			<comment>This is a fun one.  Simple to explain, tough decisions to make, and opportunities to screw over your opponents!  I also appreciate the fact that they accomodated colorblind players by using visual textures on the card.  Looking forward to introducing this to my friends and family.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="27746" subtype="boardgame" collid="11976767">
	<name sortindex="1">Colosseum</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic182188.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic182188_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="6216" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="6255" />			<average value="7.18636" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.99493" />			<stddev value="1.2325" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-01-14 12:01:49" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Had a great time playing this. Great components too. As usual for a Kramer game, it has a delicate balance of rules simplicity and tough decisions. Somewhat reminiscent of Princes of Florence, but more intuitive for new players. The big difference though is that your final production is the only thing that really matters for scoring. This definitely makes the game unique but I&#039;m not sure if I like that style of game better than the usual victory point accumulation. I would like to play this again!</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="39463" subtype="boardgame" collid="9650616">
	<name sortindex="1">Cosmic Encounter</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1521633.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1521633_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="17055" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="14459" />			<average value="7.60784" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.46702" />			<stddev value="1.68099" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-11-19 23:03:26" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>							</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="54998" subtype="boardgame" collid="9708156">
	<name sortindex="1">Cyclades</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic584779.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic584779_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="9983" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="9548" />			<average value="7.53214" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.35501" />			<stddev value="1.31839" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-06-28 17:29:00" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>So far I&#039;ve only tried it once with 2 players, but it was fun, and seemed to have a fair bit of depth.  There were a few rules hiccups, and the rulebook could have been laid out better and contained more comprehensive information, but we got through it with the help of a posted FAQ.  I think it is a game that will be better with more people, so I&#039;m looking forward to trying that.  Rating could go up or down based on further plays.

Update: After further plays, I find the endgame comes up to quickly and then everyone tries to figure out how to stop someone from winning. It also seems like the kind of game where everyone needs to know how to play otherwise it unbalances the game too much. Not ideal for the type of play groups I usually have.  Putting it up for trade.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="35935" subtype="boardgame" collid="9819037">
	<name sortindex="1">Day &amp; Night</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic369599.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic369599_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="766" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="637" />			<average value="6.61706" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.00382" />			<stddev value="1.46197" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-03-24 08:34:48" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>The theme and card artwork are really beautiful, and this game definitely captured my partner Kelsey&#039;s interest because of this.  However the actual gameplay seems like it doesn&#039;t live up to the theme.  The card decks are quite large so there is considerable variation in the quality of your hands, and there are many spells that seem less than useful most of the time. Because of this you sometimes have a hand full of spells you can&#039;t use, but to draw more cards you need to waste a turn moving around, even if there is no positional advantage to be gained.  I may increase the rating after further plays, but the initial plays seemed to be determined in part by the luck of the draw.

Update: After another 2 plays, the endgame seemed to drag on slowly, we decided to trade it.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="16991" subtype="boardgame" collid="14937546">
	<name sortindex="1">Deflexion</name>
	<originalname>Khet: The Laser Game</originalname>	<yearpublished>2005</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic447431.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic447431_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="20"																	maxplaytime="20"																	playingtime="20"																	numowned="3049" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="2162" />			<average value="6.60255" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.30004" />			<stddev value="1.36839" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-06-05 08:09:40" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>An interesting abstract game. The laser is a bit of a gimmick but it works and makes for interesting puzzle solving on your turn. Kelsey seems to like this a bit more than me as she enjoys practicing her visual-spatial skills.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="542" subtype="boardgame" collid="13119831">
	<name sortindex="1">Democrazy</name>
		<yearpublished>2000</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic714318.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic714318_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="4"																	maxplayers="10"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="1288" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="1022" />			<average value="5.50289" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.49042" />			<stddev value="1.41894" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-05-16 11:47:41" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Played only once so far. Chaotic but pretty fun. Need to try it again.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="483" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548834">
	<name sortindex="1">Diplomacy</name>
		<yearpublished>1959</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic288149.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic288149_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="7"																	minplaytime="360"																	maxplaytime="360"																	playingtime="360"																	numowned="13591" >
				<rating value="9.5">			<usersrated value="8822" />			<average value="7.08838" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.89277" />			<stddev value="1.91058" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-05-09 19:22:13" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>I play frequently by forum. I also own a vintage copy of the game but have only managed to play once, and we didn&#039;t quite finish.  I greatly enjoy the tactical calculations, and seem to do fairly well at this game.  This is very difficult to organize and play in person, so my rating includes the consideration that it can be played online over a longer period of time. Also, I think I prefer taking the time to work out my moves carefully, and you can be pressed for time to negotiate and calculate in a live game depending on the pace.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="86270" subtype="boardgame" collid="11797064">
	<name sortindex="1">Discover India</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1134624.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1134624_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="114" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="104" />			<average value="5.3" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.47394" />			<stddev value="1.40021" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="1" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-05-16 11:39:43" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>The main mechanic of set collection and tile placement on an interesting player mat is good, but the rest of the game feels tacked on. It doesn&#039;t facilitate the discovery of India because the location cards you sometimes earn do not always correspond to the location of your pawn.  It seems like something is missing or was changed halfway through development.  The core of the game is enjoyable though so I&#039;ll probably play it from time to time.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="39856" subtype="boardgame" collid="11510527">
	<name sortindex="1">Dixit</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic455883.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic455883_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="29611" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="23461" />			<average value="7.4019" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.31036" />			<stddev value="1.35321" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-10-28 19:18:37" />
	<numplays>13</numplays>			<comment>This is not the type of game I usually enjoy, but it is pretty fun, interesting, and the pictures are very beautiful and intriguing.  It gets your mind working in a different way than most board games.  My only concern is how much replayability the game will have once you&#039;ve seen all the pictures a few times. This will probably be one of my go-to games (along with No Thanks) when I need something simple, unintimidating, and easy to teach to non-gamers.  I appreciate that it can accommodate 6 players.

Update: For some reason, I got tired of this quite quickly.  It has no replay value for me now that the novelty wore off.  My partner is still enchanted with it though.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="119407" subtype="boardgame" collid="15977837">
	<name sortindex="1">Dixit Jinx</name>
		<yearpublished>2012</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1258844.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1258844_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="15"																	maxplaytime="15"																	playingtime="15"																	numowned="1409" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="756" />			<average value="5.91255" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.71094" />			<stddev value="1.52903" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-09-11 16:45:09" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>							</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="92828" subtype="boardgame" collid="14341188">
	<name sortindex="1">Dixit Odyssey</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic918568.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic918568_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="12"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="9915" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="7374" />			<average value="7.55886" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.34209" />			<stddev value="1.32329" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-01-14 12:09:20" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>The new score board is ugly, but the new card art is alright. adding more players just makes this game more boring for me. see my comment and rating in the main game entry for more details.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="36218" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548062">
	<name sortindex="1">Dominion</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic394356.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic394356_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="58046" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="46107" />			<average value="7.75581" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.67183" />			<stddev value="1.4301" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="1" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-26 22:29:01" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>I played this addictively for a few months, and I appreciate the elegance of the base set.  As the expansions came out I began to feel overwhelmed and tired of it a bit.  I still appreciate the base game for its innovative design.  Once you get familiar with what cards are good and what strategies or combos work well together, a lot of the excitement of discovery is lost, and it feels more boring. It seems like this is the reason they have come out with so many expansion sets.  I still appreciate the design of this game, but I never feel like playing it.  I know I will never play this game as much as I did when I first played the hell out of the base set.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="66098" subtype="boardgame" collid="10546984">
	<name sortindex="1">Dominion: Alchemy</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic698779.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic698779_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="12082" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="5988" />			<average value="7.01703" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.82552" />			<stddev value="1.46932" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-01-04 16:13:09" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>While I haven&#039;t had a chance to try all of the Alchemy cards yet, I can already say for sure that I like this set better than Seaside.  Maybe it&#039;s the theme, maybe it&#039;s the fact that it has succeeded in re-sparking my interest in Dominion much more than Seaside did, or maybe it&#039;s just the fact that it came with an un-overwhelming number of new cards, in a smaller box and a more modest price. Or perhaps all of the above.  I haven&#039;t found myself playing Dominion constantly like I did when it came out, but I think Alchemy will inspire me to keep playing occasionally.

Update: It hasn&#039;t really.  I can&#039;t blame Dominion entirely, as there are so many interesting games coming out, but I haven&#039;t felt inspired to play Dominion in quite awhile.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="40834" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548063">
	<name sortindex="1">Dominion: Intrigue</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic460011.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic460011_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="27366" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="19931" />			<average value="7.83917" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.72669" />			<stddev value="1.35598" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-06-28 17:29:25" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>This has some of my favourite Dominion cards, but also has some really lame ones as well (wishing well is useless!).  It would have been a lot better as a small, more affordable expansion with more consistent card quality.  I rate this slightly less than the base game both because of the inconsistency of the card quality, but also because I appreciate the elegance and simplicity of the base game card set. I would still recommend this expansion to Dominion players though because there are some really great cards.</comment>	<conditiontext>cards have some wear from use (no sleeves), but are still quite playable.</conditiontext>			</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="51811" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548087">
	<name sortindex="1">Dominion: Seaside</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic543471.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic543471_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="18980" >
				<rating value="5.5">			<usersrated value="10219" />			<average value="8.10232" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.90256" />			<stddev value="1.19204" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-04-07 10:12:10" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>It&#039;s hard to rate this one, as it came out at a time when I was starting to tire of Dominion.  Additionally, I was really not a fan of the gimmicky extra components.  It felt like they were included as a way to justify charging full price for an expansion.  That said, since I was already tiring of Dominion and the format of this expansion turned me off somewhat, I haven&#039;t really played this enough to evaluate all of the cards thoroughly.  I don&#039;t think they are worth the cost of this expansion though.

Update: traded it away.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="13004" subtype="boardgame" collid="9558155">
	<name sortindex="5">The Downfall of Pompeii</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1685805.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1685805_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="5411" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="5269" />			<average value="7.14813" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.9433" />			<stddev value="1.11339" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-02-28 10:26:36" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>An interesting game.  I was expecting the 2 player game to be a bit dull as multi-player games sometimes don&#039;t scale well down to 2 players, but this one worked well. Both phases of the game involved very interesting decision making, and it had a nice balance of skill and luck. The rules were fairly easy to explain so I&#039;m planning to introduce this to my casual gaming groups. Looking forward to seeing how it plays with more people.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="2537" subtype="boardgame" collid="12580210">
	<name sortindex="1">Draco &amp; Co</name>
		<yearpublished>2001</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic9650.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic9650_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="639" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="332" />			<average value="5.49729" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.49714" />			<stddev value="1.41045" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-07-25 10:22:47" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Rated based on 1 play with 4 players.  This was easy to learn and definitely got some laughs even before we finished reading the rules.  The theme is great, and well integrated with the mechanics. The gameplay was a bit chaotic, and depends on luck of the draw as you may not get the cards you need to improve your position. I&#039;m interested to see how this plays with 6.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="3208" subtype="boardgame" collid="10113493">
	<name sortindex="1">Dragonland</name>
		<yearpublished>2002</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic295454.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic295454_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="1271" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="806" />			<average value="6.35122" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.94049" />			<stddev value="1.1998" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2010-11-18 13:29:31" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>So far this is my favourite Knizia game.  The art has an old-school feel, and the components are great, especially the dice tower! The game is a classic set collection game, with a roll and move mechanic. But because of the special dice, action tokens, and the fact that you choose 2 of your 3 pawns to move each turn, it is nowhere near as random as you would expect for a roll and move game.  It definitely rewards skillful play, and so far Kelsey has destroyed me at it both times we&#039;ve played.  We&#039;ve played once with 2 and once with 4.  I preferred the 4 player game because there was more competition for treasure, but Kelsey preferred the 2 player game because for her there was too much downtime between turns in the 4 player (partly due to one player with bad AP).  I think next time we&#039;ll try it with 3.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="102237" subtype="boardgame" collid="13395591">
	<name sortindex="1">Drako</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1043729.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1043729_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="1504" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="1311" />			<average value="6.78709" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.31488" />			<stddev value="1.22689" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-06-19 17:29:51" />
	<numplays>11</numplays>			<comment>A great, thematic asymmetrical game. Really it&#039;s like an abstract game in some ways but they did a great job with the theme. It is really easy to teach, it plays fast, and players seem to catch on quickly. Players I&#039;ve introduced it too have requested further games. The components are both attractive and effective. They&#039;re easy to differentiate and help to draw players into the theme. Game endings seem to be close, but sometimes feel as if they are partially determined by the way the decks were dealt. Replayability might be the only concern, but so far I&#039;m still getting a kick out of it.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="23107" subtype="boardgame" collid="9599448">
	<name sortindex="1">Drakon (third edition)</name>
		<yearpublished>2006</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic153409.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic153409_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="40"																	maxplaytime="40"																	playingtime="40"																	numowned="2592" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="2361" />			<average value="6.56943" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.30026" />			<stddev value="1.35574" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-03-17 09:32:41" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>Great game, I love the elegant design and the unique tile abilities.  I like the way you can set up combos or break your opponents&#039; combos.  It seems to scale well regardless of the number of players, but the more players there are, the more chaotic it is.  There is definitely a luck factor involved in winning, but for me the fun of this game is finding clever plays, regardless of who wins. The theme is also very fun, new players get a kick out it when I explain the human eating dragon.  This is one of my partner Kelsey&#039;s favourite games.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="376" subtype="boardgame" collid="9587372">
	<name sortindex="1">DruidenWalzer</name>
		<yearpublished>1999</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic34192.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic34192_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="1145" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="689" />			<average value="5.95695" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.70959" />			<stddev value="1.50963" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2010-06-21 10:37:58" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>I love the art style and theme, this is the best feature of the game.  At first it takes some time to get your head around how the game mechanics work, but once this is done, it plays fairly easily, aside from some brain burning pauses for analysis.  Once you learn the game, the unique mechanics become a positive aspect of the game.  There may be too much luck involved in determining the winner though, I need more plays to see if this rating will hold.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="1555" subtype="boardgame" collid="9795243">
	<name sortindex="1">Dungeon Dice</name>
		<yearpublished>1977</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic229081.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic229081_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="560" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="308" />			<average value="5.86146" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.59939" />			<stddev value="1.38471" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2010-02-01 10:41:04" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>I picked this up used.  It has fun vintage-y art with a cool theme and really cool components.  The gameplay is simple and easy to learn, but does not have much strategy.  I&#039;m not a big fan of push-your-luck dice rolling games, but this will serve well as my 1 go-to game of this genre, and it might be fun to play if I have kids some day.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="12995" subtype="boardgame" collid="9554245">
	<name sortindex="1">Dungeon Twister</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic97630.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic97630_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="6531" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="4948" />			<average value="6.87584" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.66439" />			<stddev value="1.50949" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="1" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-05-16 11:37:12" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>This is a real brain burner with a fun theme and well designed mechanics.  The components are a bit on the weak side but they&#039;re tolerable.  I need to play this more.  Rating may go up a notch after further plays.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="59946" subtype="boardgame" collid="11201838">
	<name sortindex="1">Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Castle Ravenloft Board Game</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic660244.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic660244_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="9710" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="6060" />			<average value="7.01241" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.79301" />			<stddev value="1.43218" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-03-06 10:57:43" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>The first initial play was pretty fun, the player powers seem well designed and exciting, but some of the rules seem a bit odd or unintuitive. I need additional plays before rating it.

Update: After a completely frustrating play of Scenario 4, where the poorly written scenario and rulebook interfered with having a good time, and the monster slaying got boring and repetitive, I&#039;m putting this up for trade.  I feel that other games do a better job of providing what I was looking for here (co-op isn&#039;t an important feature to me).

Update: math traded.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="72125" subtype="boardgame" collid="12594732">
	<name sortindex="1">Eclipse</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1173341.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1173341_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="200"																	playingtime="200"																	numowned="18365" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="16514" />			<average value="8.06505" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.922" />			<stddev value="1.48041" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-08-20 17:52:54" />
	<numplays>20</numplays>			<comment>This game is harder to find time to play than much of my collection, yet I&#039;ve managed to play it quite a few times. This is one of those rare games where I appreciate just about everything in the game. Many other games just have that one or 2 things that bother you, whether it&#039;s the graphic design or one of the game mechanisms. Eclipse seems to get it just right on all fronts. It&#039;s clear a lot of love, time, and effort was put into the design, playtesting, and production. One of the things I appreciate the most is how intuitive the mechanics are. The rules are quite streamlined, and it is very easy to teach. And ship customization is really fun.

The only (very minor) downsides:
- It seems better with more players, but the play length can push the limits a bit. With the wrong set of gamers (AP or just chatty), a game with 4-6 players can get dragged out a bit. The estimated game time of 30/player assumes fast and focused play from all.
- I don&#039;t think Plasma Missiles are unfairly powerful like some others do, but I do think that with multiple plasma missiles in a ship build, the number of dice you end up throwing gets a bit ridiculous. I don&#039;t think it&#039;s overpowered, but it just seems a bit silly in comparison to the maturity of the rest of the design. I sometimes wonder if it would have been better to give them an energy cost of 1. But on the other hand this may have reduced some of the exciting moments of the game.

I&#039;m really looking forward to seeing what they add in with the expansion.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="112686" subtype="boardgame" collid="16028865">
	<name sortindex="1">Epic Spell Wars of the Battle Wizards: Duel at Mt. Skullzfyre</name>
		<yearpublished>2012</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1170265.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1170265_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="3603" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="2016" />			<average value="6.66651" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.29104" />			<stddev value="1.5854" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="1" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-05-16 11:38:47" />
	<numplays>5</numplays>			<comment>A similar vibe to King of Tokyo, but more random and less strategic. Also, the game length can vary wildly, depending on whether someone sweeps the 2 points in a row, or the other extreme, we all get to 1 point before anyone gets 2 points. The art is amazing though, and the spell names are funny and fun to create and read aloud. These factors alone make the game worth playing.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="1159" subtype="boardgame" collid="9552606">
	<name sortindex="1">Evo</name>
		<yearpublished>2001</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic158904.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic158904_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="3497" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="3972" />			<average value="6.91244" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.6854" />			<stddev value="1.20103" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-08-18 21:29:19" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>This one was a big hit with my family and friends, and got played constantly for awhile.  I got bored of it and lent it out to a friend, and have just recently received it back.  Perhaps I&#039;ll be more interested in replaying it soon.

Update: Played this twice recently, and was reminded what a well designed game this is.  It always seems to go over well with other players, the theme is fun and new players are able to understand the mechanics fairly quickly.  I&#039;m still a bit bored of it myself but this game deserves a good rating for being such a consistent hit with new players. </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="40628" subtype="boardgame" collid="9569494">
	<name sortindex="1">Finca</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic433784.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic433784_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="4756" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="5009" />			<average value="7.04879" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.84251" />			<stddev value="1.16309" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-11-30 10:00:37" />
	<numplays>8</numplays>			<comment>This is a fairly simple game, that consists of manipulating a rondel to attempt to collect the different types of produce in order to complete deliveries. This is an enjoyable game but doesn&#039;t break any new ground (aside from the cool wooden fruit).  It worked quite well for a quiet 2 player game when neither of us were feeling confrontational, and it was interesting enough that we both wanted a second game immediately afterward to try to improve on our scores.  Further plays with more players have also been enjoyable, this would potentially make a good gateway game.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="15511" subtype="boardgame" collid="9598618">
	<name sortindex="1">Fjords</name>
		<yearpublished>2005</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic250459.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic250459_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="2794" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="2510" />			<average value="6.70429" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.43143" />			<stddev value="1.23964" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-02-25 10:37:44" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>My initial impression is that this is a surprisingly great game for such a small and affordable package.  It is simple and straightforward but has interesting decisions and tactics to think about.  I haven&#039;t played enough to give a full analysis, but so far this looks like it will get a lot more plays than I expected it would.  Rating may go up or down based on further play.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="65334" subtype="boardgame" collid="10409577">
	<name sortindex="1">Flash Duel</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic648115.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic648115_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="5"																	maxplaytime="5"																	playingtime="5"																	numowned="332" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="291" />			<average value="6.77254" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.81235" />			<stddev value="1.68416" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-01-17 10:36:41" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>after the initial play with my partner, I thought it was alright, but she didn&#039;t find enough depth in it for her, and will likely be reluctant to try it again.  It&#039;s quick and easy to teach though, so I introduced it to another friend of mine.  How fun the game is seems to depend on which characters are facing off, and how well the player utilizes the character&#039;s special abilities.  For now I&#039;ll rate it a 7, but there is potential for the rating to go up if I get a chance to play it more against the same opponent.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="2290" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548932">
	<name sortindex="1">Ghosts!</name>
		<yearpublished>1980</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic489078.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic489078_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="15"																	maxplaytime="15"																	playingtime="15"																	numowned="1345" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="1063" />			<average value="6.39677" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.02602" />			<stddev value="1.36462" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2010-06-21 10:33:13" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>This is a nostalgic game from my childhood.  The gameplay is very simplistic and a bit boring, but the components are really cool (glow in the dark ghost pawns!) and it has a neat bluffing aspect.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="40770" subtype="boardgame" collid="10499026">
	<name sortindex="5">The Golden City</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic689677.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic689677_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="1801" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="1222" />			<average value="6.7012" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.25955" />			<stddev value="1.18738" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-07-04 10:24:14" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>I really like this type of game.  After only one play, I&#039;m looking forward to trying it again so that I can adapt my strategy based on what I learned in my first play. The only downside is that with a player count of 3-4 there are limited opportunities to get it to the table.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="3139" subtype="boardgame" collid="10571837">
	<name sortindex="1">Goldland</name>
		<yearpublished>2002</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic238750.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic238750_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="1251" >
				<rating value="8.5">			<usersrated value="1153" />			<average value="6.70364" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.24157" />			<stddev value="1.23772" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-09-29 16:20:14" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>A fun game with great, simple mechanics that are thematically intuitive.  I really love Kramer&#039;s design style.  This rating could go higher but I&#039;ve only played with 2 so far and think it could be better with more.  There is a possibility of downtime though with too many, maybe 3 might be a good number to try.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="66587" subtype="boardgame" collid="10541815">
	<name sortindex="1">GOSU</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic821651.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic821651_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="2522" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="2197" />			<average value="6.66208" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.34365" />			<stddev value="1.46999" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-09-18 12:21:51" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>I really like the artwork and style of this game, as well as the unique gameplay.  I really enjoy figuring out the interesting interactions between the cards.  However after my first few plays, the one issue I noticed is the sometimes lengthy time a turn takes, caused by the need for heavy analysis of cards in the discard, cards in play under your opponent&#039;s control, and cards in your hand.  Hopefully further plays will allow the game to be learned well enough that this issue will be reduced or eliminated.  I&#039;ll also be trying to sit side by side instead of across the table so that it is easier to read the opponent&#039;s cards in play. If the slow playing time goes down my rating will go up.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="93" subtype="boardgame" collid="12474477">
	<name sortindex="4">El Grande</name>
		<yearpublished>1995</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic180538.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic180538_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="15893" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="16282" />			<average value="7.82632" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.71368" />			<stddev value="1.34135" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-02-11 11:16:46" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>A really tense battle of wits.  A simple, elegant ruleset.  A classic beauty that I&#039;ve sadly only had a chance to play a few times.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="73863" subtype="boardgame" collid="11263003">
	<name sortindex="1">Grimoire</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1040235.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1040235_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="1773" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="1044" />			<average value="6.53204" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.09625" />			<stddev value="1.17223" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-11-10 13:48:09" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>Tried this once with 2 players and it was fun and easy to learn. We only messed up one rule which was how the rogue worked.  However I think this game will be more fun with 3 or 4 so I&#039;m going to wait to try that before rating it.

Update: Had a chance to try it with 4, it was fun, and everyone enjoyed it.  Solid game.  The only real issue is the tiny size and type of font that was chosen, it makes the cards really difficult to read.

Update 2: The new Z-man version is much easier to read and has better component quality.  And it expands the game to 5 players!

Update 3: Tried it with 3 players, and there were many times when the timing came out fairly random due to accidentally picking the same spell as someone else. It is a bit hard to control the outcome if you can&#039;t guess what your opponents will pick. I can&#039;t decide what to think of this, because in some ways you want enough players for their to be some collision, as it&#039;s one of the main mechanics of the game, but on the other hand, the more collision there is, the less control you feel you have over winning and losing.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="116" subtype="boardgame" collid="9804108">
	<name sortindex="1">Guillotine</name>
		<yearpublished>1998</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic143139.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic143139_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="17045" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="13167" />			<average value="6.53393" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.44222" />			<stddev value="1.26791" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="1" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-10-28 19:19:27" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>I have only played this twice so far, so this rating is based on first impressions.  This is not a game I would normally buy, but it was requested by some of my friends who are into politics, because of the theme.  I was really pleased with the card artwork. The gameplay was simplistic and random, as I expected, but it seemed to have more fun potential than I thought it would.  I need additional plays to decide what I think of the gameplay.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="19100" subtype="boardgame" collid="13813231">
	<name sortindex="1">Hacienda</name>
		<yearpublished>2005</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic121746.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic121746_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="3432" >
				<rating value="8.5">			<usersrated value="3565" />			<average value="6.99486" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.73896" />			<stddev value="1.20573" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-11-19 12:41:39" />
	<numplays>5</numplays>			<comment>Another Kramer beauty. In addition to my tracked plays I&#039;ve also played many times on Yucata. The game is almost an abstract game with a theme that is thin but helps connect the mechanics well. At times the two scoring rounds can create a runaway leader, but most times the games still seem quite close.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="34707" subtype="boardgame" collid="9554247">
	<name sortindex="5">The Hanging Gardens</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic580143.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic580143_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="1559" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="1846" />			<average value="6.78622" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.42505" />			<stddev value="1.20079" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-04-07 10:12:22" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>I normally don&#039;t mind a thinly themed abstract, but in this case, the theme actually seems to get in the way of the gameplay.  Really all it consists of is building sets of colours on the playing field, in order to collect sets of colours from the scoring table. The sets of colours on the playing field and the sets of colours on the scoring table each have names, but the names are irrelevant, and harder to remember than the colours.  The 2 different sets of colours have no connection to each other, it&#039;s just 2 different mechanics tied together arbitrarily.  There aren&#039;t any major problems with the game, the theme and mechanics just didn&#039;t seem coherent enough for me to really get into it.  It&#039;s still enjoyable to play though, and my partner appreciates the puzzle aspect and the non-conflict.

Update: traded away.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="8989" subtype="boardgame" collid="10281136">
	<name sortindex="1">Hansa</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic311302.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic311302_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="4930" >
				<rating value="8.5">			<usersrated value="4343" />			<average value="6.92767" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.72405" />			<stddev value="1.13695" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-12-23 23:04:01" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>Michael Schacht designs some consistently solid games, that seem halfway between an abstract strategy game and a euro (Patrician is another example).  I really love this style of game so this was definitely a hit with me.  It has some pretty unique mechanics regarding how the market stalls and goods work.

Update: This worked really well as a 2 player game with Kelsey and I, and my rating reflects the 2 player game.  I haven&#039;t tried with more players yet.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="382" subtype="boardgame" collid="10621445">
	<name sortindex="1">Heimlich &amp; Co.</name>
		<yearpublished>1984</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic183805.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic183805_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="7"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="3328" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="2366" />			<average value="6.44722" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.22704" />			<stddev value="1.26017" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-01-14 12:17:10" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>not sure what to say about this one. It has it&#039;s charms but also it&#039;s a little silly. I&#039;d like to try it again.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="638" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548818">
	<name sortindex="1">Hera and Zeus</name>
		<yearpublished>2000</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic63285.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic63285_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="4336" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="2874" />			<average value="6.54517" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.31491" />			<stddev value="1.36592" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2010-03-02 10:36:39" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>This game is really interesting and is also quite unique.  The one thing that bugs me is that at certain points in the game, the win conditions seem too indirect or unachievable, and you feel like you&#039;re just spinning your wheels.  If both players play defensively, the game will sometimes end with the unsatisfactory win condition of someone running out of cards.  This usually causes me to play too aggressively, and my partner will react by playing defensively and winning.  Also, the game rewards the skills of bluffing and reading your opponent, which she excels at.  This could be why she likes this game more than me! </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="699" subtype="boardgame" collid="10166279">
	<name sortindex="1">HeroQuest</name>
		<yearpublished>1989</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic338410.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic338410_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="10250" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="7078" />			<average value="6.96371" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.72114" />			<stddev value="1.51286" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-05-10 09:11:55" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>This is a classic from my childhood, I can recall designing my own dungeons on grid paper.  Kelsey and I just played our first scenario of this, and had a great time.  I improvised a couple of minor changes to the scenario to spice it up, and I allowed Kelsey to improvise tactical maneuvres that would allow her to potentially earn an extra attack die.  We used the  Mind stat as a skill-check number to determine if the clever move will work or not. Kelsey had a lot of fun creating her characters, appreciated how easy and fun it was to houserule, and really enjoyed the adventure.  When the campaign ended and I told her that her characters would carry over to the next scenario, and that she could upgrade them at the armoury with her gold, she was really pleased.  We&#039;re both looking forward to the next quest!  I&#039;m really happy that this game lived up to my fond memories.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="11170" subtype="boardgame" collid="11863487">
	<name sortindex="1">Heroscape Master Set: Rise of the Valkyrie</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic244662.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic244662_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="9962" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="6467" />			<average value="7.41977" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.15473" />			<stddev value="1.52789" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-26 22:27:37" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Customizing your team is really fun, and building the map is also fun in a way, but my initial impression after a couple of plays is that the overall setup time leaves the actual gameplay feeling a bit anticlimactic.  The battles are generally simple decisions followed by dice rolls.  It was pretty fun at first but got a little repetitive. I&#039;m hoping that once I have some more figures, I can get more out of the special abilities of the units to make things a bit more interesting.  It also seems like the kind of game that would be much easier if you have someplace to leave a map set up.  For now I don&#039;t, but when my basement gets renovated...  </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="8203" subtype="boardgame" collid="21519244">
	<name sortindex="1">Hey, That&#039;s My Fish!</name>
		<yearpublished>2003</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1004115.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1004115_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="20"																	maxplaytime="20"																	playingtime="20"																	numowned="15557" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="13237" />			<average value="6.81068" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.73243" />			<stddev value="1.0919" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-05-16 11:53:30" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>This game is alright but not my favourite. Easy to teach to new players. Fun for kids.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="2655" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548584">
	<name sortindex="1">Hive</name>
		<yearpublished>2001</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic791151.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic791151_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="20"																	maxplaytime="20"																	playingtime="20"																	numowned="20565" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="16610" />			<average value="7.34624" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.24831" />			<stddev value="1.26931" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-04-07 09:59:52" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>A solid game. I&#039;m not normally as big of a fan of abstracts but this one is pretty fun.  Has the unique unit movements of chess without the heavy investment in studying opening moves etc.  The only problem I noticed was that you can sometimes end up in a position where you can keep stalling for a long time but can never find a way to regain enough tempo to win.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="31594" subtype="boardgame" collid="12743739">
	<name sortindex="1">In the Year of the Dragon</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic285822.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic285822_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="75"																	maxplaytime="100"																	playingtime="100"																	numowned="6365" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="7509" />			<average value="7.43172" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.2614" />			<stddev value="1.32281" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-11-30 10:04:17" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>							</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="9674" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548576">
	<name sortindex="1">Ingenious</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1473656.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1473656_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="12416" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="11616" />			<average value="7.21238" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.09504" />			<stddev value="1.17723" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-03-17 09:36:02" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>A fun abstract, my family loves this one, especially my mom as she wins at it more frequently than other games.  I really like the scoring method, which requires you to work on all colours evenly, but rewards you  with an extra turn for a high score in a specific colour.  I appreciate that symbols were included along with the colours for colourblind gamers.  easy to teach and scales well from 2 to 4.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="68182" subtype="boardgame" collid="10844885">
	<name sortindex="1">Isla Dorada</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic774632.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic774632_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="2620" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="1818" />			<average value="6.77854" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.40444" />			<stddev value="1.32643" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-02-24 15:24:49" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>My first play with 4 people was a blast!  We played with the co-operative bidding variant since everyone seemed to think it sounded cooler, and we had a great time.  There were many funny and/or frustrating moments (depending on who was on the receiving end!), so this game is better for a group who enjoys a certain amount of &quot;take that!&quot;.  The artwork is gorgeous and the graphic design is very functional and effective.  I did poorly in my first game but I am very eager to play it again.  In fact I can&#039;t wait!

I&#039;ll provide more detailed comments after further plays, but my initial reaction is that this could be one of Bruno Faidutti&#039;s best games!

Update: The only issue that bothers me in this game is 2 of the power cards that allow the player who chooses them to penalize 2 of the other players (Samedi and Panda).  In the early game, this seems to unfairly penalize people randomly, in the late game, it comes off as an obvious catchup mechanic that doesn&#039;t feel fun.  We decided by consensus to play without these 2 cards in our last game.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="54043" subtype="boardgame" collid="10026774">
	<name sortindex="1">Jaipur</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic725500.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic725500_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="16107" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="11769" />			<average value="7.5456" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.40589" />			<stddev value="1.08102" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-01-04 16:13:26" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>This is a fun little game but it didn&#039;t blow me away.  At first it seemed like there wasn&#039;t enough tension, but the tension grew in the second round when we paid closer attention to which point tokens were remaining and what they were worth.  One thing I appreciated was how easy the game was to learn.  It plays quickly as well.  I liked it, but I&#039;m having trouble finding specific things that I liked about it.

Update: After a second playing, it still feels like something is missing, and I&#039;ve lowered the rating. The decision making is quite simple, there isn&#039;t a lot of strategy, and there is a fair amount of luck influencing the outcome. It&#039;s not a bad game, and it&#039;s cute, but it&#039;s just not interesting enough.  There are too many other 2 player games that we like to play, so I&#039;ve put this up for trade.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="28023" subtype="boardgame" collid="10577589">
	<name sortindex="1">Jamaica</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic467230.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic467230_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="9112" >
				<rating value="8.5">			<usersrated value="7036" />			<average value="7.08736" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.9128" />			<stddev value="1.26149" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-11-11 21:43:11" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>I love the gorgeous board, artwork, and components, and the box insert is expertly designed.  The theme is really fun to play with casual gamers. I&#039;m also a big fan of the simulaneous action planning mechanic. The game is very easy to teach, although the layout of the rulebook is a bit awkward.  My only complaint is the amount of luck involved in winning the game. I don&#039;t mind luck in a game, especially one this thematic, but the luck to skill ratio seems a bit high in this one, especially with the large variance of the attack die.  Luckily, this is the kind of game that is still really fun regardless of what place you&#039;re in, so I still enjoy it a lot.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="12002" subtype="boardgame" collid="9554241">
	<name sortindex="1">Jambo</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1244694.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1244694_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="8505" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="6933" />			<average value="7.08927" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.93168" />			<stddev value="1.20542" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-02-24 15:34:19" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>After further plays, this is still not wowing me and I&#039;ve lowered the rating. There are many dull points in the game where you can&#039;t find something useful and you&#039;re just cycling through cards.  The games are very close but the winner seems random or arbitrary. It feels similar but inferior to a game like San Juan, so I don&#039;t think this will be seeing many plays.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="394" subtype="boardgame" collid="9569941">
	<name sortindex="1">Kahuna</name>
		<yearpublished>1998</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2606165.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2606165_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="40"																	playingtime="40"																	numowned="6433" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="4935" />			<average value="6.66817" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.50356" />			<stddev value="1.26203" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-05-16 11:41:20" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Learned to play this one online and it is challenging and pretty fun. Hard to evaluate how much I liked it because I was playing against players who were much more skilled than me. Need to try it with a friend.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="70323" subtype="boardgame" collid="10844934">
	<name sortindex="1">King of Tokyo</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic761434.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic761434_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="36287" >
				<rating value="8.5">			<usersrated value="26616" />			<average value="7.38054" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.29094" />			<stddev value="1.31194" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-07-11 13:06:29" />
	<numplays>28</numplays>			<comment>In some ways this game is like Roll Through the Ages, but more interactive.  Either way, it&#039;s a total blast to play.  The thematic special cards really create some fun and hilarious moments. The fact that it supports up to 6 people and is easy to learn is also a nice feature as that comes in handy in certain situations. The art and components are great as well. The only thing that would have made this game cooler is if the monsters each had 1 unique ability or trait.

Update: This is seeing a lot of plays so far.  Always a hit with new players and they ask to play again.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="140535" subtype="boardgame" collid="21082402">
	<name sortindex="1">Kory</name>
		<yearpublished>2013</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1858262.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1858262_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="10"																	maxplaytime="20"																	playingtime="20"																	numowned="1252" >
				<rating value="8.5">			<usersrated value="894" />			<average value="6.89874" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.25984" />			<stddev value="1.23416" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-05-16 11:52:35" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Really love the simplicity of the rules and the way the different powers work. Will always be willing to play this. Quick to teach and play. Makes a great warm up or closing game.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="2533" subtype="boardgame" collid="11921503">
	<name sortindex="1">Kupferkessel Co.</name>
		<yearpublished>2001</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic128371.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic128371_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="1150" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="957" />			<average value="6.94545" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.33749" />			<stddev value="1.20453" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-03-26 14:05:26" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>Quite a fun little game.  This is the perfect example of a game where my partner Kelsey has a serious advantage over me, due to her excellent skill at keeping track of multiple pieces of in-game information.  She&#039;s also quite good at planning ahead.  In our first play, she was planning several turns ahead, executing her turns much faster than me, and had a clear picture of where her score stood in comparison to mine.  Perhaps it was the late night hour, but I was barely able to plan two moves ahead, and was focused on keeping track of which ingredients I collected, paying no attention to my opponent!  Needless to say, her final score completely crushed mine.  I&#039;m looking forward to trying again, and trying to pay better attention, however I&#039;m not sure if I&#039;ll ever be able to beat her.  It&#039;s quite intimidating!  </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="1219" subtype="boardgame" collid="9916350">
	<name sortindex="1">Labyrinth</name>
		<yearpublished>1986</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2773940.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2773940_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="20"																	maxplaytime="20"																	playingtime="20"																	numowned="8477" >
				<rating value="8.5">			<usersrated value="5625" />			<average value="6.34319" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.21041" />			<stddev value="1.22737" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-05-12 09:57:42" />
	<numplays>10</numplays>			<comment>Really fun, and I like this a lot better than the Master Labyrinth version.  I love the puzzle aspect of finding the best way to change the maze.  It does have some luck, but it rewards clever play.  It&#039;s also really easy to teach to non-gamers, but can be a bit of a brain-burner for those who are not good at spacial reasoning (imagining how the maze will look once it is changed). </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="45" subtype="boardgame" collid="10325608">
	<name sortindex="1">Liars Dice</name>
	<originalname>Liar&#039;s Dice</originalname>	<yearpublished>1987</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic289210.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic289210_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="15"																	maxplaytime="15"																	playingtime="15"																	numowned="9519" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="8185" />			<average value="6.93798" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.80669" />			<stddev value="1.38697" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-01-14 12:22:24" />
	<numplays>10</numplays>			<comment>This goes over really well with new/casual players. Once you know how to play, it is easy to teach. One of the new players from the last session (who is not a gamer) wanted to get a copy for himself after trying this. The gameplay creates funny moments and it plays quickly, but the decision making can still be tense. I think this will become a popular game to play with my family.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="134453" subtype="boardgame" collid="18297649">
	<name sortindex="5">The Little Prince: Make Me a Planet</name>
		<yearpublished>2013</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1815888.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1815888_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="25"																	maxplaytime="25"																	playingtime="25"																	numowned="2095" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="1734" />			<average value="6.96724" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.52244" />			<stddev value="1.13399" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-05-16 11:51:30" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Really love playing the 2 player version! The tile selection mechanic for more than 2 players is much less fun. Highly recommended with 2 players, with more it is chaotic but still fun.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="50" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548816">
	<name sortindex="1">Lost Cities</name>
		<yearpublished>1999</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2606107.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2606107_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="27517" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="22538" />			<average value="7.1206" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.03824" />			<stddev value="1.27891" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2010-07-07 11:29:50" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>What I like about this game is that it is a very simple game that can be taught to just about anyone, but still offers interesting and enjoyable decision making.  The art and large format card size look great too.  This game also works really well as a game to recommend to couples who are just getting into boardgaming.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="70512" subtype="boardgame" collid="10844939">
	<name sortindex="1">Luna</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2538939.png</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2538939_t.png</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="100"																	playingtime="100"																	numowned="3049" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="2589" />			<average value="7.42288" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.00647" />			<stddev value="1.33592" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-06-19 17:03:32" />
	<numplays>15</numplays>			<comment>I wasn&#039;t sure what to expect about this game but my first impression is that it is quite interesting and challenging.  There is a lot going on in the game, leading to some tough decisions, and the candle mechanic used to end the round adds a lot of tension. I also enjoyed the art and general theme of the game, even if some of the thematic connections for the mechanics were a bit weak.  This is a similar issue for Macao as well, by the same designer. The interactions of the mechanics are certainly well designed though. The game also scaled to 2 players much better than I expect from a euro, which is a really important feature for me. Many games of this style are only really good with 3 or 4 players, but I do a lot of 2 player gaming, and my partner enjoys this style of euro game.

Update: I&#039;m seriously impressed with how much replay value is packed into this game, and I haven&#039;t even tried it with more than 2 players or without the preselected setup. There are many different strategies to try.

Update: After one play with 4 players, it also played great at this player count.  Scalability is quite good!</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="55670" subtype="boardgame" collid="11668768">
	<name sortindex="1">Macao</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic665651.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic665651_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="50"																	maxplaytime="100"																	playingtime="100"																	numowned="5612" >
				<rating value="8.5">			<usersrated value="5252" />			<average value="7.45593" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.21882" />			<stddev value="1.32437" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-09-29 16:52:40" />
	<numplays>13</numplays>			<comment>The clever dice mechanic makes this one a joy to play.  It allows long term planning with just the right amount of risk-taking. There are a few issues with poor card translation or hesitation about the functions of certain cards, and some better word choices for rules translations could have made the game easier to teach and less confusing for new players. This is the only thing holding this back from a higher rating.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="429" subtype="boardgame" collid="10251447">
	<name sortindex="1">Magalon</name>
		<yearpublished>1998</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic283153.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic283153_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="340" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="183" />			<average value="5.97049" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.59513" />			<stddev value="1.3582" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-12-23 23:38:04" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Exactly what I would hope for with this kind of game. There is definitely some king maker or gang up on the leader issues but it&#039;s hard to avoid in a game of this style. The ease of introduction to new players, the neat mechanics handled with elegant rules, and the cool theme are the high points.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="40816" subtype="boardgame" collid="10164409">
	<name sortindex="1">Magestorm</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic977956.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic977956_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="1112" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="288" />			<average value="6.57069" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.794" />			<stddev value="1.46065" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-11-10 13:48:54" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Played once so far.  The first scenario seemed pretty cool.  I like the intuitiveness of the rules system, and the mage board was interesting. One concern I noticed so far is that because the terrain mainly provides defensive bonuses, it doesn&#039;t encourage you to attack, you would rather the opponent attacks you. 1 play is not enough to come to a conclusion on whether this is a legitimate concern though. The many combat steps made combat feel a bit tedious, but this may smooth out as I learn the game more, and some of the steps can be skipped over quickly.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="463" subtype="boardgame" collid="9916703">
	<name sortindex="1">Magic: The Gathering</name>
		<yearpublished>1993</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic163749.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic163749_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="20"																	maxplaytime="20"																	playingtime="20"																	numowned="21176" >
				<rating value="9.5">			<usersrated value="19318" />			<average value="7.43352" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.30173" />			<stddev value="1.84251" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-02-08 00:28:09" />
	<numplays>103</numplays>			<comment>I&#039;ve been playing on and off for 17 years and think the design is very innovative and clever, and the strategy required is often deep, but it also has nostalgic value too.  I go in phases where I am either playing addictively or get completely out of the loop.  The one issue that frustrates me a lot is the financially exploitative pace of new releases and the high cost of dual lands and other utility cards often needed for multiple decks.  I also really hate the frequent marketing gimmicks like foils, mythic rares, etc.  Luckily these issues are more of a metagame problem, not really a problem with the gameplay itself, so they can be ignored while playing.  As such, I haven&#039;t factored this into my rating much.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="24565" subtype="boardgame" collid="11221335">
	<name sortindex="1">Magical Athlete</name>
		<yearpublished>2002</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2695208.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2695208_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="4"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="931" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="773" />			<average value="6.54437" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.02971" />			<stddev value="1.40525" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-07-25 10:22:17" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>This game is great fun and is now my new favourite party game, beating out No Thanks! and Dixit.  The characters are well designed to create tough decisions during the draft, and interact to provide hilarious moments during the race.  The races are even fun to watch for spectators.  The only downsides are that the board is a little bit ugly, and I would have liked a wider player range.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="1309" subtype="boardgame" collid="11697355">
	<name sortindex="5">Die Magier von Pangea</name>
		<yearpublished>2001</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic194007.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic194007_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="877" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="604" />			<average value="6.25197" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.83209" />			<stddev value="1.25933" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-10-28 19:18:49" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>This is a fun puzzle game with a cute theme, and some really unique mechanics.  It mixes a pickup and deliver game with a spatial puzzle game like Amazing Labyrinth or The Stars Are Right. The rules are not as complicated as they seem at first. It&#039;s actually fairly easy to learn how to play, although it is quite a challenging game to master.  This has me looking forward to future plays so that I can try to improve on my past performance.  There can definitely be some analysis paralysis so you might want to approach this one with caution if this frustrates you.  I&#039;ve only tried it with 2 players so far.  I&#039;d imagine it would be more difficult and cause more AP with more players but I&#039;d still love to give it a try.

Update: In our third play with 2 players, we experienced a bit of a runaway leader problem where one player felt they had no chance to catch up.  I&#039;m still interested to see how the dynamic changes with more players.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="9440" subtype="boardgame" collid="9569642">
	<name sortindex="1">Maharaja: The Game of Palace Building in India</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic44952.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic44952_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="4716" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="4281" />			<average value="7.18948" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.93305" />			<stddev value="1.28764" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-04-19 10:15:31" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>After only one play I really liked this a lot.  There is a lot of tension as you don&#039;t know whether your actions will be successful, depending on what your opponents do.  It rewards clever play and I definitely saw some moves made by my opponents that really surprised me!  I came in second place but saw where I could have made better choices.  Can&#039;t wait to try it again.

Update: My second play also went great. This game hits the perfect balance between depth and rules that are simple enough for new players to grasp and do well. The second game was won by a new player who made some very clever moves. The simultaneous action selection allows for some funny and surprising moments and opportunities to screw up the other players.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="5135" subtype="boardgame" collid="9916714">
	<name sortindex="1">Malarky</name>
		<yearpublished>1996</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1547887.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1547887_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="775" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="320" />			<average value="5.68875" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.54479" />			<stddev value="1.60363" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2010-12-06 10:58:17" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>This is not my kind of game.  Partly because I suck at it, but also partly because I don&#039;t like the way the mechanics are designed.  Also, certain types of people can ruin the fun of this game if they don&#039;t know how to bluff.  If I need to play a party game, I&#039;d much prefer Apples to Apples or No Thanks.

Update: traded away.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="29223" subtype="boardgame" collid="12392946">
	<name sortindex="1">Marrakech</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic661439.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic661439_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="2029" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="1725" />			<average value="6.71912" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.35506" />			<stddev value="1.13864" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-02-28 10:45:23" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>Simplistic gameplay, but the tactile sensation given by the felt carpet components is quite unique and really caught the attention of my friends who I showed this to.  This make a nice filler as you are waiting for more to show up.  The gameplay is simple and somewhat random, but the short playing time means that this simplicity is not frustrating.  There is also a visual spatial puzzle element to the game which is enjoyable.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="437" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548021">
	<name sortindex="1">Master Labyrinth</name>
		<yearpublished>1997</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic215800.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic215800_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="20"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="2896" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="1706" />			<average value="6.30452" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.04813" />			<stddev value="1.19325" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-03-11 11:11:36" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>I like this less than the original version because of the way that everyone is hunting for the same items in sequence.  The wands and ingredient cards are neat ideas but the actual mechanic of everyone hunting the same item at the same time is not as interesting as the original version.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="2955" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548506">
	<name sortindex="1">Mexica</name>
		<yearpublished>2002</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2470537.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2470537_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="3559" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="2563" />			<average value="7.07318" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.71625" />			<stddev value="1.14702" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2010-02-24 14:31:59" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>A gorgeous game, very attractive components.  it may deserve a higher rating, but I haven&#039;t played this recently or as often as Tikal so I will rate it an 8 for now until I have a chance to replay it.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="444" subtype="boardgame" collid="10547061">
	<name sortindex="1">Midnight Party</name>
		<yearpublished>1989</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic177964.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic177964_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="8"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="1751" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="1205" />			<average value="6.42877" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.06595" />			<stddev value="1.37806" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-11-05 10:30:41" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>very simple game, tried it with 2 players which was not very much fun, but I would like to try it with a bigger group before rating it.

Update: Got a chance to try this with 4.  It was good fun.  Still quite random, but important decisions are in the placement round at the beginning.  Some &quot;push your luck&quot; involved.  Would make a good game to play with kids or as a drinking game.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="39802" subtype="boardgame" collid="11043669">
	<name sortindex="1">Mountain of Inferno</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic877891.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic877891_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="25"																	maxplaytime="25"																	playingtime="25"																	numowned="440" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="154" />			<average value="5.82662" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.56076" />			<stddev value="1.1847" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-09-18 12:21:18" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>This game is somewhat interesting, but it seems to drag, and you can keep messing up your opponent&#039;s position. It can also be hard to win until you draw a specific card you need. So far, after playing one or two rounds, my opponents don&#039;t seem to have much interest in playing to completion.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="21763" subtype="boardgame" collid="9592591">
	<name sortindex="1">Mr. Jack</name>
		<yearpublished>2006</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic156046.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic156046_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="11695" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="10403" />			<average value="7.11152" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.98994" />			<stddev value="1.22816" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-05-10 09:41:20" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>This is a nice change of pace from many of my other games.  My partner has very good bluffing and deduction skills, so we enjoy having a nice 2 player game that makes use of these skills.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="72287" subtype="boardgame" collid="11263122">
	<name sortindex="1">Mr. Jack Pocket</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1519530.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1519530_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="15"																	maxplaytime="15"																	playingtime="15"																	numowned="6314" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="3814" />			<average value="7.06338" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.80292" />			<stddev value="1.15269" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-09-07 14:34:15" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>The theme might suggest it, but this isn&#039;t really a deduction game although there is a small amount of deduction involved.  It is primarily an asymmetric visual/spatial puzzle game, and quite a fun one!  The game mechanics are easy to learn and teach, intuitive, and somewhat innovative in a cute/clever way (especially the way the action tokens are randomized, and the way the hourglass tokens work as both a game timer and victory points for Jack). It definitely earns points for the attractive artwork and great portability. Initial impressions are that the role of Jack is a little bit harder to play, but I&#039;m looking forward to future plays to see if this holds true.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="18333" subtype="boardgame" collid="9894924">
	<name sortindex="1">Nature Fluxx</name>
		<yearpublished>2005</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2649895.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2649895_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="15"																	maxplaytime="15"																	playingtime="15"																	numowned="1409" >
				<rating value="4.5">			<usersrated value="747" />			<average value="5.87818" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.6583" />			<stddev value="1.59269" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-02-11 21:08:47" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>a fun game, easy to each, with a good environmental theme, but the game usually ends somewhat suddenly, and the winner is determined too much by luck for my tastes. I will still play it occasionally if requested by someone else.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="21241" subtype="boardgame" collid="9554112">
	<name sortindex="1">Neuroshima Hex!</name>
		<yearpublished>2006</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1844819.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1844819_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="7705" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="7800" />			<average value="7.43507" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.22335" />			<stddev value="1.37356" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2010-08-23 09:06:01" />
	<numplays>8</numplays>			<comment>I really like this one a lot.  I love how it feels like both an abstract and a combat based strategy game.  It also has a puzzle aspect, when trying to find the best placement for a piece. I also love the asymmetrical teams, different unit stats, and the brightly coloured pieces.  Unfortunately Kelsey does not love it as much as me, so I don&#039;t get a chance to play enough.  I also haven&#039;t tried it with more than 2 players yet.  This is my top request if I am gaming with another gamer who knows and likes this one.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="96007" subtype="boardgame" collid="13559031">
	<name sortindex="5">The New Era</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1106275.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1106275_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="1580" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="1037" />			<average value="7.71246" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.78037" />			<stddev value="1.48383" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-10-08 00:20:42" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>I like this much better than 51st State, it seems to have streamlined some of the rules, but also added additional depth with some of the new card abilities. Working on a review with more details.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="15363" subtype="boardgame" collid="9554225">
	<name sortindex="1">Nexus Ops</name>
		<yearpublished>2005</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic566543.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic566543_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="8983" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="6964" />			<average value="7.28106" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.09244" />			<stddev value="1.21071" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-02-25 10:36:06" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>This game has a lot of things I love.  I love the graphic design, the modular board, the cool components, the strategic decision making, the units and their abilities, the win condition, etc. It also scales well from 2 to 4 players. The only complaint is that sometimes the secret mission cards can be too random. Sometimes you draw one that goes perfectly with your current position or is already accomplished, sometimes you draw one that you won&#039;t be able to achieve.

Edit: I sometimes forget the rule about discarding a card to get 1 Rubium. This somewhat balances the concern above, you can discard unattainable secret missions to get more rubium.
</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="12942" subtype="boardgame" collid="10227828">
	<name sortindex="1">No Thanks!</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic117996.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic117996_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="20"																	maxplaytime="20"																	playingtime="20"																	numowned="14631" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="11693" />			<average value="7.03597" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.93991" />			<stddev value="1.174" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-03-02 22:39:54" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>I&#039;m not usually a big party game fan, but I really appreciate this one for the simplicity of the rules, quick playing time, and the portability.  Also the game is not as random as most party games, smart play seems to often lead to winning the game. There is also a surprising amount of tension and consideration in the decision making.  Due to the ease of teaching this game, and the fun moments it creates, this is now my favourite quick filler to introduce to non gamers.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="29602" subtype="boardgame" collid="11722220">
	<name sortindex="1">Okko: Era of the Asagiri</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic384109.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic384109_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="1543" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="605" />			<average value="6.76089" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.03528" />			<stddev value="1.42735" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-05-26 14:36:59" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>So far I&#039;ve played only the introductory scenario, which doesn&#039;t really have any interesting plot points, it&#039;s just a straightforward 3 on 3 skirmish. This was useful to learn the mechanics, which are quite clever and elegant.  The movement and control zone mechanics make for some interesting tactical considerations.  I think once a scenario with a more interesting plot is used, this game will really come to life.

Update: Tried the next scenario, and the storyline aspect was more interesting, but the game dragged on a little long with 2 units left per side, and frequent stalemate or retreat-only combat results. The movement and control zone mechanics are elegant and interesting, but the combat mechanic is the weak spot, with not enough options to influence the random die results. I&#039;ll give this another try though.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="1985" subtype="boardgame" collid="9547986">
	<name sortindex="1">Overturn</name>
		<yearpublished>1987</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic238541.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic238541_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="10"																	maxplaytime="10"																	playingtime="10"																	numowned="151" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="59" />			<average value="5.96356" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.53584" />			<stddev value="1.1571" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-12-24 19:33:31" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>This is like a cross between Boggle and Othello.  I&#039;ve only played it a couple of times.  It&#039;s not bad but not very exciting.  I might try to play it again some time to get a better impression.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="37120" subtype="boardgame" collid="11726104">
	<name sortindex="1">Pack &amp; Stack</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic495850.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic495850_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="2244" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="2201" />			<average value="6.42241" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.19025" />			<stddev value="1.25595" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-11-05 10:29:46" />
	<numplays>6</numplays>			<comment>This is a pretty fun party game.  I thought I might not like it as I am usually terrible at games with a speed/reflex component, but I won the first 2 games. Quick visual-spatial perception can help to compensate for slow reflexes in this game. The one odd thing is the way the number of trucks used is scaled from 3-4 vs 5-6, but this is easily adjustable. Most players seem to enjoy this but really poor luck can sometimes ruin the fun for a player.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="30549" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548565">
	<name sortindex="1">Pandemic</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1534148.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1534148_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="63796" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="46552" />			<average value="7.66466" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.58499" />			<stddev value="1.29431" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-05-02 11:15:01" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>This game is really well designed, has a large, gorgeous board, and very nice components.  It plays really smoothly and really provides a lot of tension as you struggle to keep the viruses under control.  Unfortunately I am not a big fan of co-op games, I find once you play them a couple of times, additional plays feel repetitive.  I&#039;ll hang on to this game since I think it is so well designed, and it will serve as the co-op game I will rely on if I find myself needing or wanting to play one.

Update: I never feel like playing co-ops so I sold this to a friend.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="56692" subtype="boardgame" collid="10978509">
	<name sortindex="1">Parade</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2239001.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2239001_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="3329" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="2538" />			<average value="6.87824" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.57238" />			<stddev value="1.17891" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-02-25 10:39:42" />
	<numplays>5</numplays>			<comment>I&#039;ve tried this both with 2 and with 4 and it is pretty fun but nothing special.  I like the art but I&#039;m not crazy about the graphic design, the font is quite ugly.  It reminds me a lot of lost cities, battleline, no thanks, and other card games that involve set collection and avoiding negative points, but the actual card collection mechanic is quite unique.  The gameplay is largely tactical, no long term strategy, and there is a significant luck factor.  Sometimes there are just no good moves you can make.  It&#039;s easy to teach to new players though and will create some laughs and fun moments.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="1549" subtype="boardgame" collid="10378095">
	<name sortindex="1">Password</name>
		<yearpublished>1962</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic42588.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic42588_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="1401" >
				<rating value="4.5">			<usersrated value="749" />			<average value="6.12097" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.80692" />			<stddev value="1.60597" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="1" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-02-24 15:37:42" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>This is not really my type of game but its a classic with my family so when I saw a nice vintage copy for $2 I grabbed it.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="30241" subtype="boardgame" collid="9585936">
	<name sortindex="1">Patrician</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic313778.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic313778_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="50"																	maxplaytime="50"																	playingtime="50"																	numowned="1342" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="1158" />			<average value="6.62822" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.19122" />			<stddev value="1.16642" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="1" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-26 22:23:22" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Almost an abstract, I don&#039;t pay attention to the theme much.  Very interesting puzzler, seems to scale well from 2-4 players (haven&#039;t tried 5).  I like the colourful pieces and attractive board. I also like the simple ruleset, it&#039;s easy to teach to new players. My initial rating is an 8 but I need more plays to see if this holds up.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="2281" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548844">
	<name sortindex="1">Pictionary</name>
		<yearpublished>1985</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic336863.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic336863_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="16"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="6389" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="4654" />			<average value="5.83641" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.73919" />			<stddev value="1.57741" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2010-12-06 11:02:49" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>I&#039;m not sure why I still have this in my collection.  Maybe in case of a rare situation where I want to game with non-gamers and don&#039;t have the patience to teach them something with actual game mechanics.  Or maybe just because it is so easily available in thrift stores that there is no point trying to sell it. It is what it is, there is nothing really wrong with it, just not my kind of game.

Update: traded away.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="37371" subtype="boardgame" collid="12052889">
	<name sortindex="1">Piece o&#039; Cake</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic629711.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic629711_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="20"																	maxplaytime="20"																	playingtime="20"																	numowned="1720" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="1687" />			<average value="6.5994" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.26654" />			<stddev value="1.17143" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-05-16 11:46:28" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>One of my preferred casual warm up games. Easy to teach, fun decision making, cute theme, quick play time.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="140" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548972">
	<name sortindex="1">Pit</name>
		<yearpublished>1964</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic812175.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic812175_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="8"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="8757" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="5657" />			<average value="6.42434" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.291" />			<stddev value="1.52975" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-01-22 11:13:21" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>I&#039;ll keep this because I love the style of the old used copy I found for quite cheap, but the actual gameplay is really not my style.  Too loud and chaotic, decision making has too little impact on the outcome. </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="555" subtype="boardgame" collid="11455848">
	<name sortindex="5">The Princes of Florence</name>
		<yearpublished>2000</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic326969.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic326969_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="75"																	maxplaytime="100"																	playingtime="100"																	numowned="12854" >
				<rating value="8.5">			<usersrated value="12291" />			<average value="7.62699" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.49" />			<stddev value="1.34242" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-09-11 16:28:36" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>I really enjoy this game on many levels. Theme, artwork, and mechanics are all great. The more games I play by Wolfgang Kramer the more impressed I am.  Definitely my favourite designer. This also seems like a game with enough depth that my skill will have room to grow.  The only downside is that this game is tricky to introduce to new players, for 2 reasons.  First, there is something slightly unintuitive about how works are completed and scored (this certainly makes this game feel a bit different than other Kramer games). Secondly, experienced players have a serious advantage over new players because they will be familiar with the approximate values of the different auction items. To me the ease of introducing a game to new players is an important feature so this accessibility issue is the only thing holding me back from rating this higher.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="3228" subtype="boardgame" collid="9937333">
	<name sortindex="1">Pueblo</name>
		<yearpublished>2002</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic55922.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic55922_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="1788" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="1897" />			<average value="6.87049" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.49421" />			<stddev value="1.2052" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-08-25 10:45:49" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>This is a fun puzzle-like abstract with a pasted on theme that actually works really well.  Games with 3D visual-spatial aspects provide good exercise for the mind. It&#039;s also easy to teach to new gamers.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="3076" subtype="boardgame" collid="10022252">
	<name sortindex="1">Puerto Rico</name>
		<yearpublished>2002</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic158548.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic158548_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="150"																	playingtime="150"																	numowned="45911" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="41144" />			<average value="8.13286" />
			<bayesaverage value="8.03568" />			<stddev value="1.39426" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-02-24 15:25:43" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>This was easier to learn than I expected it to be, although there were a few fiddly rules that we had to doublecheck a couple of times.  I enjoyed it, but due to the level of complexity, I want to play it once more before rating.  As far as classic Euros go, I&#039;d much rather play this than Settlers of Catan.

Update: After a second play, I really enjoyed this. I understood the strategies better, and I feel like this is definitely a game in which your play skill can improve over time. Looking forward to playing again so I can continue to improve my strategy.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="36946" subtype="boardgame" collid="10552195">
	<name sortindex="1">Red November</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic973939.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic973939_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="8"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="8562" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="6195" />			<average value="6.37628" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.26237" />			<stddev value="1.34235" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2010-05-28 10:10:54" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>This wasn&#039;t a bad game, the theme was definitely fun, but I&#039;m not a big co-op fan, and the game seemed somewhat similar to Pandemic.  I wasn&#039;t a fan of the tiny board for this game, and I love the graphic design and large board of Pandemic, so in the rare times when I feel like playing a co-op, I couldn&#039;t see a reason to choose this game when I have Pandemic.  So I sold it.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="144270" subtype="boardgame" collid="21539939">
	<name sortindex="1">Relic Runners</name>
		<yearpublished>2013</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1696460.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1696460_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="40"																	maxplaytime="80"																	playingtime="80"																	numowned="2059" >
				<rating value="8.5">			<usersrated value="1282" />			<average value="6.71815" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.26993" />			<stddev value="1.24784" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-05-16 11:54:08" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Really like this game. Fun components and theme. Mechanics are solid and I like planning ahead and building an epic route. I wish it was a bit easier to teach, some of the mechanics are not super intuitive. Sometimes the end game triggers can catch new players off guard. Players who have played before will definitely have a strong advantage over new players.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="34887" subtype="boardgame" collid="15988799">
	<name sortindex="1">Revolution!</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic470283.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic470283_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="3518" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="3022" />			<average value="6.75826" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.49537" />			<stddev value="1.4278" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-05-26 15:41:25" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>This one was not what I expected, and really surprised me by mixing simple mechanics in a unique way. I need more plays to get a better feel for the game before I can comment further.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="51" subtype="boardgame" collid="12052896">
	<name sortindex="1">Ricochet Robots</name>
		<yearpublished>1999</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1766273.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1766273_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="15"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="5447" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="5466" />			<average value="6.99696" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.79187" />			<stddev value="1.66004" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-03-23 08:15:32" />
	<numplays>6</numplays>			<comment>It&#039;s a classic that is entertaining to introduce to new players.  It&#039;s nice to have a game without any player limit. Otherwise, it doesn&#039;t really have the game qualities I appreciate, so it&#039;s not something I would play often.

Update: This has grown on me a bit. It&#039;s not like other games but it has a certain charm. It has gone over really well with certain friends, but not so much with others.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="181" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548421">
	<name sortindex="1">Risk</name>
		<yearpublished>1993</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic205165.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic205165_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="25578" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="18760" />			<average value="5.57808" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.46384" />			<stddev value="1.63741" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="1" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-08-18 22:35:27" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>I&#039;ve only played this a couple of times, mainly because it takes a bit too long for this type of game.  Otherwise it&#039;s not a bad game, a bit random and swingy.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="18" subtype="boardgame" collid="9554250">
	<name sortindex="1">RoboRally</name>
		<yearpublished>1994</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic249264.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic249264_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="8"																	minplaytime="20"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="19778" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="17260" />			<average value="7.19521" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.09466" />			<stddev value="1.50786" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-02-25 10:39:03" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>Great chaotic fun with a big group of people.  I love the simultaneous action / programming mechanic, and I love the options cards (crab legs FTW!).
Some of the maps are overly complex, and sometimes the playing time stretches the limit of the players&#039; patience.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="201" subtype="boardgame" collid="10314149">
	<name sortindex="1">Le Roi Des Roses</name>
	<originalname>Rosenknig</originalname>	<yearpublished>2000</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic372061.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic372061_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="2457" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="1907" />			<average value="6.78753" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.43997" />			<stddev value="1.27279" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-05-16 11:44:32" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Pretty fun abstract strategy game. There is a fair bit of luck involved but still room for tactical decision making. Kelsey is better than me at this game because she is good at tracking what moves I can do in response and accounting for that in her plans.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="37380" subtype="boardgame" collid="10332234">
	<name sortindex="1">Roll Through the Ages: The Bronze Age</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic986758.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic986758_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="10065" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="9192" />			<average value="6.94344" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.83221" />			<stddev value="1.16217" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-02-24 15:26:38" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Really fun, nice mix of luck and strategy, quick playing time, portable and easy to play even without a flat surface (on the grass, on the couch, in the bed!).  It&#039;s a bit addictive!</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="9217" subtype="boardgame" collid="9554392">
	<name sortindex="1">Saint Petersburg</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic246360.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic246360_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="9927" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="11496" />			<average value="7.34241" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.22237" />			<stddev value="1.31241" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-02-25 10:38:03" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>I tried it once so far, really liked it, the components are gorgeous, although I&#039;m not a huge fan of the paper money.  For the lightness of the game, the administrative tasks were a small burden at times (we sometimes forgot to pass the markers or rotate the card stacks), but I think this will be easier on the second play.  Kelsey enjoyed it too and we&#039;re looking forward to trying this again.

Update: I play this a lot on yucata, and I like it.  The only problem is that with players of unequal skill, there can be a run-away leader problem, which makes the end-game drag a bit.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="3" subtype="boardgame" collid="9554320">
	<name sortindex="1">Samurai</name>
		<yearpublished>1998</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2571921.png</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2571921_t.png</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="10451" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="10878" />			<average value="7.43976" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.3006" />			<stddev value="1.19302" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="1" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-12-23 23:07:07" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>so far I&#039;ve only tried the iOS app, it plays quick and it&#039;s pretty fun.  Many of the mechanics remind me of other abstract strategy games, but it&#039;s all well put together here, with really attractive components.  I&#039;m looking forward to trying it with real opponents, the rating my increase once I try that out.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="8217" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548436">
	<name sortindex="1">San Juan</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic174174.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic174174_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="18129" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="17030" />			<average value="7.30681" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.21447" />			<stddev value="1.1719" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-03-26 14:01:04" />
	<numplays>13</numplays>			<comment>I play this quite frequently with my partner, it makes a great lunch hour game.  There are not many different strategies to explore, but you don&#039;t always have a choice and need to work with what you draw.  There isn&#039;t anything especially amazing about this game, but it has interesting decisions and a nice relaxing flow to it.  I was about to bump the rating down as we had started to get bored with the limited amount of winning strategies, but we just picked up the Treasure Chest expansion, which adds additional strategies.

Update: after a bit of a break I&#039;ve played this again and continue to appreciate it more, especially with the expansion.  I would rate this an 8 without the expansion and 9 with it.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="18500" subtype="boardgame" collid="11726103">
	<name sortindex="1">Sator Arepo Tenet Opera Rotas</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic370329.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic370329_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="832" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="710" />			<average value="6.92368" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.20738" />			<stddev value="1.2581" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-06-19 17:06:09" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>After 2 plays of this game I&#039;m definitely pleased with this.  It did seem to play a bit better with 2 people rather than 3 due to downtime between turns, but this was with a new player, and 2 of us playing for only the second time.  There are a couple of fiddly rules that made the initial explanations trickier from a teaching perspective, and there were a few minor details that I feel should have been added to the rulebook. However, I did a better job explaining things the second time around as I knew what to focus on, and what could be ignored and/or explained later.  Once you get past these minor difficulties, the essential gameplay is actually fairly simple to understand and intuitive, but also tricky and intriguing. The visual appeal of the game is great too.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="438" subtype="boardgame" collid="9916719">
	<name sortindex="1">Scotland Yard</name>
		<yearpublished>1983</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic172295.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic172295_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="12973" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="8828" />			<average value="6.51769" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.41333" />			<stddev value="1.24407" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2010-07-07 13:37:48" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>I recently discovered this game and have had a lot of fun with it so far.  I&#039;ve had difficulty capturing my partner when she plays as Mr X, but her superior skills at keeping track of game information and reading my facial expressions has led her to capture me several times!  Considering that she found it for only $2, this is probably the most fun per dollar of any game in my collection! (Yes, my lady not only plays games with me and plays them well, but also hunts them down in thrift stores for me. I&#039;m very lucky.)</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="320" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548841">
	<name sortindex="1">Scrabble</name>
		<yearpublished>1948</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic404651.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic404651_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="25872" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="16743" />			<average value="6.34738" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.25374" />			<stddev value="1.61913" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-07-23 22:13:19" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>I used to enjoy this game more as I have a good vocabulary and am good at finding strategic places for words, but once I realized that higher level play mainly consists of using short, strange words that you only know in order to use them in Scrabble, it lost some of its appeal.  Also, it can be frustrating to play with unskilled players as they will leave no places to build onto, and will take forever to place a word.

Update (played again after a long break): Way too much downtime in a 4 player game!</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="34219" subtype="boardgame" collid="9570200">
	<name sortindex="1">Scripts and Scribes</name>
	<originalname>Biblios</originalname>	<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic729654.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic729654_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="8512" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="6690" />			<average value="7.24746" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.06706" />			<stddev value="1.18138" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2010-09-20 13:18:40" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>The rules are much simpler than it seems when you read them, but the gameplay is deeper and more subtle than it seems when you first play it.  It has the simplicity of a game like Lost Cities, but the card evaluations and decision making are more interesting.  I&#039;ve tried it with 2 and 3 players so far, it&#039;s addictive and I&#039;ve been enjoying it a lot lately.

Update: With 4 players the game becomes a bit more random, it&#039;s hard to tell whether you are winning a category or not.  This isn&#039;t a bad thing, just a noticeable difference from the 2 player game.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="108745" subtype="boardgame" collid="15802055">
	<name sortindex="1">Seasons</name>
		<yearpublished>2012</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1299390.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1299390_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="13075" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="10577" />			<average value="7.49189" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.34008" />			<stddev value="1.32992" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-10-07 10:24:05" />
	<numplays>38</numplays>							</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="63759" subtype="boardgame" collid="11922414">
	<name sortindex="1">Seeland</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic626413.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic626413_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="1677" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="1099" />			<average value="6.92505" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.36027" />			<stddev value="1.13785" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-02-25 10:38:30" />
	<numplays>5</numplays>			<comment>Fun, elegant, with just a bit of brain burn. Rules complexity is quite low so it is family friendly. We definitely prefer the tactical board as it reduces the luck, but we haven&#039;t tried the governor and records variant yet.  Not sure if it&#039;s needed, this is quite competitive without them.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="13" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548425">
	<name sortindex="1">The Settlers of Catan</name>
	<originalname>Catan</originalname>	<yearpublished>1997</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2730.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2730_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="76151" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="55627" />			<average value="7.32498" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.19279" />			<stddev value="1.44012" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-09-11 16:38:02" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>This one was not a very big hit with my family, but I have a bunch of friends who are crazy about it.  I never loved it that much but it&#039;s not bad.  At this point though, I am really sick of it as my friends requested it constantly for awhile.  I don&#039;t normally mind blocking in games, but in this game it is frustrating, as the person who is able to successfully block the other person is usually determined by random luck.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="98085" subtype="boardgame" collid="13228227">
	<name sortindex="1">Seven Dragons</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1022004.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1022004_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="20"																	maxplaytime="20"																	playingtime="20"																	numowned="1773" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="975" />			<average value="6.25363" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.91571" />			<stddev value="1.34808" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-07-25 10:20:38" />
	<numplays>6</numplays>			<comment>A fairly simple game, it plays quickly, has an interesting mechanic, and the hidden goals add a fun aspect of trying to figure out what your opponents are going for. Not sure how much skill is involved, sometimes you just need the right card and you can win. Also, I&#039;m not sure how much replayability the game will have, it might get old once the uniqueness of the primary mechanic wears off.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="34320" subtype="boardgame" collid="11531902">
	<name sortindex="1">Shanghaien</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic310863.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic310863_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="20"																	maxplaytime="20"																	playingtime="20"																	numowned="967" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="905" />			<average value="6.65404" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.13141" />			<stddev value="1.15042" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-05-26 15:50:12" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>This is a fairly luck based game, but the mechanics introduce some unique twists that make it a fun playing experience.  I like the simple rules and the colorful dice and cards. Even though she won, my partner felt like there was not enough control over the outcome of the game.  But for something this short simple and unique, I don&#039;t mind that really.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="8935" subtype="boardgame" collid="10022256">
	<name sortindex="1">Shazamm!</name>
		<yearpublished>2003</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic37522.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic37522_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="929" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="538" />			<average value="6.26253" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.81788" />			<stddev value="1.43201" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-02-24 15:31:28" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Beautiful components, art, and graphic design, in a nice small box, a great 2 player package.  The gameplay is simple but involves a lot of double-guessing, bluffing, and clever play.  This means that Kelsey destroyed me in every play so far, as she excels at bluffing and out-double-thinking the hell out of me!</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="482" subtype="boardgame" collid="12432115">
	<name sortindex="1">Sky Runner</name>
		<yearpublished>1999</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic650195.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic650195_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="599" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="334" />			<average value="5.57666" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.50995" />			<stddev value="1.29086" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-03-03 08:30:42" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>The components are so cool!  I&#039;ve tried this once with 2 players, and would not recommend it with only 2, but based on that play, I think it will be really fun with more players.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="40692" subtype="boardgame" collid="9554047">
	<name sortindex="1">Small World</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic428828.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic428828_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="40"																	maxplaytime="80"																	playingtime="80"																	numowned="42356" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="34644" />			<average value="7.40772" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.33113" />			<stddev value="1.28576" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-04-07 10:12:54" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>I love the art style and light-hearted theme.  I also love the fun combinations of races and powers.  Unfortunately there doesn&#039;t seem to be much strategy in the combat decisions, but I&#039;ve mostly played only 2 player so far. I need more plays with more than 2 people to get a better feel for how strategic the combat is.

Update: After another play, this time with 4 players, I&#039;m just not feeling this one.  It felt a bit boring.  All the strategy is in the decisions about what race to choose, deploying the race doesn&#039;t seem to present many interesting decisions. Putting this up for trade.  It&#039;s a decent game but I can&#039;t imagine myself going out of my way to play it again.

Update: math traded.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="38054" subtype="boardgame" collid="9942229">
	<name sortindex="1">Snow Tails</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2574022.png</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2574022_t.png</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="4095" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="4138" />			<average value="6.98371" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.76798" />			<stddev value="1.18673" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-01-05 11:32:07" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>I&#039;ve played and taught this several times now, and it always goes over well with new players.  My mom requested a second game immediately. It&#039;s family friendly, but it isn&#039;t a random-fest, as it rewards clever play. The customizable track adds replayability.  I&#039;m looking forward to trying a more challenging track.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="37696" subtype="boardgame" collid="10919684">
	<name sortindex="5">The Stars Are Right</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic462378.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic462378_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="55"																	maxplaytime="55"																	playingtime="55"																	numowned="1568" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="1025" />			<average value="6.39636" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.0091" />			<stddev value="1.42181" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-11-19 12:41:55" />
	<numplays>9</numplays>			<comment>This game is really fun but challenging! If you get annoyed when someone takes a long time on their turn, you may want to avoid this one.  Although slow play usually frustrates my partner, she really likes this one a lot.  This seems superior to most other &quot;puzzle-like&quot; games we&#039;ve tried, such as The Hanging Gardens.  I really love the artwork as well, and the satisfying feeling you get when you finally figure out the tricky manipulations needed to summon a great old one.  As long as you go into it knowing that the variabilty of the playing field means there is not a lot of possible advanced planning, just tactical puzzle solving, this is the best and most challenging game of that genre that I&#039;ve tried.  I just hope that I&#039;ll get better at it after further plays, it&#039;s really challenging!

Update: I&#039;ve definitely improved at this game over time, and with players of equal skill, often the finish is very close and the winner can seem like it is determined by luck. The gameplay is still challenging and enjoyable though as long as you don&#039;t put too much value on who wins. My partner and I have changed the end game condition to allow each player the same number of turns to increase fairness and make scores more competitive.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="1917" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548961">
	<name sortindex="1">Stratego</name>
		<yearpublished>1947</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic25644.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic25644_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="13118" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="8695" />			<average value="6.02241" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.92758" />			<stddev value="1.38636" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-02-24 15:33:13" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>This should probably deserve a lower rating, but gets a bit of a bump due to nostalgic reasons.  I played this constantly as a kid, because it was in my grandma&#039;s game collection and I pulled it out every time we visited. I still think it is a fun game, but I&#039;m quite biased by fond memories.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="58281" subtype="boardgame" collid="10353875">
	<name sortindex="1">Summoner Wars</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2407328.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2407328_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="3993" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="4325" />			<average value="7.39618" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.07838" />			<stddev value="1.57853" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-12-23 23:03:36" />
	<numplays>139</numplays>			<comment>The game hits a nice mix of strategy and risk-taking. Often you&#039;ll have very difficult decisions to make that will have a significant impact on the outcome of the game, but you can&#039;t always count on getting all the dice rolls you need. The asymmetric factions are really well designed and provide huge replayability, as the different faction matchups play out very differently. Also, the thematic designs for many of the factions are very cool. Normally in thematic games I&#039;m drawn to a specific faction or thematic style, but for this game, there are many factions that really hit the spot for me. In fact, all of the factions have at least something interesting about them that makes you want to give them a try. Achieving such variety while maintaining balance and consistent appeal is probably the most impressive aspect of Summoner Wars.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="93260" subtype="boardgame" collid="13331619">
	<name sortindex="1">Summoner Wars: Master Set</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic923048.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic923048_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="9969" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="7240" />			<average value="7.72494" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.47855" />			<stddev value="1.46792" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-12-23 23:03:46" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>An impressive collection of highly varied factions for an amazing game. See my comments in the main game entry for more details.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="2653" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548967">
	<name sortindex="1">Survive!</name>
	<originalname>Survive: Escape from Atlantis!</originalname>	<yearpublished>1982</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic353191.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic353191_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="14975" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="10508" />			<average value="7.34643" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.20185" />			<stddev value="1.14664" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-03-26 13:48:49" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>A nostalgic game from my childhood, but it seems to have held up really well and is still quite fun.  In fact, the family-strategy style of this game, and the cool tile flipping mechanic, are what eventually led me to look into newer board games and discover the world of eurogames!

Update: I just replayed this one again, and even with only 2 players, it was much better than I remembered.  I&#039;m looking forward to trying it with more players.  Not only did it lead me to the world of Euro games, I think it also acted as an inspiration for some Euro mechanics.  A classic!</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="2653" subtype="boardgame" collid="12603114">
	<name sortindex="1">Survive: Escape from Atlantis!</name>
		<yearpublished>1982</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1300182.png</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1300182_t.png</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="14975" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="10508" />			<average value="7.34643" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.20185" />			<stddev value="1.14664" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="1" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-11-30 10:02:10" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>The new version maintains the cool things about this game and upgrades the components.  The graphics and the components of the original are more charming, but the new design is clean and functional and easier to handle and play, and the 3D tiles are a nice feature.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="70919" subtype="boardgame" collid="10845008">
	<name sortindex="1">Takenoko</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1912529.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1912529_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="19010" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="12650" />			<average value="7.36397" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.22502" />			<stddev value="1.14889" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-05-12 19:56:30" />
	<numplays>9</numplays>			<comment>Simple and clever family strategy game. The cute components also add to the charm. There are a few aspects of the game that could have been better (irrigation is not used often, and the watershed development is way more powerful than the others). Overall though we&#039;ve been enjoying it.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="24508" subtype="boardgame" collid="9554314">
	<name sortindex="1">Taluva</name>
		<yearpublished>2006</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1948254.png</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1948254_t.png</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="5156" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="5295" />			<average value="7.17846" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.95894" />			<stddev value="1.26063" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-02-24 15:24:22" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>What a great, neat little game.  The pieces are gorgeous, and the mechanics are quite interesting.  It&#039;s definitely an abstract strategy game though, don&#039;t expect much theme.  I really like the way the board develops over time, and the mechanics are simple to learn, but offer a fair bit of depth.  I felt as I played my first game, new insights were gradually coming to me in how I could better position my pieces.  Also, I love that the ending can be triggered in different ways, which can sometimes sneak up on you, and can reward smart tactical play with a nice surprise victory.  Looking forward to future plays.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="17240" subtype="boardgame" collid="12474495">
	<name sortindex="1">That&#039;s Life!</name>
		<yearpublished>2005</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic108094.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic108094_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="2168" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="2215" />			<average value="6.49947" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.24531" />			<stddev value="1.22231" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-06-30 10:24:25" />
	<numplays>10</numplays>			<comment>That&#039;s Life is a game you&#039;ll be loving one minute and cursing the next. I had 2 fun games with my family recently. One player said &quot;I hate this game!&quot; while smiling, laughing, and asking for another round.  It&#039;s heavily luck influenced, but still provides you with interesting decisions each turn. Plus there are many opportunities to screw over another player, and this is what makes the game so fun and funny sometimes.  The game has great interactivity. It also accommodates a wide player range (2-6) which is helpful in a casual gaming situation, and it scales well. I appreciate Kramer&#039;s ability to design enjoyable games that can fit in at various difficulty levels yet always remain interesting and engaging.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="503" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548252">
	<name sortindex="1">Through the Desert</name>
		<yearpublished>1998</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic730576.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic730576_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="10094" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="10031" />			<average value="7.06858" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.95128" />			<stddev value="1.22672" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2010-05-27 08:56:29" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Interesting gameplay but a little bit chaotic.  I would likely rate it higher if it wasn&#039;t for the colour scheme being extremely unfriendly to colourblind players.  I&#039;ll try it once or twice more and if it seems worth it I will paint some of the pieces, otherwise I may sell or trade this away.
UPDATE: Traded</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="14996" subtype="boardgame" collid="9586165">
	<name sortindex="1">Ticket to Ride: Europe</name>
		<yearpublished>2005</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic66668.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic66668_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="32545" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="27373" />			<average value="7.5943" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.48901" />			<stddev value="1.19475" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-01-04 16:14:00" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>I&#039;ve only played this once, but based on my plays of Nordic Countries, I feel comfortable rating this one about the same.  I like learning the European cities, and I like the bright colours and attractive map.  There is also a fair amount of strategy in deciding what to pursue. The mechanics are intuitive and easy to teach, and I&#039;m looking forward to introducing this one to my family.

Update: We never seem to play this, my partner is not a big fan because with 4 or 5 players there is too much downtime between turns, when the turns should be simple and quick. She likes Nordic Countries with less players better.  Up for trade now.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="31627" subtype="boardgame" collid="9603747">
	<name sortindex="1">Ticket to Ride: Nordic Countries</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic369616.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic369616_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="3"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="8787" >
				<rating value="6.5">			<usersrated value="6433" />			<average value="7.68323" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.43494" />			<stddev value="1.23292" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-06-28 17:30:12" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>So I finally got around to trying a TTR game, and liked it more than expected!  I also really enjoy the attractive, large map, because I plan to visit Northern Europe soon and this will help me become familiar with the geography.  I have the Europe map too now and will be trying that one next.  This one is useful though as I more commonly play 2 or 3 player games.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="54" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548474">
	<name sortindex="1">Tikal</name>
		<yearpublished>1999</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic178078.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic178078_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="14135" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="12231" />			<average value="7.3502" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.22759" />			<stddev value="1.19277" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2010-08-09 14:23:32" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>My favourite Euro game.  The mechanics are elegant, the components are beautiful, it scales well from 2 to 4, it&#039;s easy to teach, and has fun tactical decision making.  Read my review for more details.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="67180" subtype="boardgame" collid="10055641">
	<name sortindex="1">Tikal II: The Lost Temple</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic802073.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic802073_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="1630" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="1048" />			<average value="6.91596" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.35094" />			<stddev value="1.28909" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-03-10 10:57:59" />
	<numplays>6</numplays>			<comment>The rules were a bit fiddly and there was some AP during the first play, but I really enjoyed this. The different scoring options allow you to focus on a different strategy than your opponent. So far it seems this is one advantage over the previous Tikal (where treasures are very important), but I&#039;d like to play it a lot more to see if one of the different scoring options proves itself to be more important. The one downside I can see so far, compared to another of Kramer&#039;s new games, Asara, is that the rules in this one are a little bit harder to teach and the scoring options less obvious than Asara, so it might be less ideal for casual gamers, but I&#039;m not sure if it has the depth to satisfy more serious gamers.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="42215" subtype="boardgame" collid="9554232">
	<name sortindex="1">Tobago</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic596625.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic596625_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="7874" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="7120" />			<average value="7.13335" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.9725" />			<stddev value="1.15441" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="1" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-12-23 23:08:27" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>My first impression so far is that the game is definitely interesting and beautiful, and the mechanics are quite neat and unique.  These are all factors that are important to me in a game, however the actual gameplay is not quite as fun as I would like. It seems to drag at times but this could just be due to slow play as we learn the game. It&#039;s still enjoyable though and is definitely unlike any other game in my collection. I&#039;m curious about how it will play now that we are past the learning stage.
Edit: After another play the pace seemed improved, it plays faster when all the players know the game.  Raised my rating a bit.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="123540" subtype="boardgame" collid="15802116">
	<name sortindex="1">Tokaido</name>
		<yearpublished>2012</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1293719.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1293719_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="8620" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="5858" />			<average value="7.05084" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.84507" />			<stddev value="1.36661" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-05-16 11:50:01" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Simple flowing decisions. Lots of different ways to get points and often they don&#039;t seem much different from each other, but eventually someone does come out ahead. Easy to teach and engaging for new players.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="88" subtype="boardgame" collid="9548470">
	<name sortindex="1">Torres</name>
		<yearpublished>1999</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic73550.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic73550_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="7716" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="6492" />			<average value="7.19255" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.00159" />			<stddev value="1.2734" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="1" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-26 22:26:00" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>I&#039;ve played this once, but had problems with a couple of the rules, so I need to replay it before rating it.  My intitial reaction is that neither the theme or the gameplay seem as fun as other similar titles by these designers, and the rules seem less intuitive, so I&#039;m not sure how often this will get played.

Update: Finally learned how to play this better by playing online. Still not my favourite by these designers though. It&#039;s pretty mathy and abstract.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="1515" subtype="boardgame" collid="9547989">
	<name sortindex="1">Upwords</name>
		<yearpublished>1981</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic6080.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic6080_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="3720" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="2026" />			<average value="5.70105" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.6284" />			<stddev value="1.4412" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-12-24 19:33:09" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>An interesting twist on Scrabble, stacking letters can be kind of fun, but I got bored of this rather quickly.  There is not really much to it.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="25420" subtype="boardgame" collid="9552728">
	<name sortindex="1">UR</name>
		<yearpublished>2006</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic145204.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic145204_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="1034" >
				<rating value="7.5">			<usersrated value="851" />			<average value="6.51845" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.05419" />			<stddev value="1.36884" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-02-25 10:38:13" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>This is essentially an abstract area control game with a set collection mechanic for victory points.  The theme is thin but matches up with the action mechanics in an intuitive way.  This is a great example of a game that holds a surprising amount of depth within a simple ruleset.  It can definitely be a brain burner though, and can sometimes result in some AP.  I like the design a lot, both mechanically and graphically, but it is hard to get to the table because it is fairly deep and not immediately visually appealing to someone unfamiliar with it.

Update: I&#039;ve been enjoying playing this on mabiweb.  It&#039;s easier to find players, and playing it turn based allows more time to contemplate your moves.  
Update 2: Had a fun 3 player face to face session.  There was some AP but it was still quite satisfying.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="40769" subtype="boardgame" collid="10365110">
	<name sortindex="1">Valdora</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic443834.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic443834_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="1649" >
				<rating value="8.5">			<usersrated value="1585" />			<average value="6.87026" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.44076" />			<stddev value="1.25692" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-01-14 12:30:40" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>For some reason I really enjoy this pickup and delivery game. The rules are simple and elegant, however the theme is a bit abstracted. Nice art and components too. The ending seemed to drag a bit once but I think that was only due to new players who were unsure what to do.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="27532" subtype="boardgame" collid="10512568">
	<name sortindex="1">Vineta</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic295534.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic295534_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="1247" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="800" />			<average value="6.28016" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.89961" />			<stddev value="1.31992" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-06-28 17:30:25" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Our first (and only) play did not go really well. We spent a lot of time referencing the player aid to try to understand what the special cards did.  Some of them were not worded well, and there was a mistake on the reference sheet (2 of the card descriptions are reversed, and we didn&#039;t realize until close to the end of the game). The amount of time spent trying to figure out the rules seemed disproportionate to the amount of strategy you could use and the amount of control you have over the outcome of the game.  Many of the special cards are very situational, so you spend time figuring out what it does, only to have it sit unused in your hand. The cards to move or protect houses seemed especially useless, because in order to play them, you have to miss out on playing a wave towards that turn&#039;s wave surge, which reduces your chances of sharing in the prize points for that round. And there is no way to know in advance if the place you move the houses to will be any more safe than where they were. 

At the end of the game, the last wave surge was tied, which means all players play another wave card to break the tie.  Unfortunately I ended the game with full hand of useless event cards, and no wave cards to use towards the tie.

It&#039;s possible that some of these problems may have been related to the fact that we tried it with only 3 players, the lowest number you can play with. This means there are less houses in play, which may make the house-related special cards less useful (I can&#039;t say for sure though). The rule interpretation problems would certainly be reduced on a second play, but due to the poor experience I had the first time, I can&#039;t see myself being motivated to try again.</comment>	<conditiontext>this version is the international version with the full board. It includes English, French, and German rules.</conditiontext>			</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="4911" subtype="boardgame" collid="10129400">
	<name sortindex="1">Wacky Wizard Game</name>
		<yearpublished>1977</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic44134.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic44134_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="10"																	maxplaytime="10"																	playingtime="10"																	numowned="8" >
				<rating value="2">			<usersrated value="3" />			<average value="2.66667" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />			<stddev value="0.942809" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-06-18 10:56:20" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>The components are really great, but unfortunately it uses a roll and move mechanic with a spinner, and one of the spinner results totally changes your win condition.  Totally random game. It might make a good kids game, but I&#039;m not sure I even want to expose kids I might one day have to such a random-fest.  The other option is that the components could be re-used for a new game design.

I&#039;m not sure what to do with this one, as it&#039;s really old and cool looking, but unplayable.  Want to trade it from me?</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="33154" subtype="boardgame" collid="10008928">
	<name sortindex="1">Wasabi!</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic273575.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic273575_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="4348" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="4178" />			<average value="6.56679" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.39685" />			<stddev value="1.24573" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="1" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-05-16 11:38:01" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>I was pleasantly surprised by this game.  I was expecting it to get by mostly on theme, but the mechanics were well designed and intuitive, and the gameplay was competitive and tactical.  I also love the bright colours and graphic design work.  It was easy to teach to non-gamers on the fly. A perfect complement to a great sushi night I just held.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="3236" subtype="boardgame" collid="11814590">
	<name sortindex="1">WildLife</name>
		<yearpublished>2002</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic55581.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic55581_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="1548" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="1270" />			<average value="6.69179" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.26227" />			<stddev value="1.27986" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-06-19 17:38:25" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>On first impression I like this one, but I need more plays to really decide what I think. I love the theme and the way the movement/expansion and attack mechanics work.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="156" subtype="boardgame" collid="10845109">
	<name sortindex="1">Wildlife Adventure</name>
		<yearpublished>1985</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic561132.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic561132_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="698" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="473" />			<average value="6.91036" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.04996" />			<stddev value="1.32496" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-04-11 10:43:50" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>This is a great game for learning about different animal species, and a game I would look forward to introducing to my kids if I have some one day.  It also scaled down to 2 players much better than I expected.  Some luck is involved in winning, and I&#039;m not crazy about the Chance cards, but overall I was pleased with this game.  I am curious about the Expedition version though.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="97875" subtype="boardgame" collid="14138636">
	<name sortindex="1">Wiraqocha</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1262364.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1262364_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="594" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="373" />			<average value="6.7059" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.90528" />			<stddev value="1.42773" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-05-16 11:48:20" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Only tried it once so far. I really love the art and theme, and the mechanics seem solid. With only 2 players there was not quite enough interaction. Need to try this again with more players.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="34084" subtype="boardgame" collid="9818732">
	<name sortindex="1">Witch&#039;s Brew</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic365958.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic365958_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="3130" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="3108" />			<average value="7.05874" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.7579" />			<stddev value="1.19251" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-10-28 19:13:25" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>I really like this, and it has been a hit with all of my friends. It shares some elements with other games that I like such as San Juan (role selection), and Dominion (using action cards, buying victory cards), but the theme is way more fun than either of those games.  I really love the wooden droplet tokens, and the fun art style.  Everyone gets a kick out of the part of the game where you announce your chosen role. So be it!</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="104710" subtype="boardgame" collid="15359557">
	<name sortindex="1">Wiz-War (eighth edition)</name>
		<yearpublished>2012</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1222733.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1222733_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="4748" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="3128" />			<average value="7.17953" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.83114" />			<stddev value="1.35566" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-08-11 20:07:29" />
	<numplays>8</numplays>			<comment>For some reason I really like this one, even though it seems like the winner needs a significant dose of luck. I find it is one of those games where it is fun to see what you can pull off even if it may not help you win. For the most part I think FFG did an alright job on the reprint, but I haven&#039;t played the original. I kinda wish they wouldn&#039;t mess around with the rules when reprinting games, but on the other hand the rules changes made here seem pretty simple and reasonable.

Update: The fun seems to vary based on which card sets you are using. Some of the cards are not useful enough to justify the time taken to read their overly wordy text. I think I will try making my own mix of cards before I play this next time.</comment>				</item>
		
</items>