<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<items totalitems="217" termsofuse="http://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse" pubdate="Tue, 05 Jan 2016 08:24:30 +0000">
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="421" subtype="boardgame" collid="1412817">
	<name sortindex="1">1830: Railways &amp; Robber Barons</name>
		<yearpublished>1986</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic882119.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic882119_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="7"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="360"																	playingtime="360"																	numowned="4269" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="2971" />			<average value="7.7915" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.34033" />			<stddev value="1.676" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:37:33" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>At the moment I am very interested in the 18xx family and I am going to play a lot of 18xx games (provided I find opponents). They are my preferred games!

My intention is to rate games of the family so that the ratings will be relative to each other. Surely there will be one (ore more) 10s and likely 1830 will continue to be rated 10, but at the moment the rating is based on my memory of games I played a long time ago.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="32424" subtype="boardgame" collid="17875938">
	<name sortindex="1">1848: Australia</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1207685.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1207685_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="360"																	maxplaytime="360"																	playingtime="360"																	numowned="143" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="137" />			<average value="7.85146" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.88472" />			<stddev value="1.34672" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-07-28 09:10:59" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>Very beautiful game: it is very playable and maybe a bit less aggressive than other games of the 18xx series.

There are a lot of innovative things compared to other 18xxs, the most significant being the Bank of England: between other things companies go in receivership instead of bankrupting, making the punishment less hard for the director of the company.

As other games of the series it offers a lot of choices, so significantly more and deeper than the average Euro game that for me it is a real pleasure to play, there are so many ways to be creative.

The only problem is the length: it is a middle length 18xx game, that means still being around 5 hours, more in the first games. If it were not for this I would rate the game at &quot;11&quot; :)

Very recommended if you like deep gamer&#039;s games and you are not frightened by the length and by the fact that you will need all your neurons to win this :)


</comment>				<wishlistcomment>Around 4 / 5 hours.</wishlistcomment></item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="3097" subtype="boardgame" collid="17630759">
	<name sortindex="1">1849</name>
		<yearpublished>1998</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic193760.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic193760_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="139" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="109" />			<average value="7.7133" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.79835" />			<stddev value="1.41853" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-02-02 14:33:36" />
	<numplays>5</numplays>			<comment>Wonderful, really wonderful game. It is a hard game, difficult to play well, unforgiving, where a lot can happen, a lot of terrible things can be done to the fellow players. 

It has all the characteristics that I like in the games of the 18xx series and more. It offers a lot of strategic possibilities and a lot of freedom and possibilities to be creative.

The rules and the design are like a swiss clock, very logical and with beautiful details, but very intuitive at the same time. 

The random sequence of companies on sales guarantee a high replayability: the difficult choices of the beginning are different at each game.

As a further plus it lasts usually less than the average 18xx game.

I think it really shines with three players, but it is also very good in four. Not tried in five, possibly not the best, but not sure.

On BGG there is the possibility to download all materials and build a PnP game. It is worth it.

Very recommended... but not to the faint at heart :)

</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="66837" subtype="boardgame" collid="18717063">
	<name sortindex="1">1862: Railway Mania in the Eastern Counties</name>
		<yearpublished>2013</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1853204.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1853204_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="8"																	minplaytime="300"																	maxplaytime="300"																	playingtime="300"																	numowned="353" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="140" />			<average value="8.376" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.96214" />			<stddev value="1.1917" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-25 12:10:52" />
	<numplays>8</numplays>			<comment>Masterpiece!

This is a great simulation of a stock market and all the dirty tricks we were used to in other games of the 18xx series are gone. No more ruining a company to drop it on another player. Consequently freedom for the players to buy shares of companies of which they are not directors. And a lot of other rules changes that go all in the direction of making a game in which one wins owning the best shares and not through dirty tricks. The tricks that experienced 18xx players were used to (as the above mentioned dropping of a company, or the buying and selling shares of a company in a single stock round to lower its value) are all gone. Some 18xx veterans may not like it, but IMHO the freedom, the huge decision space that 1862 offers opens the road to a second generation 18xx, much better than the (already wonderful) way of the past.

There are still a lot of ways to interact with the other players. Just an example: can you imagine a small map where up to 16 (16!) companies can operate, each with up to 7 station tokens? There is even a phase in which one has to win an auction to have the rights to start the (perceived) best company. And it is not an easy going game for a lot of other reasons: I can mention the brutal way the trains rush. Or the crazy way shares prices can literally jump forward.

There are so many other things to like. There is a random set up of the starting 16 companies. Merge and acquisitions. Two ways to start a company. Three types of trains. Not only the decision space is huge, but the replayability is greater than in any other game I have played in my life (not only of the 18xx series). 

And so much more, without making the rules complicated, on the contrary, one can see that anything in the game has been designed to enhance ease of play, even the (simpler than usual) track tiles. As important example I cite the simplification of the revenue calculation (each station or off-map area can be counted only once, tracks of different trains can overlap, at least one of the train must run in the home station: all this makes calculation easier). 

There are no private companies: this, added to initial random set up, removes the possibilities of having  &quot;masters&quot; of the game whose proficiency is based on stats on the best companies, private or otherwise. 

Last but not least this is one of the shortest game of the series, that is really a great feat considering the depth it offers. 

As an added bonus the game is still good with only two players.

Is this game for everyone? No, please try it only if you are not afraid of heavy games. As said the rules of this game are not very heavy, but playing and playing well is heavy. But if you are like me and if you like heavy games, then do not miss it!

Games of the 18xx series are my preferred. I wanted to differentiate their rating, but till now there is none of the ones I have played  that I would give less than a 10 rating (if I did I am afraid I could not give any 10 to any other game not in the series).

Considering the above, I had decided to put at the top of my top ten list the entire 18xx series instead of the single games of the series, to leave room to other “normal” games not in the series.  But after “meeting” 1862 everything changes... this is my preferred 18xx game, this is my preferred game! So I have put it at the top of my top ten, followed by the 18xx series and then by other games.

Have I already said that I like it?
</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="68448" subtype="boardgame" collid="14176832">
	<name sortindex="1">7 Wonders</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic860217.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic860217_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="7"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="48549" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="39256" />			<average value="7.86176" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.78267" />			<stddev value="1.26857" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-10-13 02:50:26" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>I prefer player-driven games to card-driven games. Besides it seems to me that the game is a bit a collecting of points with strategy quite obvious and a lot of tactical moves. If you like games in which cards are so powerful, you may like it, surely more than me.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="36888" subtype="boardgame" collid="7130509">
	<name sortindex="1">After the Flood</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic352448.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic352448_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="3"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="1003" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="837" />			<average value="6.90967" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.25093" />			<stddev value="1.40735" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:17:23" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>Interesting game, sometimes tense to play, but with some problems. 

It seems more tactical than strategical: there is not so much story. Each turn is almost independent from the others; not completely, but a bit too much for my taste. I prefer to have a game in which an important move in one turn really &quot;shapes&quot; the rest of the game and not only in the possibility to win or not. Instead this game seem to give more importance to the single tactical choice, still depending by the context, but with too short &quot;memory&quot;.

The real problem seem to be that, contrary to what the designer suggests, it is better to pass as last as possible. If you pass as first the other players may ruin your position completely. The price to pay for each further move after someone passes doesn&#039;t balance things enough. 

So what happens is that there is a common strategy adopted: trying to postpone the moment you pass, making very &quot;small&quot; actions. As a consequence, the workers are placed in the only place where they can&#039;t be attacked : only one worker in this safe area, and you can do all your trade, as slowly as possible. The other areas on the board are almost ignored when you have to place workers (with some exception: like in the end when they are worth points, or because there is a single area that can give a valuable good or to start a new empire). 

So the game becomes a fight to be the last to pass and mostly a military game. The tactical choices, most based on timing, are not the ones I like.

Still not a bad game, with tense moments and still worth to try, but not the best of Wallace, IMHO.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="22545" subtype="boardgame" collid="5616700">
	<name sortindex="1">Age of Empires III: The Age of Discovery</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic990261.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic990261_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="7100" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="8153" />			<average value="7.61937" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.42877" />			<stddev value="1.34947" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-12-08 15:33:54" />
	<numplays>10</numplays>			<comment>Nice mix of two beautiful mechanics: worker placement and area control.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="4098" subtype="boardgame" collid="3689211">
	<name sortindex="1">Age of Steam</name>
		<yearpublished>2002</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic429576.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic429576_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="5750" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="6205" />			<average value="7.72003" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.48516" />			<stddev value="1.64931" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 02:16:37" />
	<numplays>9</numplays>			<comment>The only reason it doesn&#039;t get a 10 is: it stresses more the tactical/logistic aspect than the resource/money management, which I would prefer instead. Only taste, in any case, the game is very good.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="31260" subtype="boardgame" collid="6252189">
	<name sortindex="1">Agricola</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic259085.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic259085_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="150"																	playingtime="150"																	numowned="49244" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="41180" />			<average value="8.10282" />
			<bayesaverage value="8.01809" />			<stddev value="1.56385" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-25 11:58:13" />
	<numplays>25</numplays>			<comment>After all the hype, I played... and I liked it, but I was not enthusiastic... then I played again, then I played again, then... I am hooked... What a beautiful game! You can adopt a strategy and see how your strategy develop... and each time new ideas, for new strategies... Also, thinking of the strategy, often it is easier to think more on the things you can do as a farmer (e.g. maybe I should cultivate more before acquiring sheep) and not in terms of points... Very very very recommended (in spite of the hype). 

UPDATE March 2013
I still consider it a wonderful game, but I moved down the rating to 9 because I like more &quot;Ora et labora&quot; that gives a similar experience, but which I like more.

UPDATE October 2015
Rating lowered to 8. I prefer Fields of Arle, and also Ora et Labora and Caverna. This should be reflected in my ratings.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="76" subtype="boardgame" collid="1085131">
	<name sortindex="1">Air Baron</name>
		<yearpublished>1996</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic163634.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic163634_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="850" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="687" />			<average value="6.39525" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.91116" />			<stddev value="1.53574" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:19:58" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Too much dependent on luck</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="110277" subtype="boardgame" collid="25136383">
	<name sortindex="1">Among the Stars</name>
		<yearpublished>2012</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2037906.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2037906_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="6001" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="3937" />			<average value="7.29895" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.01399" />			<stddev value="1.17567" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-10-12 13:28:23" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>A tactical game based on cards: not my cup of tea.  </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="5404" subtype="boardgame" collid="5187384">
	<name sortindex="1">Amun-Re</name>
		<yearpublished>2003</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic547986.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic547986_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="6410" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="6780" />			<average value="7.37718" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.18867" />			<stddev value="1.21126" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2007-07-29 12:32:42" />
	<numplays>5</numplays>			<comment>I like it, but somehow it doesn&#039;t excite me.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="29934" subtype="boardgame" collid="6722637">
	<name sortindex="1">Amyitis</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic224426.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic224426_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="3101" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="2457" />			<average value="7.00703" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.66163" />			<stddev value="1.25985" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:56:32" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Attempt of a rating after only one game. I don&#039;t think I want to play the game again, there are many games that I prefer to this. It is not bad, but not exciting either.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="39339" subtype="boardgame" collid="7523425">
	<name sortindex="1">Android</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic400196.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic400196_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="4913" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="3026" />			<average value="6.77283" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.51278" />			<stddev value="1.77315" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 03:05:28" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>Reasons it doesn&#039;t get a higher ranking: it has a bit too much luck for my taste and it lasts too long for what it gives to the player.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="323" subtype="boardgame" collid="1085259">
	<name sortindex="1">Anno 1452</name>
		<yearpublished>1999</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic324971.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic324971_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="386" >
				<rating value="2">			<usersrated value="167" />			<average value="6.03952" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.59338" />			<stddev value="1.40729" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:21:41" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>A game which should have been playtested much more. </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="19600" subtype="boardgame" collid="4614915">
	<name sortindex="1">Antike</name>
		<yearpublished>2005</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic171444.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic171444_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="3421" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="4129" />			<average value="7.15113" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.88643" />			<stddev value="1.3397" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2009-10-06 04:16:41" />
	<numplays>16</numplays>			<comment>Wonderful civilation game with a map. My preferred one (so much better than other I have tried, like Tempus or Mare Nostrum). Better than Wallenstein (that is of the same weight, but with much less freedom and possibility to express a personal way to play). No luck involved. Many paths to victory. No waiting time. Not too long. What else can I ask for?</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="104955" subtype="boardgame" collid="13826500">
	<name sortindex="1">Antike Duellum</name>
		<yearpublished>2012</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1282841.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1282841_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="75"																	maxplaytime="75"																	playingtime="75"																	numowned="1583" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="1022" />			<average value="7.26669" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.52613" />			<stddev value="1.28704" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-06-26 12:26:21" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>This is an attempt rating after only two games. I am not so eager to play it again and this is the reason of the rating. Maybe I am spoiled by Polis, a much better two-players game in my opinion.

What I find missing is the strategic tension. There are cards one needs to win, but acquiring those cards is somehow not exciting as not directly related to strategic objectives. So this catching points seems a bit boring. 

I may be wrong and if /when I play it again I will update the rating. Still a rondel game, with no luck, clean rules, lot of choices: so it is unlikely that the rating will go lower than this.
</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="13122" subtype="boardgame" collid="7546130">
	<name sortindex="1">Antiquity</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic138460.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic138460_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="2176" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="2028" />			<average value="7.83596" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.2381" />			<stddev value="1.62502" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-12-28 03:42:02" />
	<numplays>21</numplays>			<comment>Love at first sight.

Antiquity offers all I like in games. It is a heavy and beautiful resource management game that as a bonus has an important spatial element, with the map different each time.

It is beautiful in two. It has the right balance between having the possibility to follow your strategies without your opponent messing your plans up, but at the same time there is interaction.

There is a multitude of chits to be managed, but this doesn&#039;t disturb me, actually I like to touch and see all those pieces as the game evolves as a story.

Very recommended if you like heavy strategic games as I do. 

</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="3548" subtype="boardgame" collid="1085261">
	<name sortindex="1">Assault on Hoth: The Empire Strikes Back</name>
		<yearpublished>1988</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2477264.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2477264_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="737" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="404" />			<average value="6.99979" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.01088" />			<stddev value="1.34236" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-01-03 02:36:32" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Not too many choices and after a few games the fun is over.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="8051" subtype="boardgame" collid="1412822">
	<name sortindex="1">Attika</name>
		<yearpublished>2003</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic33096.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic33096_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="5217" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="5704" />			<average value="7.04084" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.84703" />			<stddev value="1.23431" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:18:11" />
	<numplays>14</numplays>			<comment>Nice simple game. A bit too much luck for my taste. Good for non-gamers and children.

UPDATE
I decreased the rating because a lot of better games (also light games) have appeared in the last years that i would prefer nearly always to this.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="162" subtype="boardgame" collid="1085288">
	<name sortindex="5">The Awful Green Things From Outer Space</name>
		<yearpublished>1979</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic949958.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic949958_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="3634" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="2126" />			<average value="6.47338" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.18992" />			<stddev value="1.37968" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2003-12-31 13:20:26" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>							</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="986" subtype="boardgame" collid="1323733">
	<name sortindex="1">Babel</name>
		<yearpublished>2000</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1629288.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1629288_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="4535" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="2916" />			<average value="6.72832" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.47061" />			<stddev value="1.24886" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:12:22" />
	<numplays>31</numplays>			<comment>Best games of the 2-players Kosmos series, even better than LoR The Confrontation (which was my preferred of the series before trying this). Please give a look at my review for details.

UPDATE
My taste have changed a bit with the years passing, so I am much less attracted to play games like this at the moment.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="3955" subtype="boardgame" collid="5132432">
	<name sortindex="1">BANG!</name>
		<yearpublished>2002</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1170986.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1170986_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="4"																	maxplayers="7"																	minplaytime="20"																	maxplaytime="40"																	playingtime="40"																	numowned="18874" >
				<rating value="2">			<usersrated value="17081" />			<average value="6.60055" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.48967" />			<stddev value="1.45617" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 02:14:16" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Not at all the kind of game I like (something like a bluff party game). It is not even as fun as it is supposed to be. Besides there are really almost no choices (the way to play for each role is extremely obvious). If you want a similar party game, look at Werewolf instead, much better IMHO.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="9013" subtype="boardgame" collid="1085153">
	<name sortindex="1">Battle of the Five Armies</name>
		<yearpublished>1975</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic50645.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic50645_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="84" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="30" />			<average value="5.7" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.50204" />			<stddev value="1.66633" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2003-12-31 13:10:44" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>							</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="37111" subtype="boardgame" collid="7482375">
	<name sortindex="1">Battlestar Galactica</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic354500.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic354500_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="240"																	playingtime="240"																	numowned="23673" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="21614" />			<average value="7.81243" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.68755" />			<stddev value="1.53381" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-12-08 15:16:52" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>I would play a game of the discover-the-traitor kind as a short fun game (e.g. The Resistance), but I would prefer strategy games to Battlestar Galactica any time.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="50750" subtype="boardgame" collid="13854956">
	<name sortindex="1">Belfort</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1368514.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1368514_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="5228" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="4253" />			<average value="7.39379" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.09851" />			<stddev value="1.20738" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:10:42" />
	<numplays>5</numplays>			<comment>Solid game with a nice theme that makes it attractive for children and non-gamers.

The reason it doesn&#039;t score higher for me is that winning is more decided by calculation on small differences in points than by strategic decisions.

UPDATE
Lowered the rating because it is a bit boring after a while, a bit &quot;flat&quot;, few significant and tense choices. </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="235" subtype="boardgame" collid="1085319">
	<name sortindex="1">Blackbeard</name>
		<yearpublished>1991</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic164665.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic164665_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="2295" >
				<rating value="2">			<usersrated value="1202" />			<average value="6.34503" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.99449" />			<stddev value="1.58261" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 02:00:07" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>A lot of rules. Almost no choices. This means very bad, for me.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="9446" subtype="boardgame" collid="2072067">
	<name sortindex="1">Blue Moon</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic174185.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic174185_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="5883" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="4815" />			<average value="6.77149" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.58876" />			<stddev value="1.49695" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:49:29" />
	<numplays>14</numplays>			<comment>I don&#039;t like CCG, but this is something else: first of all you don&#039;t need a lot of money (expansions have a fix number of cards). Second: each race has its own style and you have to adopt special strategies to win. Third: it is much fun to play, funnier IMO than Magic.

UPDATE
My taste has changed a bit with the years passing, so I am much less attracted to play games like this at the moment.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="21882" subtype="boardgame" collid="4614918">
	<name sortindex="1">Blue Moon City</name>
		<yearpublished>2006</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic114772.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic114772_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="5974" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="6413" />			<average value="7.06339" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.89226" />			<stddev value="1.20017" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-09-02 02:28:59" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>I had a lot of expectation about this game. I find it cold, really cold and not exciting at all. I can play it, it is not bad. But not good either.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="11" subtype="boardgame" collid="16557260">
	<name sortindex="1">Bohnanza</name>
		<yearpublished>1997</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic69366.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic69366_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="7"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="32932" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="24497" />			<average value="7.08778" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.00624" />			<stddev value="1.27816" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-08-20 10:59:46" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>Light game. Not too bad, but too luck dependent and too few significant decisions.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="15839" subtype="boardgame" collid="5674338">
	<name sortindex="1">Bonaparte at Marengo</name>
		<yearpublished>2005</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic289180.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic289180_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="1117" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="827" />			<average value="7.41359" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.51698" />			<stddev value="1.45705" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-01-21 01:22:54" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Attempt rating after only one not finished and one finished game. It is innovative, but it seems a bit dry.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="127060" subtype="boardgame" collid="18542755">
	<name sortindex="1">Bora Bora</name>
		<yearpublished>2013</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1542342.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1542342_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="7289" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="5073" />			<average value="7.65159" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.37236" />			<stddev value="1.32493" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-25 12:01:57" />
	<numplays>7</numplays>			<comment>Although it has some luck, I like it, not only because luck eventually is not important (the stronger player wins 99% of the times), but because the game is good and exciting to play. 

A lot of ways to win, really a brain burner at certain crucial points.

The game creates many different situations, forcing the player to adapt and adopt new strategies depending on the current state of the game. The interaction is partly due to the typical &quot;who comes first gets the best&quot;, but even more because one has to continuously look at what the others are aiming at.

Replayability is high, but somehow less than I expected given the variability of the game.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="28720" subtype="boardgame" collid="6107134">
	<name sortindex="1">Brass</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic261878.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic261878_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="9550" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="9143" />			<average value="8.03209" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.85527" />			<stddev value="1.4579" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2008-09-14 08:48:21" />
	<numplays>13</numplays>			<comment>I like Wallace&#039;s games and this is my preferred one. This games needs to be played more to see the gem it is. Very recommended. </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="240" subtype="boardgame" collid="1086805">
	<name sortindex="1">Britannia</name>
		<yearpublished>1986</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic106711.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic106711_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="240"																	maxplaytime="240"																	playingtime="240"																	numowned="4741" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="3323" />			<average value="7.25745" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.90912" />			<stddev value="1.4761" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2004-01-01 10:21:45" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>							</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="144592" subtype="boardgame" collid="20565624">
	<name sortindex="1">Bruxelles 1893</name>
		<yearpublished>2013</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1726346.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1726346_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="50"																	maxplaytime="125"																	playingtime="125"																	numowned="2556" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="2203" />			<average value="7.67393" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.12817" />			<stddev value="1.28394" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-06-13 06:27:00" />
	<numplays>6</numplays>			<comment>Nice game, every move counts in many directions, but it is not my preferred kind of game: a bit too light, a bit more tactical than strategical and, more than anything else, the decision space is too limited. Choices are interesting, but usually they are limited to a set of possibilities. Winning is through opportunistic play, exploiting at the best the situation: a puzzle-like experience not offering room for a creative personalized play (more something like choices between some defined roads than roads that can be opened by players). So this is not what I search in the greatest games.

Thus said, I like the mechanics (with the possible exception of the bidding that favors too much the last one to play in a column), and the game is short and easy, so not the greatest game, but a good game, especially  when time is little. 

I suggest to try it, at least to give a look at the very original way a lot of mechanics are combined together.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="548" subtype="boardgame" collid="1085285">
	<name sortindex="1">Buck Rogers: Battle for the 25th Century Game</name>
		<yearpublished>1988</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic694341.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic694341_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="1246" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="656" />			<average value="6.39966" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.87849" />			<stddev value="1.40655" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-08-28 04:35:08" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>							</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="146" subtype="boardgame" collid="1085168">
	<name sortindex="1">Buy Low Sell High</name>
		<yearpublished>1996</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic977869.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic977869_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="1126" >
				<rating value="2">			<usersrated value="792" />			<average value="6.17586" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.84512" />			<stddev value="1.19914" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 02:06:09" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>							</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="19237" subtype="boardgame" collid="13911879">
	<name sortindex="1">Ca$h &#039;n Gun$</name>
		<yearpublished>2005</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic87523.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic87523_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="4"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="7393" >
				<rating value="2">			<usersrated value="8170" />			<average value="6.6954" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.58224" />			<stddev value="1.34257" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 02:04:34" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>A &quot;party game&quot;, suitable also for children: not a game that I would like to play.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="132" subtype="boardgame" collid="1783734">
	<name sortindex="1">Caesar &amp; Cleopatra</name>
		<yearpublished>1997</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic192517.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic192517_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="5507" >
				<rating value="2">			<usersrated value="3618" />			<average value="6.46093" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.27878" />			<stddev value="1.17448" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 02:04:08" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>Boring and uninteresting card game.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="822" subtype="boardgame" collid="5238166">
	<name sortindex="1">Carcassonne</name>
		<yearpublished>2000</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2337577.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2337577_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="72890" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="54848" />			<average value="7.43722" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.34222" />			<stddev value="1.29851" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:18:30" />
	<numplays>50</numplays>			<comment>Everyone likes this game: grandparents, children, gamers, not gamers. Just a bit too much luck for my taste.

UPDATE
getting bored (but after many plays)

UPDATE
My taste have changed a bit with the years passing, so I am much less attracted to play games like this at the moment.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="2993" subtype="boardgame" collid="1412829">
	<name sortindex="1">Carcassonne: Expansion 1 – Inns &amp; Cathedrals</name>
		<yearpublished>2002</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2659943.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2659943_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="26200" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="13990" />			<average value="7.60188" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.45941" />			<stddev value="1.11409" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-10-31 13:34:21" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>							</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="7717" subtype="boardgame" collid="1783733">
	<name sortindex="1">Carcassonne: The Castle</name>
		<yearpublished>2003</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2606367.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2606367_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="8321" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="5950" />			<average value="7.07922" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.87564" />			<stddev value="1.27451" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:12:32" />
	<numplays>31</numplays>			<comment>Subtle changes to original game by Knizia, which make the game similar to the original, but magically much more appealing to &quot;heavy&quot; gamers.

UPDATE
My taste have changed a bit with the years passing, so I am much less attracted to play games like this at the moment.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="16216" subtype="boardgame" collid="7765779">
	<name sortindex="1">Carcassonne: The Discovery</name>
		<yearpublished>2005</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic134384.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic134384_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="2827" >
				<rating value="2">			<usersrated value="1800" />			<average value="6.53347" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.21917" />			<stddev value="1.34051" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 02:00:50" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Really uninteresting.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="481" subtype="boardgame" collid="1412831">
	<name sortindex="1">Carolus Magnus</name>
		<yearpublished>2000</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic130679.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic130679_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="3349" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="2925" />			<average value="6.86531" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.58525" />			<stddev value="1.33488" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-05-02 13:01:29" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>Nice abstract game, especially with the variant posted on BGG that reduces the effect of randomness. But a bit too light for my tastes.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="25823" subtype="boardgame" collid="6800555">
	<name sortindex="1">Cartagena 2. The Pirate&#039;s Nest</name>
		<yearpublished>2006</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic252156.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic252156_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="1056" >
				<rating value="2">			<usersrated value="762" />			<average value="6.5086" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.01586" />			<stddev value="1.13784" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2009-09-21 08:04:12" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Not the kind of game I like. Too light and luck dependent for my taste.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="13" subtype="boardgame" collid="1413638">
	<name sortindex="1">Catan</name>
		<yearpublished>1995</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2419375.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2419375_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="76373" >
				<rating value="2">			<usersrated value="55766" />			<average value="7.32369" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.19102" />			<stddev value="1.43977" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-12-27 13:45:55" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>Too much luck and too few &quot;strategic&quot; choices for my taste. I have played this game the first time in May 2004, and I think that nowadays there are much better games, even if only considering &quot;family&quot; games.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="102794" subtype="boardgame" collid="20879462">
	<name sortindex="1">Caverna: The Cave Farmers</name>
		<yearpublished>2013</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1790789.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1790789_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="7"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="210"																	playingtime="210"																	numowned="14075" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="10751" />			<average value="8.25138" />
			<bayesaverage value="8.05719" />			<stddev value="1.39895" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-25 11:53:16" />
	<numplays>20</numplays>			<comment>Possibly the best game by a great designer (Uwe Rosenberg has affirmed that Caverna is his best game, someone thinks it is just advertisement, I think it can just be simply true!).

It is very similar to Agricola, but so much better in so many ways. And I think I like it even more than Ora et Labora, that was my favorite of Uwe&#039;s games until I tried Caverna.

Agricola was more influenced by cards. Here everything is available to everyone from the beginning, but in a very limited quantity. And I agree with a post here on BGG, the better players know this game, the more it will be a real fight for the most valuable things. So much interaction, a lot of nice tension. And very personalized playing is possible. There are many paths to go (I think even more than in Ora et Labora that I loved for this). Strategy is more important than tactics (as in the other two games mentioned, maybe even more).

It is very thematic and realistic (as Agricola, maybe even  more): this makes the game more intuitive to play than Ora et Labora where the effects of buildings were quite weird (in Caverna there are very few things that sound a bit strange, most of the time names of items are easily connected to real things in the dwarfs settings). And the theme is nice also for children at the point that I have never before seen my daughter as excited to play a game as her first game of Caverna. 

One (tiny) thing that I am missing is the rondel for goods that was offered in Ora et Labora that reduced the bookkeeping (but I do see that probably in this case it would have been impossible to adopt it without losing some of the flexibility in goods grow). 

Caverna is great game in itself, it doesn&#039;t need comparison with its predecessors: not only it is better than Uwe&#039;s other games, but there are very few games, if any, between the many that I have played in my life, that I would prefer to it.  Eventually the most important thing is not the many good attributes of the game, but something that can only be appreciated by playing: this game is incredibly beautiful to play, satisfying, engaging. Gaming experience at his best. It should belong to any gamer&#039;s collection, both if already owning other Uwe&#039;s games or not. 

Masterpiece. Very recommended. 

UPDATE November 2014
I like Caverna still a lot, but I prefer Fields of Arle. Caverna is still a 10, but Arle has taken its place in my top ten.

UPDATE October 2015
Rating moved from 10 to 9. Although I still consider it  a great game, I think that I would prefer Fields of Arle to it, any time. And this should be reflected in my ratings.

 </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="18602" subtype="boardgame" collid="3746990">
	<name sortindex="1">Caylus</name>
		<yearpublished>2005</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1638795.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1638795_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="150"																	playingtime="150"																	numowned="19472" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="19649" />			<average value="7.89428" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.77345" />			<stddev value="1.48209" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-25 11:47:49" />
	<numplays>16</numplays>			<comment>So many paths to victory: you can really use your own personal style. Incredibly exciting, no waiting time, strong interaction between players (it seems subtle in the first games, but it is there!), every game is different. A masterpiece. Try it if you haven&#039;t done so yet.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="171" subtype="boardgame" collid="14223264">
	<name sortindex="1">Chess</name>
		<yearpublished>1475</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic260745.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic260745_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="22417" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="17417" />			<average value="7.09508" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.94372" />			<stddev value="1.84266" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-09-02 03:09:16" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Computers can play better than humans. Boring and tiring. I like Go so much more than there is no chance I would play a game of chess.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="31730" subtype="boardgame" collid="7130519">
	<name sortindex="1">Chicago Express</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1566274.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1566274_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="4871" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="5323" />			<average value="7.23986" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.02999" />			<stddev value="1.32999" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-11-05 14:40:10" />
	<numplays>19</numplays>			<comment>A wonderful game experience: it is playable in less than one hour, with tense and interesting choices, players interaction and no luck...WOW!</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="554" subtype="boardgame" collid="1413660">
	<name sortindex="4">La Città</name>
		<yearpublished>2000</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic274350.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic274350_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="5466" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="4438" />			<average value="7.131" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.88927" />			<stddev value="1.26278" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-09-08 04:41:07" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>Nice game, but I have the feeling that the choices are quite obvious. All the scoring and counting makes the game less fun.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="5782" subtype="boardgame" collid="13761599">
	<name sortindex="1">Coloretto</name>
		<yearpublished>2003</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic149765.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic149765_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="14486" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="12032" />			<average value="6.98429" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.8848" />			<stddev value="1.11927" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-01-03 02:37:48" />
	<numplays>5</numplays>			<comment>Used to play with my daughter... at least better than Zooloretto IMHO</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="14105" subtype="boardgame" collid="3689240">
	<name sortindex="1">Commands &amp; Colors: Ancients</name>
		<yearpublished>2006</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic132447.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic132447_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="7938" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="6217" />			<average value="7.82502" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.56066" />			<stddev value="1.41682" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:08:49" />
	<numplays>29</numplays>			<comment>Fun game (much better than Memoir&#039;44). Not a strategic game, a lot of luck, but entertaining.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="124361" subtype="boardgame" collid="16396846">
	<name sortindex="1">Concordia</name>
		<yearpublished>2013</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1980675.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1980675_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="100"																	maxplaytime="100"																	playingtime="100"																	numowned="5868" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="5460" />			<average value="7.86314" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.57868" />			<stddev value="1.1412" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-12-28 04:13:40" />
	<numplays>11</numplays>			<comment>Concordia has very elegant, beautiful and easy to teach rules offering a deep game experience at the same time.

Very replayable: different situations in each game. Very short waiting time (one move for player, one after the other, as most of the games by its designer). It is easy to concentrate on the game (not fiddly at all). Very beautiful material, both the map and the wooden pieces. It offers both strategy and tactics. 

The only thing that stops me giving it a ten is that the choices are somehow interesting, but the effect of choosing one path instead of another is not dramatic, very few points are at stage. This allows for a well-balanced game, but a bit less exciting and tense to play. But it is close to being a ten and I can possibly increase the rating in the future.

It has the further advantage that it is a game for all occasions, since it can be taught in a few minutes, it is not long  and it scales very well (it can be played from 2 to 5 players). 

Recommended.</comment>				<wishlistcomment>Maybe better with some sleeves, but size? If it is true that they are the same as Agrcola then FFP purple (2 packs)</wishlistcomment></item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="72225" subtype="boardgame" collid="14779998">
	<name sortindex="1">CO₂</name>
		<yearpublished>2012</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1350204.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1350204_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="3186" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="2355" />			<average value="7.2795" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.8584" />			<stddev value="1.43805" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-12-28 04:22:05" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>The first disappointment of the 2012 Essen crop.

It seems &quot;complicated&quot; to play in the wrong direction: a lot of micro things to pay attention to, but there seems to be no corresponding depth in the offered choices.

I may change my opinion with further plays, but at the moment I am not so eager to try it again. 

It is a matter of taste: I miss the wide strategic depth that I am searching in games, substituted by a set of tactics and calculations that I find more tiring than rewarding. 

You may enjoy it, I feel the love and effort of the designer, just for some reasons I don&#039;t like it.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="29603" subtype="boardgame" collid="20257779">
	<name sortindex="1">D-Day at Omaha Beach</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2212619.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2212619_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="480"																	maxplaytime="480"																	playingtime="480"																	numowned="2149" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="853" />			<average value="8.29848" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.96767" />			<stddev value="1.41124" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-06-19 08:21:21" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>I should not have bought this game. I thought that I would have liked to play a game especially designed for solitaire play. The problem is that almost any time I push myself to buy a wargame it is because I have forgotten the last time  I had tried and then not played the last acquired wargame more than once. The real fact is that I don&#039;t like any more that the bookkeeping requires more energy than the creative deep choices I search in games (there are exceptions, there are wargames that I do like, notably Maria, but because they are &quot;different&quot;).

So after one play I don&#039;t want to play it again. If I strictly adhered to the meaning of the ratings here on BGG (oriented to subjective &quot;want-to-play&quot; instead of &quot;how good-is-the game-for-its-genre&quot;), I should have rated it lower. But this would have not been fair: this game is good in its genre, just it is not my cup of tea. So I try a middle approach for my rating. For people that like wargames and solitary wargames: this is a good game, one of the best solitary wargames. But for people that like me prefer  to use most of their mental energy on significant choices and not on bookkeeping... probably better avoid it.

I may try to play it again if in some future I don&#039;t find people to play with.</comment>				<wishlistcomment>Sleeves
Number of Cards: 55
Mayday Sleeve Size: Chimera Sized 57.5 x 89 mm
Fantasy Flight Sleeve Size: ??Standard American?? 2 1/4&quot; x 3 1/2&quot; (56x87 MM)</wishlistcomment></item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="393" subtype="boardgame" collid="1085392">
	<name sortindex="1">Dinosaurs of the Lost World</name>
		<yearpublished>1987</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic675608.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic675608_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="572" >
				<rating value="1">			<usersrated value="355" />			<average value="6.52369" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.81541" />			<stddev value="1.51663" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2008-10-27 09:52:22" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>							</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="62219" subtype="boardgame" collid="11640922">
	<name sortindex="1">Dominant Species</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1037851.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1037851_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="240"																	playingtime="240"																	numowned="11555" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="10748" />			<average value="7.88863" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.7217" />			<stddev value="1.48344" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-12-27 12:37:14" />
	<numplays>14</numplays>			<comment>Beautiful and original game. 

It could have some small disadvantages for my taste: it is less predictable than I usually like (a bit of luck, e.g. when drawing the elements, and a bit too much depending on which opponent players choose to &quot;punish&quot;). 

BUT... 

The game is really different each time it is played and it develops in ways difficult to foresee: this is somehow part of the disadvantage I was mentioning above, but it is also its strength at the same time, because very thematically it represents the struggle to become dominant in a dramatically changing environment. 

The games are beautifully tense and fun. It is also nice to see how a single game develops, almost like reading a story that we are writing while playing it.

The length that could have been a problem is solved easily using the official variant of discarding 4 event cards (you can find it here on BGG).

The rules are beautiful and logical, without exceptions, intuitive because very well matched with the theme. My eight year old daughter manages to play DS, and to play well! No doubt about any rule (she can count dominance at a glance, surely better than me :) ).

All considered, if you like boardgaming it would be a mistake to miss this top game, IMHO. Very recommended.

UPDATE
What a pity I can&#039;t give this game more than 10: wonderful. All disadvantages I mentioned above disappeared after really getting into the game. I suggest playing with the variant mentioned above: besides being a faster game, it becomes more balanced. And what a game! Every single step is a tense and beautiful choice. Every game so different from the other. It is thematic. Rules are crystal clear and logical. After playing more games you, like me, may come to regret that 10 is the maximum you can give to a game here on BGG :P</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="36218" subtype="boardgame" collid="7191698">
	<name sortindex="1">Dominion</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic394356.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic394356_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="58250" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="46231" />			<average value="7.75429" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.66979" />			<stddev value="1.43018" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:08:59" />
	<numplays>50</numplays>			<comment>Wonderful game, fun to play, much more interaction than in Race for the Galaxy. I thank my Geekbuddies and more generally BGG for letting me discover this gem.

UPDATE
After 50 games starts to feel a bit repetitive for me. But please try it in any case. It is much fun.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="97207" subtype="boardgame" collid="14925596">
	<name sortindex="1">Dungeon Petz</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1103979.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1103979_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="8859" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="6634" />			<average value="7.63561" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.41175" />			<stddev value="1.30387" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-10-31 03:38:46" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>Original and fun game (especially the rules are really a pleasure to read). Also difficult to play well.

Theme is nice and well implemented.

The reason that it doesn&#039;t score higher for me is that there is more tactic than strategy: I prefer games that offer more &quot;freedom&quot; and &quot;creativity&quot; in the strategy realm. In Dungeon Petz there are interesting choices, but more of the calculable sort and more &quot;scripted&quot;. The customers card for example determine the way you play in great  amount, there is still some &quot;freedom&quot;, but not enough for my taste. </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="2346" subtype="boardgame" collid="4614873">
	<name sortindex="1">DVONN</name>
		<yearpublished>2001</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2070667.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2070667_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="4100" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="3328" />			<average value="7.42265" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.06361" />			<stddev value="1.34756" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-12-08 15:32:19" />
	<numplays>32</numplays>			<comment>This is a solid good game, but my interest in abstract games is much less that it used to be. </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="72125" subtype="boardgame" collid="13590135">
	<name sortindex="1">Eclipse</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1173341.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1173341_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="200"																	playingtime="200"																	numowned="18410" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="16585" />			<average value="8.06285" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.91851" />			<stddev value="1.48262" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-30 14:30:34" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>Beautiful game. An epic space game played in a bit more than two hours: so much happens in that short time.

The game is conceived to be extremely playable, keeping the bookkeeping at the minimum, offering the best experience with the minimum effort.

The only (but significant) thing that I don&#039;t like is that eventually battles count AND battles are resolved by dice rolls, in a not completely satisfying way.

A good game in any case. </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="10" subtype="boardgame" collid="1084512">
	<name sortindex="1">Elfenland</name>
		<yearpublished>1998</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic168036.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic168036_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="7077" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="6195" />			<average value="6.7677" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.62298" />			<stddev value="1.24759" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-01-03 02:38:05" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Too much luck and really not the sort of game I like. No meaningful decisions, apart of some obvious tactical moves. I play it occasionally with my young daughter.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="20134" subtype="boardgame" collid="6652816">
	<name sortindex="5">The End of the Triumvirate</name>
		<yearpublished>2005</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic158273.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic158273_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="3"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="1808" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="1452" />			<average value="6.84419" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.40081" />			<stddev value="1.27409" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:18:03" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Attempt rating after only one game. Playing seems to me like collecting points / conditions that bring players to the victory, but without so much excitement.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="33160" subtype="boardgame" collid="7608690">
	<name sortindex="1">Endeavor</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic379881.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic379881_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="6256" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="7503" />			<average value="7.46704" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.28735" />			<stddev value="1.2051" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:15:00" />
	<numplays>11</numplays>			<comment>Nice middle-weight game with very elegant rules.

Maybe difficult to win by a big strategical plan, instead it seems it is won by the sum of many good tactical moves (I prefer strategy over tactics). But I may be wrong, and I want to play the game more to discover if it has more &quot;substance&quot;.

Surely it is nice to play and to try new combination of buildings / ways to victory.

It is fast and this, together with the elegance of the rules, is a very good thing (even if it often seems to finish too soon).

UPDATE March 2013
There are so many games at the moment that I prefer to this that I decreased the rating accordingly.
</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="7805" subtype="boardgame" collid="1783731">
	<name sortindex="1">Fearsome Floors</name>
		<yearpublished>2003</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic163508.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic163508_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="7"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="5508" >
				<rating value="2">			<usersrated value="5678" />			<average value="6.67176" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.52467" />			<stddev value="1.21183" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:22:22" />
	<numplays>8</numplays>			<comment>Funny game, but very few choices. It is not a &quot;gamer&#039;s game&quot; and a bit disappointing also as a &quot;family game&quot;.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="32125" subtype="boardgame" collid="7765777">
	<name sortindex="1">Felix: The Cat in the Sack</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic253489.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic253489_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="20"																	maxplaytime="20"																	playingtime="20"																	numowned="4183" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="3780" />			<average value="6.61754" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.43102" />			<stddev value="1.19111" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-12-08 15:20:27" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Too light for my tastes.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="159675" subtype="boardgame" collid="23946857">
	<name sortindex="1">Fields of Arle</name>
		<yearpublished>2014</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2225968.png</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2225968_t.png</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="3160" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="1579" />			<average value="8.35291" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.44263" />			<stddev value="1.19317" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-11-23 11:17:01" />
	<numplays>24</numplays>			<comment>See my review at https://boardgamegeek.com/thread/1274148/uwe-what-have-you-done-again</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="173" subtype="boardgame" collid="1086080">
	<name sortindex="1">Formula Dé</name>
		<yearpublished>1991</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic168167.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic168167_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="10"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="6756" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="6760" />			<average value="7.00019" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.81958" />			<stddev value="1.4015" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-12-08 15:27:31" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Very boring.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="12891" subtype="boardgame" collid="4614864">
	<name sortindex="1">Friedrich</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1064931.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1064931_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="210"																	maxplaytime="210"																	playingtime="210"																	numowned="2562" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="2019" />			<average value="7.57732" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.00526" />			<stddev value="1.5323" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-12-25 03:28:45" />
	<numplays>5</numplays>			<comment>Wonderful game. You can feel the love and the time the author dedicated to it. Very easy rules. Incredibly deep in play (without being tiring). Fun. Tense till the end. A feast for people that, like me, prefer strategy over tactics. A game in which you, the gamer, are in control. A game in which you, the gamer, can choose your personal way to victory. A game that reaches this without using a complicated set of rules, and let you concentrate on the game and the strategy instead. In two words: highly recommended (only warning: it is quite long).

UPDATE
It doesn&#039;t scores higher because of the too powerful effect of the  fate cards (a kind of luck deciding who wins, but at least not deciding the way people play). Also a bit too long, especially considering that the players not playing Prussia (particularly the French player) have sometimes to wait a bit too long. Both problems are supposed to be solved by Maria, a game that hopefully  I am going to try soon.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="12166" subtype="boardgame" collid="7172161">
	<name sortindex="1">Funkenschlag</name>
		<yearpublished>2001</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic186713.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic186713_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="904" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="674" />			<average value="7.61949" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.48803" />			<stddev value="1.50278" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-07-28 09:02:00" />
	<numplays>7</numplays>			<comment> I liked it a lot at the beginning, but it tends to be repetitive after some games.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="27463" subtype="boardgame" collid="7297639">
	<name sortindex="1">Galactic Emperor</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic252954.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic252954_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="1299" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="1303" />			<average value="6.6828" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.26247" />			<stddev value="1.40504" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:55:16" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>The game is not bad and has the advantage to be not too long, given the kind of game it is (a strategic space game). I have discovered lately that I am less interested in these sort of games (I didn&#039;t like Starcraft either). I prefer resource management games and more generally games in which other can ruin your plans, but not completely destroy them (e.g. Kingmaking).

In GE I have noticed that being last in the first turn can be an enormous disadvantage, especially if playing with many players.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="6472" subtype="boardgame" collid="3689255">
	<name sortindex="3">A Game of Thrones (first edition)</name>
		<yearpublished>2003</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1222116.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1222116_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="8449" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="8891" />			<average value="7.33416" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.14074" />			<stddev value="1.55787" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-09-08 04:42:38" />
	<numplays>6</numplays>			<comment>It combines the tension and the theme of a wargame with the fun of a German game. Recommended.

UPDATE: due to his long playing time and the fact that it doesn&#039;t scale well (not so nice with fewer players) I play this game very rarely, so I have decreased my rating.

UPDATE
I played one game that seemed so long (in a not nice way). So I decreased the rating
</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="1471" subtype="boardgame" collid="1085368">
	<name sortindex="1">Gangsters</name>
		<yearpublished>1992</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic56244.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic56244_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="508" >
				<rating value="2">			<usersrated value="280" />			<average value="6.25" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.69616" />			<stddev value="1.46017" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2003-12-31 13:25:59" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>							</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="1345" subtype="boardgame" collid="1085160">
	<name sortindex="1">Genoa</name>
		<yearpublished>2001</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic450409.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic450409_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="6150" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="5229" />			<average value="7.19939" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.97031" />			<stddev value="1.38498" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:56:06" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>I don&#039;t like it.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="35285" subtype="boardgame" collid="13799688">
	<name sortindex="1">German Railways</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1097251.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1097251_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="1000" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="595" />			<average value="6.97341" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.17763" />			<stddev value="1.48579" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-25 11:38:16" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>I like the way the game is built so that one is forced to ally with others in order to win: the game is played in a very different way than other train games. What I like a bit less is that in order to allow this, there is a random element that in the first turns can be decisive. So the luck factor is a bit beyond my threshold, but in return, the game is really fun to play.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="38862" subtype="boardgame" collid="7370064">
	<name sortindex="1">Giants</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic920285.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic920285_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="2620" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="1897" />			<average value="7.01193" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.5924" />			<stddev value="1.23734" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:46:22" />
	<numplays>10</numplays>			<comment>Nice light-to-medium game. Exciting to play. Very beautiful components. Not too hard to play, but with interesting decision nevertheless. Maybe a bit too light for my taste.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="128271" subtype="boardgame" collid="17091238">
	<name sortindex="1">Ginkgopolis</name>
		<yearpublished>2012</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1412371.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1412371_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="3025" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="3087" />			<average value="7.43576" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.06477" />			<stddev value="1.25124" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-13 07:15:56" />
	<numplays>21</numplays>			<comment>For me this game has two features in common with Troyes, the previous game which the same designer contributed to: a plus (it is very original) and a minus (luck counts somehow a bit more than I like).
Also, like Troyes, tactic seems more important than strategy, that is something that I usually don&#039;t like.

So, considering this, Ginkgopolis seems far from a game that I would enjoy, right? Wrong.

First of all it is REALLY original. It is a game that somehow is fresh, new, with some things seen before (for example the card drafting like in &quot;7 Wonders&quot; or the way of scoring the area majority points seen in other games), but there is also A LOT of new ideas. 

Originality would not be enough to enjoy the game, I would have kept my mouth open in wonder for the genial design, but not necessarily wishing to play the game. But.. it is not only an original game. Ginkgopolis is really fun to play and exciting. And, contrarily to what I had read and thought, there is strategy. Yes, the plans can be ruined a bit by luck (and the influence of luck is the only reason that I don&#039;t rate this game even higher), but usually the stronger player wins. Besides it is a short game (one hour or less), so the time invested is not too high and makes the luck factor more bearable.

Even if the theme doesn&#039;t shine through a lot and it seems nearly an abstract game, actually I enjoy the way players build something and that playing is very open, there are so many different possibilities both for each single player and for the city they are building. Will the city spread outwards a lot, will there be a very high building in it? I confess that looking at the way things evolve so unpredictably makes my child heart rejoice.

Possibly I like this game for the same reason I like Dominant Species, for the spacial dimension and the very tense battles for territory.

It is a game extremely re-playable. It scales from two to four (possibly in five it is not the best, but I have not tried it). In two gets more interesting, because there is more control. In three is better than in four, but in four is still good.

I think that a gamer should not miss this game, at least you have to give a look at the crazily original way the designer couples the cards and the tiles.

A very good game!</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="527" subtype="boardgame" collid="5519236">
	<name sortindex="1">GIPF</name>
		<yearpublished>1997</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic698919.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic698919_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="3054" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="2037" />			<average value="7.11267" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.67804" />			<stddev value="1.33853" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-12-26 02:34:12" />
	<numplays>100</numplays>			<comment>My initial rating of this game was 6. After playing more it went to 8. Now it is at 9, it may go upper. After many games I start appreciating how subtle and beautiful this game is. And I have just started to use potentials: a completely new story...

UPDATE 16th oct 2007: Playing with potentials now... WOW... rating moved to 10. The best abstract game after Go that I have ever played. It needs some time to show its beauty. I am hooked now.

UPDATE 23rd nov 2007: rating back to 9. I have played ultimate GIPF (with all the potentials). The game even improved, but now my interest to play again has diminished. Probably I &quot;burnt&quot; the game playing too much. In any case recommended (I played really A LOT of games and I enjoyed them). 

UPDATE 5th November 2011
I lowered a bit the rating of this game, since any time  I want to play an abstract game at this moment I play Go. It is still a very good game if you want to play an abstract game other than Go.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="5117" subtype="boardgame" collid="5472488">
	<name sortindex="1">GIPF Project Set 2</name>
		<yearpublished>2001</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic17504.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic17504_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="696" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="111" />			<average value="7.25631" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.73025" />			<stddev value="1.54777" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-12-26 02:34:58" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Especially good for the extra rings of Zértz. I play Zértz with 61 rings and the game becomes much more interesting.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="19857" subtype="boardgame" collid="6942316">
	<name sortindex="1">Glory to Rome</name>
		<yearpublished>2005</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1079512.png</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1079512_t.png</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="11224" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="9792" />			<average value="7.51576" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.36953" />			<stddev value="1.36708" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:23:55" />
	<numplays>9</numplays>			<comment>I think this game is appreciated more with more plays. So, probably, my rating is going to move upwards.

UPDATE
My interest for card-driven games is diminishing... so I have not increased the rating, but decreased it.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="188" subtype="boardgame" collid="1084532">
	<name sortindex="1">Go</name>
		<yearpublished>-2200</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1728832.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1728832_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="13159" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="9968" />			<average value="7.70164" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.45855" />			<stddev value="1.90553" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-01-25 05:56:01" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Simply the best abstract game of the world. Much nicer than chess. 

My preferred game without any doubt. It is not only a game, it is a form of art.

I play Go only on a server, and I don&#039;t register the games on BGG, but it is by far the game I have most played.
</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="9216" subtype="boardgame" collid="1413655">
	<name sortindex="1">Goa</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1215969.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1215969_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="8515" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="8839" />			<average value="7.6856" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.51851" />			<stddev value="1.29696" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-25 11:36:46" />
	<numplays>21</numplays>			<comment>By far the best game of the ca. 15 I have played in the period it was published. Mechanics similar to Princes of Florence, but Goa is more thrilling and with more interaction between players. Very, very recommended!!</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="93" subtype="boardgame" collid="1289164">
	<name sortindex="4">El Grande</name>
		<yearpublished>1995</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic180538.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic180538_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="15916" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="16310" />			<average value="7.82495" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.71102" />			<stddev value="1.34366" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2007-10-31 15:48:19" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>A classic. Good, but probably there are better games nowadays.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="370" subtype="boardgame" collid="1289165">
	<name sortindex="4">El Grande: König &amp; Intrigant</name>
		<yearpublished>1997</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic293862.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic293862_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="1573" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="496" />			<average value="7.36901" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.25385" />			<stddev value="1.51912" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2007-11-06 12:02:35" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>It makes the main game much more interesting and less luck dependent</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="111341" subtype="boardgame" collid="14780052">
	<name sortindex="5">The Great Zimbabwe</name>
		<yearpublished>2012</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1400856.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1400856_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="150"																	playingtime="150"																	numowned="1019" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="1002" />			<average value="7.6043" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.73136" />			<stddev value="1.42882" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-05-15 10:00:47" />
	<numplays>17</numplays>			<comment>The first time I played this game I was so disappointed. It seemed a stupid game, especially too fast, so that eventually what seemed to matter was some clever tactical moves more than anything else.

Then I played it more. And more. And the more I play it the more I like it. It happens the opposite of what happens with other games. Usually the more we play a game the less we like it. Not with this game. It needs to be played a lot to show its greatness.

There is another effect, related to the above: normally a game is difficult to play at the beginning, and easier to play after a while, because we start to know strategies and we start to use the auto-pilot (and also often start being bored by it). Not with this game. It has the strange feature to become harder to play the more we play it, because only when some subtle things become evident further depths are shown and deeper and more interesting thinking becomes necessary.

So I am afraid the reason the game is not reaching the greater rating that it deserves here on BGG is that people may stop playing after too few games (because I think the first games are really not exciting and seem to be only some tactical puzzle-like affair). Even 5 or more games can be two few to really appreciate it. But if one is patient and goes on trying, they will be repaid with  wonderful game experiences.

I like the way the map is built randomly each game and at the same time the total absence of luck or of hidden information. It scales well. It is highly interactive and   each game is tense. The different powers acquired through gods and specialists require a totally different approach to the game, further increasing the huge replayability. The rules are very elegant and simple, the game is hard to play well. 

So a very good game for my taste. The only reason it doesn&#039;t get a 10 from me is that I prefer highly strategical games, instead in this one the tactical aspect is maybe a bit too important. I prefer the wider horizon, games in which one wins for the big plan and the creative long term choices more than for the puzzle-like tactical moves. But it is just a bit more tactical than what I like, there is a lot of strategy too, and the more I play the more the depth in strategy is coming to the surface, so it is not impossible that my rating will go up with further plays.

Try this game, in any case. It is well worth the price. It is original and beautiful in a way that is like a landmark for Splotter Games.

UPDATE March 2013
After playing the game more I raised the rating to ten. A beautiful experience packed in such a short time and with such simple rules. And each game is completely different from the other. It is really a gem, what a shame that it does not have the success it deserves because it needs time to be appreciated.

</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="55952" subtype="boardgame" collid="9316064">
	<name sortindex="1">Greed Incorporated</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic575518.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic575518_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="864" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="728" />			<average value="7.00674" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.27573" />			<stddev value="1.53663" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-08-19 06:16:18" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>I have to play this more to give a preciser rating.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="30381" subtype="boardgame" collid="6929869">
	<name sortindex="1">Hamburgum</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic260141.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic260141_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="75"																	maxplaytime="75"																	playingtime="75"																	numowned="2780" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="2644" />			<average value="7.08474" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.74815" />			<stddev value="1.17813" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-01-03 02:34:01" />
	<numplays>7</numplays>			<comment>Not a bad game, but it is not Imperial or Antike...  Not so much replayability.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="3685" subtype="boardgame" collid="1086704">
	<name sortindex="1">Hammer of the Scots</name>
		<yearpublished>2002</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic623710.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic623710_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="4019" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="3222" />			<average value="7.58422" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.17779" />			<stddev value="1.38331" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:48:17" />
	<numplays>7</numplays>			<comment>I don&#039;t think I am going to play this again soon. There are very few war games that I like at the moment. I prefer games with less luck and offering more interesting choices at each move.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="98778" subtype="boardgame" collid="17103414">
	<name sortindex="1">Hanabi</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2007286.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2007286_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="25"																	maxplaytime="25"																	playingtime="25"																	numowned="26590" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="16745" />			<average value="7.31507" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.22586" />			<stddev value="1.32301" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:11:22" />
	<numplays>9</numplays>			<comment>Quite nice simple and fast cooperative game.

I like it for its originality and for the way it solicits a different kind of cooperation between players. So I would have liked to give a higher rating, but, to be honest, I find the actual play a bit flat. There is no real tension, maybe because most of the time the team is just scoring an average score and so it is neither really a lost game nor a won one.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="234" subtype="boardgame" collid="4614936">
	<name sortindex="1">Hannibal: Rome vs. Carthage</name>
		<yearpublished>1996</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic706069.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic706069_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="40"																	maxplaytime="200"																	playingtime="200"																	numowned="6334" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="4034" />			<average value="7.83155" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.4479" />			<stddev value="1.51523" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:44:58" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>I used to play a lot of wargames in the past, but now I am nearly always playing &quot;European&quot; games. This is one of the few wargames which I still would play, with accessible rules and length, given the strategic choices and the fun it offers.

UPDATE April 2013
Rating lowered: I prefer more and more games with no luck and user driven instead of card driven.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="8989" subtype="boardgame" collid="2060908">
	<name sortindex="1">Hansa</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic311302.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic311302_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="4931" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="4346" />			<average value="6.92719" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.72093" />			<stddev value="1.13702" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-01-03 02:33:13" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>Not as good as I had expected. Its short playing time is one of its pros. Its &quot;cold&quot; collecting of VP one of its cons.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="43015" subtype="boardgame" collid="9750804">
	<name sortindex="1">Hansa Teutonica</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic839090.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic839090_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="6744" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="7013" />			<average value="7.64223" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.44454" />			<stddev value="1.38415" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:06:42" />
	<numplays>14</numplays>			<comment>Nice middle-weight game offering a lot of choices. Strategical and not only tactical. And after some small perplexities for people that don&#039;t like &quot;hard&quot; games in the first game, it goes very smooth. My eight years old daughter plays it without problems.

UPDATE March 2013
Lowered the rating to 7 because recently games have appeared that somehow have a similar feeling (simple rules and deep play, not long to play etc.) that I do prefer much more because they offer deeper and more strategical and interesting choices (i.e. Terra Mystica or The great Zimbabwe)</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="35677" subtype="boardgame" collid="7130501">
	<name sortindex="4">Le Havre</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic447994.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic447994_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="100"																	maxplaytime="200"																	playingtime="200"																	numowned="17096" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="16381" />			<average value="7.97455" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.86471" />			<stddev value="1.43681" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-25 11:58:41" />
	<numplays>16</numplays>			<comment>Superb resource management game. It offers many different paths to victory. Really exciting and fun to play. It takes the best of Caylus and Agricola, bettering both of them. It manages to be original even using known mechanics.

A masterpiece. 

UPDATE 7th Nov 2012
I still consider it a wonderful game, but I moved down the rating to 9 because I like more &quot;Ora et labora&quot; that gives a similar experience, but which I like much more.

UPDATE October 2015
Rating lowered to 8. I prefer Fields of Arle, and also Ora et Labora and Caverna. This should be reflected in my ratings.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="92666" subtype="boardgame" collid="16018538">
	<name sortindex="1">Hegemonic</name>
		<yearpublished>2013</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1819022.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1819022_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="1159" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="394" />			<average value="7.05673" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.03975" />			<stddev value="1.48007" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-07-22 06:22:21" />
	<numplays>6</numplays>			<comment>Great game. I find it thematic, and nice: I like to imagine different cultures expanding in the galaxy in a very long time. 

I think the game is not having the success it deserves because it needs more plays to be appreciated (becoming  proficient with the rules and the strategies). I am afraid people give up playing too soon, and it is a pity, because this is a wonderful game. Consequently its BGG rating and ranking are not adequate IMHO. 

It has great replayability and incredibly high interaction: sometimes there are big diplomatic discussions that are quite interesting. And it offers a lot of strategic choices, a huge decision space, as I like in games.

I like it much more than Eclipse, for a lot of reasons. For example because the way to win is determined by who has more area control on the galaxy and not by how many points  one collects in a mixed salad way.

Recommended.</comment>				<wishlistcomment>Sleeves: standard US playing card sizes, which means 3.5&quot; x 2.5</wishlistcomment></item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="4529" subtype="boardgame" collid="1308757">
	<name sortindex="1">Hellas</name>
		<yearpublished>2002</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic178402.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic178402_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="2909" >
				<rating value="2">			<usersrated value="1865" />			<average value="6.23924" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.01689" />			<stddev value="1.31596" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-12-31 18:31:52" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>Really no fun at all. There is no consistent strategy that can be tried. In any moment you can steal easily a land-hex from your opponent and the other way around. It seems that whatever you do is not so important. At the end, winning the game does&#039;t leave the feeling you have done something good... very likely you have used some tricky tactical moves or just have had luck with the cards.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="638" subtype="boardgame" collid="1413659">
	<name sortindex="1">Hera and Zeus</name>
		<yearpublished>2000</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic63285.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic63285_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="4339" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="2875" />			<average value="6.54331" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.31242" />			<stddev value="1.36739" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:13:36" />
	<numplays>27</numplays>			<comment>My second preferred game in the Kosmos &quot;2-players&quot; series (first one being Babel). Slightly better than LoR: The Confrontation, that has a similar &quot;feeling&quot;.

UPDATE
My taste have changed a bit with the years passing, so I am much less attracted to play games like this at the moment.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="224" subtype="boardgame" collid="1086083">
	<name sortindex="1">History of the World</name>
		<yearpublished>1991</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic287451.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic287451_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="4423" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="3749" />			<average value="7.14029" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.83814" />			<stddev value="1.47885" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:55:31" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>							</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="2655" subtype="boardgame" collid="5061646">
	<name sortindex="1">Hive</name>
		<yearpublished>2001</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic791151.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic791151_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="20"																	maxplaytime="20"																	playingtime="20"																	numowned="20610" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="16648" />			<average value="7.34518" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.24811" />			<stddev value="1.27191" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2007-11-06 12:03:59" />
	<numplays>8</numplays>			<comment>Nice abstract game, but I prefer games of the GIPF family much more (they give more choices and at a deeper level). The nice thing about Hive is that you can easily carry it anywhere.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="120" subtype="boardgame" collid="1085293">
	<name sortindex="1">Hoity Toity</name>
		<yearpublished>1990</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic38466.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic38466_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="5619" >
				<rating value="2">			<usersrated value="4173" />			<average value="6.55408" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.38249" />			<stddev value="1.32072" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-01-03 02:41:03" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>I don&#039;t like games where bluffing is the main characteristic.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="26566" subtype="boardgame" collid="14698549">
	<name sortindex="1">Homesteaders</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1113708.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1113708_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="3190" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="2844" />			<average value="7.35923" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.98501" />			<stddev value="1.17912" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-25 11:39:37" />
	<numplays>10</numplays>			<comment>Simple and elegant rules, quick playing time and at the same time deep and beautiful to play, with a lot of choices and strategic possibilities. I like it really a lot.

UPDATE
After more plays seems to become less interesting. I still suggest you to play it, but I have lowered the rating from 8 t0 7.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="701" subtype="boardgame" collid="1085128">
	<name sortindex="3">A House Divided</name>
		<yearpublished>1981</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1261028.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1261028_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="240"																	maxplaytime="240"																	playingtime="240"																	numowned="3108" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="1597" />			<average value="7.09707" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.57198" />			<stddev value="1.36381" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:51:45" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Good classic, but there are better wargames nowadays. And I am not so more interested in wargames later.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="859" subtype="boardgame" collid="1086082">
	<name sortindex="1">Illuminati</name>
		<yearpublished>1982</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic55406.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic55406_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="2821" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="2172" />			<average value="6.20106" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.97849" />			<stddev value="1.64856" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2007-10-31 15:54:42" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>							</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="24181" subtype="boardgame" collid="5061644">
	<name sortindex="1">Imperial</name>
		<yearpublished>2006</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic840712.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic840712_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="5667" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="6682" />			<average value="7.65412" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.42661" />			<stddev value="1.49124" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2009-10-06 04:15:34" />
	<numplays>21</numplays>			<comment>Wonderful game. It is often compared to Antique because they have similar basic mechanics, but they are very different games. BOTH OF THEM are top games in my opinion. Imperial has the advantage, for me, that is probably more enjoyable with only three players. Very recommended!</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="54138" subtype="boardgame" collid="24436021">
	<name sortindex="1">Imperial 2030</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic586346.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic586346_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="3413" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="3387" />			<average value="7.76052" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.3418" />			<stddev value="1.44577" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-10-18 02:16:44" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>Imperial 2030 (as its predecessor Imperial) is a wonderful game, a classic, a game that should be in the top ten of BGG.

It offers a lot of very interesting strategic choices, with a huge decision space, open to creative play. Players are investing in nations, and nations pay dividend based on their success rating in conquering part of the world.  Nations are controlled by the player who has more shares. But nations and players have not the same objectives: playing this game as a wargame is likely a way to lose.

Incredibly clean and simple rules for a game of this depth. The famous rondel fragments the nation&#039;s activities in tiny actions: each action can usually be played very fast, so there is usually no long waiting times. It is exciting to play. It scales incredibly well from 3 to 6 (because all nations are always in the game, whatever the number of players). There is absolutely no luck involved in the game.

I play it without the investor card and IMHO this is by far the best way to play the game.

There are little changes compared with Imperial, but I prefer Imperial 2030, especially because in my opinion the map offers more interesting and balanced strategical choices (and it is more beautiful too). 

</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="3661" subtype="boardgame" collid="1413666">
	<name sortindex="1">Imperium</name>
		<yearpublished>1977</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic349893.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic349893_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="1026" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="435" />			<average value="6.85323" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.98606" />			<stddev value="1.27232" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2004-07-11 05:45:13" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>							</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="13780" subtype="boardgame" collid="6706766">
	<name sortindex="1">In the Shadow of the Emperor</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic202677.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic202677_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="3552" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="2617" />			<average value="6.97485" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.658" />			<stddev value="1.30135" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:47:22" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>Good, but not great: victory comes more from slowly collecting points for local tactical decisions than for a strategical view (something not too good for my taste).</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="31594" subtype="boardgame" collid="6740076">
	<name sortindex="1">In the Year of the Dragon</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic285822.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic285822_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="75"																	maxplaytime="100"																	playingtime="100"																	numowned="6370" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="7520" />			<average value="7.42937" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.25811" />			<stddev value="1.32587" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-04-04 12:16:22" />
	<numplays>11</numplays>			<comment>Good game, but somehow the interest of playing it again fades away after around 10 games.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="19777" subtype="boardgame" collid="5717676">
	<name sortindex="1">Indonesia</name>
		<yearpublished>2005</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic93485.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic93485_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="240"																	playingtime="240"																	numowned="1986" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="2254" />			<average value="7.71512" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.19669" />			<stddev value="1.5713" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2007-11-19 05:17:21" />
	<numplays>13</numplays>			<comment>I gave this game a 9. I update it to 10 after many plays. It is a wonderful game, so rich of possibilities, so different each time. I have played really a lot of 2 players games and I didn&#039;t experiment the critiques I have heard. The game is still very interesting in two and it doesn&#039;t last more than with more players (usually a two players game lasts between 2 and 3 hours, in my case at least).</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="855" subtype="boardgame" collid="1290489">
	<name sortindex="1">Java</name>
		<yearpublished>2000</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic178934.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic178934_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="3921" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="2800" />			<average value="7.04132" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.72165" />			<stddev value="1.32852" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2004-04-24 08:18:33" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>Too much time waiting for other gamers to play. In any case better than Tikal.
Nice game in 2 (where the waiting time become acceptable)</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="30869" subtype="boardgame" collid="7107799">
	<name sortindex="1">Jenseits von Theben</name>
	<originalname>Thebes</originalname>	<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic202159.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic202159_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="7520" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="6898" />			<average value="7.20373" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.02734" />			<stddev value="1.18604" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:20:08" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>Too much luck and too few decisions for my taste. Becoming boring after a few games.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="37836" subtype="boardgame" collid="14229172">
	<name sortindex="1">Julius Caesar</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic732997.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic732997_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="1345" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="896" />			<average value="7.84218" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.75955" />			<stddev value="1.32368" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:11:52" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Too muck luck-dependent and too few significant strategical and tactical choices.

Sometimes ten or more throws of dice are needed for a single  battle: instead of throwing the dice I could have spent my time better in some of my preferred games that continuously offer the player significant and tense choices and not just a few. For me it is much more exciting if the results of a game are based on the way people play and not on luck with dice and/or cards.

If you have my same taste (look for example at my top ten) you probably better avoid this game. Otherwise you could still consider to try it. In its genre (that is not my cup of tea) it is one of the best.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="8098" subtype="boardgame" collid="14172822">
	<name sortindex="1">Jungle Speed</name>
		<yearpublished>1997</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic736534.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic736534_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="8"																	minplaytime="10"																	maxplaytime="10"																	playingtime="10"																	numowned="8641" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="6501" />			<average value="6.62408" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.46716" />			<stddev value="1.4959" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-10-31 05:00:47" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>Party game: not my cup of tea. If you like this sort of game, this is one of the best in his genre.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="34585" subtype="boardgame" collid="7265021">
	<name sortindex="1">Keltis</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic382457.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic382457_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="4134" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="3822" />			<average value="6.48896" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.31602" />			<stddev value="1.35069" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:56:23" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>Nice easy game, fun to play.  Just a bit too much luck and little strategical options for my taste. I like to play it, in any case. It is similar in feeling to Lost Cities (if you like Lost Cities, you would like this too).

UPDATE
My taste have changed a bit with the years passing, so I am much less attracted to play games like this at the moment.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="122515" subtype="boardgame" collid="16080688">
	<name sortindex="1">Keyflower</name>
		<yearpublished>2012</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2278942.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2278942_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="9748" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="7572" />			<average value="7.97367" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.75038" />			<stddev value="1.23935" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-01-01 13:51:57" />
	<numplays>11</numplays>			<comment>There are a lot of nice things in this game: workers of different colors, but once one starts to bid / use a tile with a color, everyone must continue using that color;  player can choose to bid or use a tile in their move; one can even use tiles which are still being bid for or belonging to other players, even if losing the workers in the process, etc. 

The game offers really a lot of interesting choices.

Replayability is huge: each game offers different challenges, possibly one of the most variable games I have ever played.

Small disadvantages for my tastes are that it may be a bit difficult to apply a consistent strategy (tactic counts!) and that there is a bit less control, also due to some luck: for example the way the winter tiles (i.e. the goals each player &quot;knows&quot; alone at the beginning of the game) and the other tiles that actually come into play may form combinations that are more advantageous for some players than others. Because of these disadvantages, I think the game is suitable also for the casual gamer.

But these are minor quibbles. I like this game a lot, and as many new games I have played recently, I have the feeling that we are at a new stage of boardgame design, new games are getting better and better... and as many of this new generation games, Keyflower manages to compress in quite a short time a lot of gaming experience.

UPDATE 1 Jan 2012
Lowered the rating from 9 to 8. The lack of control due to some luck and even more to the hidden information seems to be more than I expected and like. Also somehow the game is a bit less tense than other new &quot;second generation&quot; games I am playing in this period. The game is still very good and I still like to play it. Also its huge replayability is confirmed: every game seems a new one.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="7806" subtype="boardgame" collid="13911873">
	<name sortindex="1">King Me!</name>
		<yearpublished>1998</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic329420.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic329420_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="1792" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="1737" />			<average value="6.37242" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.09747" />			<stddev value="1.21521" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-11-05 14:33:49" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>Very light game, that I can play if requested, but really it is at the limit of what I consider a game for thinking adults :)</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="8138" subtype="boardgame" collid="24247057">
	<name sortindex="1">Kogge</name>
		<yearpublished>2003</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic56853.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic56853_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="392" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="267" />			<average value="6.72384" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.8405" />			<stddev value="1.47722" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-11-11 04:37:28" />
	<numplays>10</numplays>			<comment>Andreas Steding’s most known game is Hansa Teutonica, but in my opinion his Kogge is a much better game.

Kogge is more unique than original. A brilliant design. Simple rules, deep as the ocean. Also as opaque as the mysteries at the bottom of the ocean: try to calculate how to win at this game. If you are serious, even if you are not inclined to AP, you may go in a never-ending loop. So is this a disaster of a game, a cold game of calculation? It is the opposite, since it is virtually impossible to calculate how to win. Actually in the first games I have played I didn&#039;t even know the direction, what in other games is given for granted... go there, there you obstacle the opponent so, you know paths and you choose the best between many paths... this is how we reason in other games, we know what we are doing. Not here. Here even the paths, the directions are obscure. Here intuition is the only weapon we have. Because every single move has repercussions that change everything. At a certain point one stops thinking as we normally do in normal games, and we discover that to play this beast we need a completely different set of abilities, nothing I have experienced before. This is not a normal game, for sure.

So Kogge has minimal rules and it is deep at the same moment and original. That’s all? No, there is more. One of the reasons people don’t like Hansa Teutonica is that it appears to be cold. At least is appears cold to me. I find even the interaction present in Hansa Teutonica a bit cold. As in other optimization games, this happens to other games too, not only with Hansa Teutonica. And Kogge? Kogge is not only highly interactive (you have to look at what the opponents are doing and react or you don’t have any chance to win, and ruining others’ plans MUST be part of your strategy, as far as I have understood), but it is a FUN interaction, in the literal sense of the word “fun”. As an example I cite that you can steal from an opponent or from a city and then you are banned from that city. This is never nice for the victims, but I have never resented when I was the victim, because... because the game is structured that even if it really seems a simulation of a difficult time in travelling on sea, it is actually fun, very fun to play.

So, after reading this, look at the rating of Kogge on BGG. Not only at the rank, that could be low because there are too few votes, but at the average rating itself. It makes me so sad, below 7. WHY? There are many explanations. Kogge is not an easy game to approach. You don’t need to be a heavy gamer to play it, I think one can play this game without going too deep in the analysis of the game, so playing it lightly. You may have even to stop calculating in order to win (because the only effect of calculation in this game seems to be that it distracts you from doing the simple intuitive things you have to do to win :-) ). I have won most of the games I have played till now, but the only one in which I really started understanding how to win was the last in which I stopped calculating deeply, and instead formulated  a simple plan in my mind, like be patient, do not rush, grow slowly. So the game can be played without calculation: choose a strategy, and react to what others are doing. But I started seeing this at my fourth game, before the game was frightening in its opacity. So this is the first reason Kogge is not appreciated: it has been played very little, even by people that own it, because Kogge is not a friendly fellow at the first meetings. Then add these other points: it was produced by a small company; graphics is quite old fashioned and not really beautiful; the rules themselves are not explained so well (the German rules and the English rules are both wrong in some points, but they compensate at least, mistakes are not in the same points). So, add all this together, and you have the perfect recipe to make of a masterpiece like Kogge an almost unknown game on BGG.

But this does make me sad. I hope one day this game will be published again, maybe by a big publisher. It deserves it. And the players deserve to play this game.

I have played Kogge only 4 times at the moment I am writing this comment (but I have already planned with friends more games!) and so I give now a provisional rating of 9, I want to see how it is with more plays before thinking to give it a 10. But my gut feeling is that this game is one of those (rare) games that become better the more we play them, and more interesting (vs. becoming boring, as it usually happens with games that tire us after a while), because subtle strategies not noticed at the beginning appear on the surface, as gifts to people that dared deepen the friendship with it. So my rating can still become a 10. But already now, I shout this: I RECOMMEND THIS GAME!</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="29937" subtype="boardgame" collid="25975494">
	<name sortindex="1">König von Siam</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic261132.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic261132_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="1605" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="1835" />			<average value="6.93603" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.53528" />			<stddev value="1.3807" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-03-08 07:02:23" />
	<numplays>11</numplays>			<comment>Given that it is a pure area control game, with minimalist rules and a very short playing time, it offers much variety, tense game play and a lot of strategical possibilities. 

Not the perfect game for me (the winning strategy that one has to apply seems to me more like betting on a horse than positional strategy), but a game I will play over and over when I have little time.

Good in 3 players, but surprisingly also very good with 4 players (the game is played in two teams in the latter case).

You may consider adding it to your collection if you like area control games and minimalist design.
</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="26859" subtype="boardgame" collid="7765774">
	<name sortindex="1">Kragmortha</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic165271.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic165271_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="8"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="956" >
				<rating value="2">			<usersrated value="759" />			<average value="5.86925" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.65181" />			<stddev value="1.677" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:22:29" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>The game is fun, but it is not the sort of game I like to play.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="196" subtype="boardgame" collid="1085143">
	<name sortindex="1">Kremlin</name>
		<yearpublished>1986</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1787203.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1787203_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="75"																	maxplaytime="75"																	playingtime="75"																	numowned="3224" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="2274" />			<average value="7.02033" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.62673" />			<stddev value="1.52495" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2008-11-29 06:46:13" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>An old AH classic. There are probably better games today.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="21920" subtype="boardgame" collid="4681446">
	<name sortindex="1">Leonardo da Vinci</name>
		<yearpublished>2006</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic143408.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic143408_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="4047" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="3110" />			<average value="6.82982" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.56176" />			<stddev value="1.28792" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 02:05:39" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>I find this game cold and boring, even if the ideas beyond it seem good. It is not fun for me. I may update this after I play it more, but at the moment I have not so much wish to do it again (very bad sign).</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="59959" subtype="boardgame" collid="15504003">
	<name sortindex="1">Letters from Whitechapel</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1545654.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1545654_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="8783" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="6518" />			<average value="7.52527" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.29026" />			<stddev value="1.36461" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-04-05 08:45:29" />
	<numplays>19</numplays>			<comment>Very beautiful and exciting deduction game. Games are very tense and undecided till the very last moment.

I find the game balanced (I am playing allowing a third move to the policemen instead of the searching for clues or arrest attempt and using a random generator for Jack&#039;s hideout). 

It is very easy to learn and play, also because the mechanics are integrated with the theme; it is playable with children and non gamers. 

Recommended.

</comment>				<wishlistcomment>When second edition is published.</wishlistcomment></item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="140620" subtype="boardgame" collid="20847312">
	<name sortindex="1">Lewis &amp; Clark</name>
		<yearpublished>2013</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1902092.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1902092_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="8146" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="6300" />			<average value="7.68323" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.44366" />			<stddev value="1.23796" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-08-19 10:32:23" />
	<numplays>5</numplays>			<comment>Good and original game for its kind, but it is not my kind. Too tactical and too much dependent on cards. A lot of puzzle-like reasoning that make the game not fun to play.</comment>				<wishlistcomment>Number of cards: 89

Arcane Tinmen sleeve size: Standard - Gray (AT-10406) - (63 x 88mm)
Fantasy Flight sleeve size: Standard Card Game - Gray (FFS05) - (2-1/2&quot; x 3-1/2&quot; - 63.5 x 88mm)
Mayday sleeve size: Card Game - Green - (63.5 x 88mm)
Swan PanAsia sleeve size: Standard Card (SWN-032) - (65 x 90mm)
Ultra-Pro sleeve size: Clear Standard Deck Protector (82689) - (66 x 91mm) or Pro-Fit Standard Size (82712) - (64 x 89mm)</wishlistcomment></item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="823" subtype="boardgame" collid="1085148">
	<name sortindex="1">Lord of the Rings</name>
		<yearpublished>2000</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic479124.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic479124_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="15952" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="10787" />			<average value="6.81084" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.70182" />			<stddev value="1.49308" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:19:50" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Simply I don&#039;t like it. There are better Knizia games.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="3201" subtype="boardgame" collid="1783722">
	<name sortindex="1">Lord of the Rings: The Confrontation</name>
		<yearpublished>2002</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic69357.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic69357_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="6474" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="5584" />			<average value="7.23565" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.0172" />			<stddev value="1.37076" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:43:45" />
	<numplays>44</numplays>			<comment>Very good game for two. I am a bit tired to play it after 80 games. But probably this would happen to a lot of other games too. UPDATE: after a little rest I started playing again, other 20 games. And I like it again. New subtle strategies discovered and probably there are still more to be discovered.

UPDATE April 2013
My tastes have changed and I am less interested to play this game at the moment. Rating lowered to 6.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="4610" subtype="boardgame" collid="1412836">
	<name sortindex="1">Lord of the Rings: The Duel</name>
		<yearpublished>2002</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic658637.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic658637_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="2314" >
				<rating value="2">			<usersrated value="1066" />			<average value="5.91254" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.73758" />			<stddev value="1.2853" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-01-01 03:56:01" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Very boring game, offering no interesting choices to the player</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="50" subtype="boardgame" collid="1289155">
	<name sortindex="1">Lost Cities</name>
		<yearpublished>1999</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2606107.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2606107_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="27590" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="22582" />			<average value="7.12075" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.0388" />			<stddev value="1.27896" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:55:43" />
	<numplays>26</numplays>			<comment>I have played this game quite a lot in the past, but now I am not interested at all in trying it again. My tastes have changed and I like no more light card games.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="13642" subtype="boardgame" collid="3644551">
	<name sortindex="1">Louis XIV</name>
		<yearpublished>2005</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic63296.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic63296_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="75"																	maxplaytime="100"																	playingtime="100"																	numowned="5652" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="4773" />			<average value="7.13525" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.91193" />			<stddev value="1.23486" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-11-05 14:25:19" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>Good, but somehow not exciting to play.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="66" subtype="boardgame" collid="1413661">
	<name sortindex="1">Löwenherz</name>
		<yearpublished>1997</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic582814.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic582814_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="2823" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="2092" />			<average value="7.09854" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.68293" />			<stddev value="1.35797" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-11-05 14:22:53" />
	<numplays>7</numplays>			<comment>Simple, but beautiful, with a lot of strategy and interaction.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="95527" subtype="boardgame" collid="16472510">
	<name sortindex="1">Madeira</name>
		<yearpublished>2013</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1762708.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1762708_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="2771" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="1656" />			<average value="7.65835" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.98793" />			<stddev value="1.46145" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-07-23 10:16:16" />
	<numplays>16</numplays>			<comment>Very beautiful game. It offers a lot of choices, both strategical and tactical.

It is a gamer&#039;s game, but not as complex as some people are afraid of, I would say more or less the same weight as Bora Bora. There are a lot of different things to remember, but they are simple in themselves: since there are a lot of these micro-rules it can be that in the first games one makes some mistakes (not because the rules are not clear, but because one forgets some details). But after 2 or 3 games everything becomes easy and it is worth the effort.

All elements are well integrated and it is not a victory point salad, but a very good design. The game offers a lot and replayability is one of its main strengths. 

It scales well and it is surprisingly VERY good in two. Maybe in three it is a bit less interesting (but really just a tiny bit), because the game seems to become less tense.

There is some luck, but inside my limit of acceptance. The random mechanisms are useful in two directions: they enhance replayability and they reduce AP (because it is impossible to calculate everything and so players have to use intuition).

There is interaction: the more one plays the more it becomes evident that to be strong at this game one has to look and react to what other players are doing.

If you like &quot;heavy&quot; games, do not miss this.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="463" subtype="boardgame" collid="1086075">
	<name sortindex="1">Magic: The Gathering</name>
		<yearpublished>1993</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic163749.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic163749_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="20"																	maxplaytime="20"																	playingtime="20"																	numowned="21211" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="19357" />			<average value="7.43239" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.30392" />			<stddev value="1.84175" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-11-07 10:20:10" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>I think that the most interesting part of Magic is composing the deck. But in order to compose the deck you have to collect many cards. Collecting = having = uninteresting. Not my idea of boardgaming. I prefer a Go board (or a board of any game that I appreciate) in which there are infinite possibilities, open roads to the creativity of players and not creativity based on the designers making up new ideas to gain more and more money. Besides I don&#039;t like card driven games.

My rating of this game is even too kind, because of the original and innovating idea when it came out. But I am not going to play this, not interested at all.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="9440" subtype="boardgame" collid="1784135">
	<name sortindex="1">Maharaja: The Game of Palace Building in India</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic44952.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic44952_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="4720" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="4286" />			<average value="7.19005" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.93048" />			<stddev value="1.28709" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:12:13" />
	<numplays>7</numplays>			<comment>The Kramer-Kiesling&#039;s game I most like. They managed somehow to solve the &quot;waiting time&quot; problem which affected their previous games I tried (Tikal and Java).

UPDATE
Played again in 2008. It is less nice than what I remembered. Maybe because new games in the years are becoming better and better and it loses a bit of appeal comparing it with them.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="3931" subtype="boardgame" collid="6652779">
	<name sortindex="1">Mare Nostrum</name>
		<yearpublished>2003</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic10998.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic10998_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="3081" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="2720" />			<average value="6.76938" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.4696" />			<stddev value="1.5136" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:48:35" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>I prefer other civilization games to this, for example Antike</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="40354" subtype="boardgame" collid="13584091">
	<name sortindex="1">Maria</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic524669.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic524669_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="3"																	minplaytime="210"																	maxplaytime="210"																	playingtime="210"																	numowned="2433" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="1622" />			<average value="8.00166" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.2251" />			<stddev value="1.4242" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-03-24 08:28:29" />
	<numplays>13</numplays>			<comment>I usually don&#039;t play war games, not any more, and usually I avoid playing games that are too long. There are exceptions and at the top of all of them there is Maria.

Maria is an absolute masterpiece. There is so much depth and so many interesting strategical choices that the game appears like a canvas in which the players can express their personal way of playing. And the interactions and the shifting negotiations between players are very tense and beautiful. 

In the game I have found some of the mechanics of Friedrich that I liked already so much in Friedrich. But it improves with respect to Friedrich in so many ways. So if you like Friedrich, please do yourself a favor, and try Maria. If you don&#039;t like Friedrich, do yourself a favor, and play Maria. If you have never played Friedrich, try Maria. If you like deep games (and if you are not afraid to play a game that in the worst case can last till around 5 hours), it is unlikely that you will be disappointed. It requires a bit more effort and time than the usual Euro game, but it is all worth it (and you don&#039;t need to be a war gamer to appreciate it).

Very very recommended.  </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="10630" subtype="boardgame" collid="3746994">
	<name sortindex="1">Memoir &#039;44</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic43663.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic43663_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="20569" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="16874" />			<average value="7.52475" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.39937" />			<stddev value="1.38753" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-12-08 15:30:25" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>Too luck dependent and too tactical for my tastes. Commands &amp; Colors: Ancients is a better game.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="230" subtype="boardgame" collid="1413667">
	<name sortindex="1">Merchant of Venus</name>
		<yearpublished>1988</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic159117.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic159117_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="2688" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="2285" />			<average value="7.19467" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.76301" />			<stddev value="1.49361" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2004-07-11 05:46:02" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>An AH classic. I used to play it a lot in the past, but nowadays there are better games.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="118" subtype="boardgame" collid="1413668">
	<name sortindex="1">Modern Art</name>
		<yearpublished>1992</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic149747.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic149747_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="10848" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="10621" />			<average value="7.31278" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.17583" />			<stddev value="1.35284" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:41:05" />
	<numplays>9</numplays>			<comment>A classic. I have played it so much that I am at the moment not willing to play it anymore. I think in any case that you should try it if you haven&#039;t played it yet. Recommended both for gamers and not gamers.

</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="21441" subtype="boardgame" collid="4614856">
	<name sortindex="1">Mykerinos</name>
		<yearpublished>2006</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic171450.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic171450_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="3486" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="3428" />			<average value="6.90449" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.66159" />			<stddev value="1.15705" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-11-18 07:48:27" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>One of the few times that I was disappointed about a game for which I had read very good about, here on BGG. Really very cold and not exciting at all. Too simple, without even being so easy to explain. There are much better &quot;light&quot; games around.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="126792" subtype="boardgame" collid="16396189">
	<name sortindex="1">Myrmes</name>
		<yearpublished>2012</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1370050.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1370050_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="3950" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="2999" />			<average value="7.37066" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.98649" />			<stddev value="1.26701" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-12-28 03:23:31" />
	<numplays>5</numplays>			<comment>Good game, but not great. 

What I like: there is replayability, due to the objectives, the seasons dice and the choices of the players; there is also very little luck; there is interactions between players (even if limited to the shared board). 

What I don&#039;t like is that the choices are too few, somehow the game doesn&#039;t allow a personal creative play, what I am searching in great games.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="18098" subtype="boardgame" collid="13820279">
	<name sortindex="1">Napoleon&#039;s Triumph</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic291050.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic291050_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="2387" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="1423" />			<average value="7.98016" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.12847" />			<stddev value="1.76034" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-25 10:10:29" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>Beautiful original game, with very tense and exciting battles, lasting not too long. One of the few wargames that I still like to play.

The reason I don&#039;t rate it higher is because of the hidden information (necessary in this game design of course) and that quite complicated tactical moves and calculation seem to be at least as important as strategy (and I do ptrefer strategy in games). 

A very good game, in any case.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="66589" subtype="boardgame" collid="11641033">
	<name sortindex="1">Navegador</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic824016.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic824016_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="4966" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="5360" />			<average value="7.60958" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.35803" />			<stddev value="1.15975" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-25 11:36:11" />
	<numplays>13</numplays>			<comment>Game offering a lot of choices, with almost absent dependence on luck. To win at this game strategy is more important than tactic, in a way that I like. 

The components are very beautiful.

Strong (indirect) interaction between players and very fast turns due to the rondel.

UPDATE
Raised rating to 10 after playing more times. Strategic in a nicer and deeper way than it appears in the first games. And fast and beautiful to play. The best of the rondel games, together with Imperial. Very recommended.

UPDATE October 2015
Rating lowered to 9: after some plays the strategies seems a bit to repeat themselves. Still a great game.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="12681" subtype="boardgame" collid="24262041">
	<name sortindex="1">Neuland</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic299414.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic299414_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="100"																	maxplaytime="100"																	playingtime="100"																	numowned="1945" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="1213" />			<average value="6.5313" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.14949" />			<stddev value="1.52521" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-25 11:13:22" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>Tentative rating. It seems a bit too tactical and puzzle-like for my taste. But I may be wrong,  I have to play it more, my rating can go higher, not lower. 

There are things that I like: the absence of luck, the strong interaction; the simplicity of the rules, but at the time its offering a lot of decisions.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="70149" subtype="boardgame" collid="13556947">
	<name sortindex="1">Ora et Labora</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1165426.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1165426_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="7569" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="6334" />			<average value="7.80775" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.56278" />			<stddev value="1.3594" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-25 11:53:41" />
	<numplays>19</numplays>			<comment>Masterpiece, perfect game.

It is better than Agricola and Le Havre in many ways: less fiddly, a significant spatial element, no random components (a very strong plus for me), deep choices with many paths to victories, etc., etc... 

Very strongly recommended!!!

UPDATE October 2015
Rating moved from 10 to 9. Although I still consider it  a great game, I think that I would prefer Fields of Arle to it, any time. And this should be reflected in my ratings.</comment>				<wishlistcomment>Italian version!</wishlistcomment></item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="2136" subtype="boardgame" collid="7329529">
	<name sortindex="1">Pachisi</name>
		<yearpublished>400</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic516869.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic516869_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="4170" >
				<rating value="1">			<usersrated value="2821" />			<average value="4.44346" />
			<bayesaverage value="4.61002" />			<stddev value="1.79048" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2009-10-06 04:27:41" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Very boring game in which luck with the dice is the only important skill needed</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="24480" subtype="boardgame" collid="6652847">
	<name sortindex="5">The Pillars of the Earth</name>
		<yearpublished>2006</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic212815.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic212815_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="12709" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="11701" />			<average value="7.31882" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.19011" />			<stddev value="1.19445" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 02:07:19" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>Caylus-like game. I prefer by far Caylus (IMO not even harder to play and with a more elegant design).</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="23094" subtype="boardgame" collid="7350596">
	<name sortindex="1">Planet Steam</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1639600.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1639600_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="3066" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="1840" />			<average value="7.33209" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.80277" />			<stddev value="1.41738" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2009-09-30 03:00:06" />
	<numplays>11</numplays>			<comment>I think this is a half hidden gem. If you like resource management games, you should not miss this. 

It is expensive, but the material is really wonderful.

A lot of player interaction (of particular mention the tense auctions to choose the character that will &quot;support&quot; you each turn).

Simple, but very effective simulation of a market in which prices grow or fall based on demand.

Recommended.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="69779" subtype="boardgame" collid="17100621">
	<name sortindex="1">Polis: Fight for the Hegemony</name>
		<yearpublished>2012</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1032795.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1032795_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="2172" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="1127" />			<average value="7.92481" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.94051" />			<stddev value="1.41073" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-11-13 15:10:58" />
	<numplays>9</numplays>			<comment>See my review at http://www.boardgamegeek.com/thread/883808/polis-a-game-deserving-a-wider-audience</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="30878" subtype="boardgame" collid="24435856">
	<name sortindex="1">Power &amp; Weakness</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic260563.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic260563_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="413" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="200" />			<average value="6.6231" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.74987" />			<stddev value="1.30327" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-09-12 06:01:57" />
	<numplays>10</numplays>			<comment>In my opinion the most underrated game on BGG. At the moment I am writing this, the avg. users rating is only 6.58. There are very few games recorded too, how can people miss that this game needs more plays to show its greatness?

This is a small masterpiece for exactly two players. The game is very short, 45 minutes, often less. There is a lot of tension, the entire game, because it can be won suddenly and unexpectedly with clever attack moves. There are two layers of area control, with alternating cycles: if one player wins one cycle, the other usually wins the other, and this going up and down, really power alternating with weakness, is its most characteristic aspect.  

Rules are incredibly clever, perfectly balanced, every game is always in equilibrium, each player attacks and then is attacked... but it is not a meaningless bouncing back and forth, because to win one has to find a way to prevail, using strategy and tactic: incredible how strategic it is, given the length.

It is a gamer&#039;s game, because strategies are not obvious, which I think is the main reason it hasn&#039;t had much success: people usually go to a new game if beauty is not revealed in the first two / three games.

It is by Andreas Steding, the same author of the more famous Hansa Teutonica, but IMHO it is a far more exciting and interesting game to play than HT. 

It offers an incredibly huge decision space for such a small package. Very low luck. Great replayability. More unique than original. A gem in a small box. 

Recommended. </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="2651" subtype="boardgame" collid="1289169">
	<name sortindex="1">Power Grid</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic173153.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic173153_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="40161" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="35811" />			<average value="7.98277" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.91129" />			<stddev value="1.33371" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2009-01-14 06:43:08" />
	<numplays>9</numplays>			<comment>Intuitive, so it can be taught to non gamers. Beautiful, but I find the choices somehow limited in scope.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="555" subtype="boardgame" collid="1316157">
	<name sortindex="5">The Princes of Florence</name>
		<yearpublished>2000</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1306997.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1306997_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="75"																	maxplaytime="100"																	playingtime="100"																	numowned="12860" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="12300" />			<average value="7.62697" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.48806" />			<stddev value="1.3425" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-01-03 02:03:15" />
	<numplays>11</numplays>			<comment>Very recommended game. A lot of strategies to win are possible. Different each time. Graphically very nice: at the end what players have built looks beautiful.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="36811" subtype="boardgame" collid="7130540">
	<name sortindex="5">The Princes of Machu Picchu</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic366663.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic366663_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="1431" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="1397" />			<average value="6.99384" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.48597" />			<stddev value="1.29827" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-25 11:37:22" />
	<numplays>10</numplays>			<comment>Beautiful underrated game. It gets nicer the more I play it.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="8045" subtype="boardgame" collid="1413670">
	<name sortindex="1">Princes of the Renaissance</name>
		<yearpublished>2003</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic181330.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic181330_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="1447" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="1629" />			<average value="7.4772" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.87027" />			<stddev value="1.46141" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2008-09-11 01:03:47" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>Very good game. I have played only 3 games up to now and my rating may still change after more games.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="127" subtype="boardgame" collid="1085394">
	<name sortindex="1">Princess Ryan&#039;s Star Marines</name>
		<yearpublished>1997</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic328153.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic328153_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="463" >
				<rating value="1">			<usersrated value="192" />			<average value="5.30937" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.44983" />			<stddev value="1.72908" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-01-01 03:54:54" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Probably the worst game I have ever played.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="3076" subtype="boardgame" collid="1084637">
	<name sortindex="1">Puerto Rico</name>
		<yearpublished>2002</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic158548.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic158548_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="150"																	playingtime="150"																	numowned="46020" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="41228" />			<average value="8.13179" />
			<bayesaverage value="8.03381" />			<stddev value="1.39539" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 13:52:03" />
	<numplays>34</numplays>			<comment>Great game. Different each time you play, fun, strategic, simple rules, short waiting times, your playing can influence all other players without king making. In a word: wonderful.

UPDATE March 2013
With the new games that came out in the last years I don&#039;t consider Puerto Rico any more at the top of my preferences. Still a good game and it has an important part in the boardgaming history (and in my heart). </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="19764" subtype="boardgame" collid="4681447">
	<name sortindex="1">PÜNCT</name>
		<yearpublished>2005</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic204410.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic204410_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="2068" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="1217" />			<average value="6.86559" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.35762" />			<stddev value="1.3938" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2009-09-21 08:01:40" />
	<numplays>10</numplays>			<comment>The game that I less like of the GIPF family</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="12" subtype="boardgame" collid="1086455">
	<name sortindex="1">Ra</name>
		<yearpublished>1999</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1603278.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1603278_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="12726" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="13940" />			<average value="7.47048" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.36247" />			<stddev value="1.35275" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-11-18 07:46:53" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Overrated. In my opinion one of Knizia&#039;s worst games. Just a lot of  different scoring mechanisms, mixed together.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="28143" subtype="boardgame" collid="6706823">
	<name sortindex="1">Race for the Galaxy</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic236327.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic236327_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="34920" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="29668" />			<average value="7.79479" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.71588" />			<stddev value="1.50256" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:42:23" />
	<numplays>33</numplays>			<comment>It has a lot of theoretical disadvantages, according to my taste: card driven, with luck, very little interaction between players. But it is very fun to play and addictive :). Its short playing time makes very common to play a lot of games in a row (and wanting more and more). So I like to play it. 

UPDATE November 2008
Rating moved from 8 to 7. It lost its appeal after a while and my wish to play it further decreased after the appearance of Dominion.

UPDATE April 2013
Rating moved from 7 to 6. My interest for card based games is lower at the moment.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="12962" subtype="boardgame" collid="5061653">
	<name sortindex="1">Reef Encounter</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic85905.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic85905_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="5049" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="4425" />			<average value="7.18164" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.94284" />			<stddev value="1.40521" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-08-11 08:52:55" />
	<numplays>14</numplays>			<comment>Nice game. Maybe a bit too tactical (I prefer strategical game). But nice and tense to play in any case.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="1513" subtype="boardgame" collid="7213021">
	<name sortindex="5">The Republic of Rome</name>
		<yearpublished>1990</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic487045.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic487045_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="300"																	maxplaytime="300"																	playingtime="300"																	numowned="4681" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="3092" />			<average value="7.55278" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.11019" />			<stddev value="1.75928" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-08-28 04:48:31" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>It is a game that was good at his time, but nowadays there are better games. Even without considering the terribly confusing way the rules are written. I can play on occasion, but it is very unlikely given the amount of better games that I prefer. </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="128882" subtype="boardgame" collid="18994540">
	<name sortindex="5">The Resistance: Avalon</name>
		<yearpublished>2012</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1398895.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1398895_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="5"																	maxplayers="10"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="15589" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="10794" />			<average value="7.82025" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.63962" />			<stddev value="1.47902" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="1" wishlistpriority="4" preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-10-31 03:41:56" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>Usually I don&#039;t like party games, but this is really a beautiful game. Much better than Werewolf.</comment>				<wishlistcomment>Number of Cards: 26
Mayday Sleeve Size: Chimera Sized 57.5 x 89 mm
Fantasy Flight Sleeve Size: Standard American 2 1/4&quot; x 3 1/2&quot; (56x87 MM)
</wishlistcomment></item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="30658" subtype="boardgame" collid="9342261">
	<name sortindex="1">Rise of Empires</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic434539.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic434539_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="2489" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="1716" />			<average value="7.14769" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.65063" />			<stddev value="1.37868" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:45:40" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>Good civilization game. Good, but not great IMHO. The main thing I don&#039;t like is that it seems to be more tactical then strategical, because the situation (especially on the board) changes too fast. 

Too much advantage for the attacker, especially for the last attacker in move order.

My rating takes into consideration that the game is quite long. Consequently, if I have to spend a lot of times on this game, there are other games with similar length, but with more strategical depth that I prefer much more to play.

But still worth to play, because there is a lot of good &quot;tension&quot; and it is nice to play.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="181" subtype="boardgame" collid="14223272">
	<name sortindex="1">Risk</name>
		<yearpublished>1959</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2395242.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2395242_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="25648" >
				<rating value="2">			<usersrated value="18792" />			<average value="5.57873" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.46436" />			<stddev value="1.63715" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:21:34" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>I used to play this when I was a teenager and there were not the wonderful boardgames that BGG is helping me to discover. I would not play it again now.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="875" subtype="boardgame" collid="1413671">
	<name sortindex="1">Roads &amp; Boats</name>
		<yearpublished>1999</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic713985.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic713985_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="240"																	maxplaytime="240"																	playingtime="240"																	numowned="3107" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="2200" />			<average value="7.73324" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.19124" />			<stddev value="1.64165" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-12-31 05:58:09" />
	<numplays>8</numplays>			<comment>I like this game, but I prefer other games of Splotter Spellen. Reason: it appears to me as a puzzle, searching through calculation for an optimum path, while I prefer games that do not have an optimum solution and that give more room to the intuitive and creative side of the mind.

But I may change my mind, if I manage to play it more. And it is surely a game that I like much more than average, in any case.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="121921" subtype="boardgame" collid="17085007">
	<name sortindex="1">Robinson Crusoe: Adventures on the Cursed Island</name>
		<yearpublished>2012</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1413154.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1413154_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="17581" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="11814" />			<average value="8.06602" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.87043" />			<stddev value="1.40325" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-10-05 01:39:29" />
	<numplays>7</numplays>			<comment>A cooperative thematic game is usually not the kind of game I prefer (with the noteworthy exception of Space Alert). Also there is a lot of luck involved that is usually another minus for me (but clearly a needed part of the design in this case, otherwise the game would be just uninteresting).

In spite of this I like this game and my family liked it even more.

It is a nice simulation with a lot going on.

Two drawbacks.

The first is that the rules are not smooth, especially the way they are written down. There are often small doubts coming up, even after playing many games (although the doubts tend to be only about tiny matters, even only after one game).

The second is that the game is tense and really making the players curious to know what is going to happen next, but after some games the game (and the way it is played) seems to be scripted, even if the author put much effort in giving a lot of materials (for example there are really a lot of event cards). 

But these are minor quibbles. The only reason my rating isn&#039;t higher is because it is not the kind of game that I prefer. I enjoyed very much the first games and you may like it even more if you like this sort of game more than me. For example my daughter likes it really a lot.

I advise you to play it, whatever your tastes, at the very least to enjoy the adventure-feeling of the game and the original mechanics. 

It is unique in its genre.

UPDATE October 2013
I played the game again after some time and I liked it less, especially because it is quite painful to refresh memory about all the micro-rules, especially because you need the FAQ to understand how some of them work. 

Besides IMHO the number of meaningful decisions is too little compared to luck and bookkeeping.

Consequently I have lowered the rating from 7 to 6 and possibly I would rate it even lower if it were not that my daughter really likes it: the thematic experience seems the strong point of this game, but it is not what I search for in a game, not only at least.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="99630" subtype="boardgame" collid="24438219">
	<name sortindex="1">Rolling Stock</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1898221.png</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1898221_t.png</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="240"																	maxplaytime="240"																	playingtime="240"																	numowned="124" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="85" />			<average value="7.55059" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.72064" />			<stddev value="1.67763" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-25 12:30:26" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>A perfect, beautiful game. It has very simple rules, 2 pages plus 2 pages of glossary, but at the same time it is incredibly hard to play and open to creative, personal play. The rules are so clear and so perfectly conceived, like tools that let the players build their own strategy. High interaction: the games are very tense.

It is a pure economical game, similar to the games of the 18xx family, but there are no railroads (they are simulated by synergies between companies): so there are no rails to build, there is only the stocking manipulation, the part that I prefer of the 18xx games. But there a lot of other  differences with the 18xx games, the main ones being: 1. the price goes down “before” selling a share, the price goes up “before” buying a share; 2. the company values goes up and down depending on the assets that belong to the company (in all 18xx games, as far as I know, the share price is usually related to the company paying or not dividends). These two apparently small changes have an enormous impact on the way the game is played.  Although I have played a lot of 18xx games,  Rolling Stock appears to me as more natural, avoiding tactical nasty moves, but at the same time leaving the possibility to strategic conflict between players.

The game is so hard that the first game can be quite terrible. It is a very unforgiving game. The other side of the coin is that it gives enormous pleasure to play it well, one can surprise the other players with clever moves. 

It is almost a cards game, because company and even share prices  are simulated by cards. It is a P&amp;P game that can be downloaded and easily assembled by yourself. The quality of the distributed material is very high. Besides the rules and the components, there are two handbooks: a user guide and an extremely useful “strategy” guide that is a pleasure to read. All for free! 

This is one of the best games I have ever played, one can feel the love and the care the author put into designing it, and it is free! (although its is possible to buy a copy at All-Aboard Games).

It has three scenarios with different playing time: the full advanced game lasts around 4 hours that pass very quickly, the others last less. The strategy handbook sums up the times that the game requires for each scenario depending on the number of players. I played the game in 3 and 4 players and it seems to scale very well.

If you like heavy games open to creative strategy, easy to learn and difficult to master, this is THE game for you. A masterpiece!</comment>				<wishlistcomment>PnP</wishlistcomment></item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="130390" subtype="boardgame" collid="17074787">
	<name sortindex="1">Ruhrschifffahrt 1769-1890</name>
		<yearpublished>2012</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1426929.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1426929_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="568" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="344" />			<average value="7.3548" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.09816" />			<stddev value="1.22292" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-25 11:43:35" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>A nice game: original and thematic (much more than the average Euro). It is not difficult to play: rules are not difficult; even if the handbook has the fame not to be well written, I had no problem in learning the game, apart for minor things. It is replayable. The only (somehow not small) minus is that the choices offered, although interesting both at the strategic and at the tactical level, are too few (there is not a huge decision space as I prefer in games).</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="144733" subtype="boardgame" collid="20565556">
	<name sortindex="1">Russian Railroads</name>
		<yearpublished>2013</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1772936.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1772936_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="6836" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="6035" />			<average value="7.84408" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.58666" />			<stddev value="1.26389" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-08-28 06:12:31" />
	<numplays>6</numplays>			<comment>A pure worker placement game. After reading the rules I thought that the game was too scripted and that there were too few choices. Instead the game is very exciting to play, in a surprising way, so much more than what I supposed reading the rules.

The reason I don&#039;t rate it even higher is that choices, although more &quot;personalized&quot; and creative than what I imagined reading the rules, are somehow a bit too &quot;easy&quot;, there is no possibilities of an extremely creative move, but a sum of optimization moves that may result in collecting a lot of points. Also I am not sure about replayability.

In any case a nice game, relaxing to play.

UPDATE
After 6 plays my wish to play again has become very low, the game is somehow too scripted for my tastes and replayabiility is low. Sold and lowered the rating.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="9217" subtype="boardgame" collid="7183129">
	<name sortindex="1">Saint Petersburg</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic246360.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic246360_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="9936" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="11512" />			<average value="7.34177" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.2202" />			<stddev value="1.31455" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:52:13" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Attempt of rating after only one game: it seems too mechanical and based on very tactical (and calculable) moves.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="13884" subtype="boardgame" collid="6409673">
	<name sortindex="5">The Scepter of Zavandor</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic133721.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic133721_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="2401" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="2215" />			<average value="7.05356" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.65818" />			<stddev value="1.51459" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-09-18 06:30:21" />
	<numplays>7</numplays>			<comment>Good game, with many paths to victory, but it requires a lot of tiring and repetitive calculations. I prefer other optimization games which don&#039;t have this disadvantage (e.g. Caylus, Goa, Agricola, etc.).</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="25021" subtype="boardgame" collid="15452634">
	<name sortindex="1">Sekigahara: The Unification of Japan</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1063508.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1063508_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="2807" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="1659" />			<average value="8.03024" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.25161" />			<stddev value="1.23989" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-07-28 11:59:47" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>Rating based on three games, it can still change.

I don&#039;t like wargames so much any more, because of the usually too low ratio between bookkeeping and strategic choices. There are exception, most notably Maria.

I bought Sekigahara because I imagined to be a different wargame, user-friendly and not needing an encyclopedic handbook. I was not disappointed. All expectation from this point of view have been satisfied.

The reason it doesn&#039;t score higher for me is that it seems to me more tactical than strategical. The way the cards are played is similar to Maria (and I like it) but because in Sekigahara a  player can keep only a small amount of cards in his hands, it doesn&#039;t allow a strategy based on them. There is in this way more luck-dependence and consequently a game based on the card draws, with optimization turn by turn, instead of a broader strategic view as I would have liked more.

Because of this and more generally for my not so strong wish to play it again, I consider the game good but not great. As said rating may change if / when I manage to play it more.</comment>				<wishlistcomment>When seconds edition is published. Sleeves needed (110):
Fantasy Flight Sleeve Size: Standard Card Game 2 1/2&quot; x 3 1/2&quot; (63.5 x 88 MM (the grey packs)

http://www.uplay.it/gioco_da_tavolo-50_Clear_Sleeves__Standard_Card_Game_Pack__63_5x88_mm_.html

http://www.egyp.it/accessori/1475-63-5x88-mm-premium-euro-b.html</wishlistcomment></item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="232" subtype="boardgame" collid="1085116">
	<name sortindex="1">Serenissima (first edition)</name>
		<yearpublished>1996</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic205658.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic205658_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="2617" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="1988" />			<average value="6.90197" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.48017" />			<stddev value="1.39467" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2007-11-06 12:03:38" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>Overrated game in my opinion. Choices are quite obvious and the rare attacks can ruin the best strategy (i.e. king making).</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="38054" subtype="boardgame" collid="7607920">
	<name sortindex="1">Snow Tails</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2574022.png</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2574022_t.png</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="4117" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="4149" />			<average value="6.98532" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.76797" />			<stddev value="1.18599" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2010-11-19 03:18:11" />
	<numplays>14</numplays>			<comment>Possibly the best race game I have ever played. Only I find the race games too tactical and boring after a while.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="38453" subtype="boardgame" collid="7232219">
	<name sortindex="1">Space Alert</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic384313.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic384313_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="13452" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="10220" />			<average value="7.58633" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.42841" />			<stddev value="1.55107" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2008-11-02 13:50:37" />
	<numplays>17</numplays>			<comment>See my review at http://www.boardgamegeek.com/thread/352838</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="22827" subtype="boardgame" collid="6778911">
	<name sortindex="1">StarCraft: The Board Game</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic265704.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic265704_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="6588" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="5544" />			<average value="7.34213" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.07131" />			<stddev value="1.54872" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:56:56" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>This was my last attempt to play/buy games of these kind... too much wargame-like for my current taste... rules are not flowing freely.. too many things to pay attention to... and, even without considering the effort and the time it requires, IMHO it offers less fun and much less interesting strategical choices than simpler (and nicer) games. It is only a matter of taste, so please look at games I like more to see if you are like me (then better to avoid this tile) or not :)

Sold.
</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="2338" subtype="boardgame" collid="1413672">
	<name sortindex="1">Starship Catan</name>
		<yearpublished>2001</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic149643.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic149643_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="5445" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="3599" />			<average value="6.85976" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.62017" />			<stddev value="1.30545" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:20:39" />
	<numplays>6</numplays>			<comment>Very well realized SF theme. The game is nice, but not exciting... you win &quot;quietly&quot;.
UPDATE
Rating went down, simply because the game is really not fun to play.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="166226" subtype="boardgame" collid="25050654">
	<name sortindex="5">The Staufer Dynasty</name>
		<yearpublished>2014</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2256945.png</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2256945_t.png</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="1263" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="925" />			<average value="7.28652" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.50707" />			<stddev value="1.191" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-25 11:05:33" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>Good but not great game. There are other games of the same author that I prefer (IMHO Kogge and Power&amp;Weakness are his masterpieces). 

It seems too much a race to collect points in various ways, around a area-control game. Too tactical for my taste. I would play it any time, but I prefer other games to it.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="37387" subtype="boardgame" collid="7130516">
	<name sortindex="1">Steel Driver</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic644894.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic644894_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="1956" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="1692" />			<average value="7.03825" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.58054" />			<stddev value="1.19334" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-10-31 15:28:45" />
	<numplays>8</numplays>			<comment>Nice game. Easy to play, but with interesting decisions and no luck.

UPDATE January 2008
I have decreased my rating after playing Chicago Express, which gives a similar experience, but which is much more exciting and beautiful to play.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="204" subtype="boardgame" collid="24543478">
	<name sortindex="1">Stephensons Rocket</name>
		<yearpublished>1999</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic192462.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic192462_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="2413" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="1996" />			<average value="6.89235" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.51958" />			<stddev value="1.36521" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-03-22 07:46:44" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>Theoretically this game offers everything that I like in games: no luck dependency, a lot of variability, a lot of interaction and so forth. But the appreciation of a game is not completely equal to the sum of the factors that shape our tastes, there is a more important factor, that is how much we like and want to play it. I find this game cold, not exciting to play. The game can go in one direction or another depending on the combined actions of the players and it seems a feast of the tactical moves and of king-making more than a strategy game of the sort I really like. Rating can go up if I play it more and I discover that it is nicer with many more plays, but I don&#039;t think I will soon, there are so many other games that I prefer.</comment>				<wishlistcomment>SLEEVES
Number of cards: 128

Arcane Tinmen sleeve size: Small - Red (AT-10404) - (44 x 68mm)
Fantasy Flight sleeve size: Mini European - Red (FFS02) - (1-11/16” x 2-5/8&quot; - 44 x 68mm)
Mayday sleeve size: Mini Euro - Light Blue - (45 x 68mm)
Swan PanAsia sleeve size: Mini Euro (SWN-006) - (45 x 70mm)
Ultra-Pro sleeve size: Mini European - Purple (82661) - (44 x 68mm)

Actually no sleeves needed, cards are only shares</wishlistcomment></item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="3731" subtype="boardgame" collid="1085373">
	<name sortindex="1">Stock Market Guru</name>
		<yearpublished>1997</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic243329.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic243329_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="1"																	maxplayers="10"																	minplaytime="240"																	maxplaytime="240"																	playingtime="240"																	numowned="165" >
				<rating value="2">			<usersrated value="80" />			<average value="5.78312" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.52257" />			<stddev value="1.70843" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2003-12-31 13:27:14" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>							</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="34635" subtype="boardgame" collid="6693701">
	<name sortindex="1">Stone Age</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1632539.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1632539_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="25187" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="24656" />			<average value="7.64378" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.55357" />			<stddev value="1.23146" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2008-09-12 02:31:22" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>Nice light game. With a bit of luck, which makes it relaxing to play. Some doubts about replayability: players tend to repeat the same patterns at every game, i.e. no new strategies to be discovered with time, but just a fine optimization of the (few) known ones. </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="9625" subtype="boardgame" collid="2060887">
	<name sortindex="1">Struggle of Empires</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1367165.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1367165_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="7"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="240"																	playingtime="240"																	numowned="3927" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="3225" />			<average value="7.53004" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.14386" />			<stddev value="1.45629" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2009-01-27 06:18:38" />
	<numplays>4</numplays>			<comment>Good area control game, offering a lot of choices and strategies. </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="35761" subtype="boardgame" collid="7232297">
	<name sortindex="1">Sylla</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic324935.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic324935_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="2756" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="1630" />			<average value="6.83109" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.42476" />			<stddev value="1.24211" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:16:49" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Attempt rating after one game. </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="475" subtype="boardgame" collid="1084534">
	<name sortindex="1">Taj Mahal</name>
		<yearpublished>2000</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic178427.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic178427_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="75"																	maxplaytime="100"																	playingtime="100"																	numowned="6412" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="5897" />			<average value="7.3617" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.15045" />			<stddev value="1.32297" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:00:30" />
	<numplays>11</numplays>			<comment>It was one of my preferred game at the time he came out. Now there are games I prefer, but still it is a nice game.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="108" subtype="boardgame" collid="4614868">
	<name sortindex="1">TAMSK</name>
		<yearpublished>1998</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic203773.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic203773_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="20"																	maxplaytime="20"																	playingtime="20"																	numowned="1720" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="1178" />			<average value="6.76385" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.27636" />			<stddev value="1.41519" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-12-26 02:37:10" />
	<numplays>36</numplays>			<comment>Nice idea. Good to play, even exceptional the first times you play it. After some games it became good, but not exceptional. Maybe a bit too simple.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="17161" subtype="boardgame" collid="4615024">
	<name sortindex="1">Tempus</name>
		<yearpublished>2006</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic218485.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic218485_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="2765" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="2350" />			<average value="6.53443" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.29012" />			<stddev value="1.39063" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-09-08 04:41:33" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Rating based on only one game. But enough to say that it didn&#039;t excite me at all (even if I can play it on occasions). I prefer Antike so much more that I don&#039;t know why I should play Tempus instead.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="120677" subtype="boardgame" collid="16080680">
	<name sortindex="1">Terra Mystica</name>
		<yearpublished>2012</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1356616.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1356616_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="150"																	playingtime="150"																	numowned="18455" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="16126" />			<average value="8.27663" />
			<bayesaverage value="8.13745" />			<stddev value="1.48774" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 04:49:06" />
	<numplays>24</numplays>			<comment>A perfect ten, now in my top ten.

There are so many things that I like. Just to mention a few of them:
- No luck, no hidden information.
- 14 different fantasy races that with small difference in their special rules allow for a great difference in playing the game. Besides allowing a huge variability and replayability, this attracts family and friends alike because the theme comes through.
- Variable set-up further enriches the replayability.
- Strategic deep decisions, with a lot of choices, some subtler ones shoving themselves with more plays.
- The way magic power is managed allows to recover from tactical mistakes as a consequence speeding up play (e.g. one coin is missing because of miscalculation, just transform a magic power in a coin and nothing is lost).
- Original in so many ways. I like very much the above mentioned use of magic power, besides so many other things. Maybe some other mechanisms have already been seen, but they are integrated in such a new way that this game is very different from what I have played before. There are games that are milestones, and this is one of them: in the story of boardgaming there is a point in time that divides the flux, before and after Terra Mystica, this is how much it is different IMHO.
- There is interaction without screwing up. I had read negative comments about the game being too much a solitary thing. I don&#039;t agree with this at all, it is a game where one has to watch very carefully at what the others are doing and react if one wants to win.

I can&#039;t imagine a gamer not liking Terra Mystica, unless he/she has some aversion for Euro games and stops beforehand trying to like or even trying to play it.

Very recommended!</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="25613" subtype="boardgame" collid="7130521">
	<name sortindex="1">Through the Ages: A Story of Civilization</name>
		<yearpublished>2006</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic236169.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic236169_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="240"																	maxplaytime="240"																	playingtime="240"																	numowned="14773" >
				<rating value="10">			<usersrated value="13799" />			<average value="8.19372" />
			<bayesaverage value="8.04604" />			<stddev value="1.63794" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 03:03:47" />
	<numplays>12</numplays>			<comment>Wonderful game, different each time, with a lot of different ways to win and a lot of choices.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="503" subtype="boardgame" collid="5303303">
	<name sortindex="1">Through the Desert</name>
		<yearpublished>1998</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic730576.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic730576_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="10100" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="10042" />			<average value="7.06845" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.95013" />			<stddev value="1.22756" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-08-09 09:23:50" />
	<numplays>16</numplays>			<comment>Good but less good than I thought given the enthusiastic comments here on BGG.
Update after more plays: nicer than I thought.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="21790" subtype="boardgame" collid="4614861">
	<name sortindex="1">Thurn and Taxis</name>
		<yearpublished>2006</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic115300.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic115300_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="14914" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="13821" />			<average value="7.14512" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.04407" />			<stddev value="1.16667" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:16:38" />
	<numplays>28</numplays>			<comment>I prefer heavy games, but this is my preferred &quot;light&quot; game so far. Much better than other more appreciated &quot;light&quot; games here on BGG (surely better than Ticket to Ride, just to make an example). Even better than Carcassone, the game that I used to propose to non gamers. Even heavy gamers can like it, since there are many different paths to victory and it is possible to have your own personal path to victory. There is luck, but less decisive than some critiques let intend (I think at least 90 % of the games the strongest player wins). I don&#039;t agree that it seems a multi player solitaire and that there is no interaction at all. The key point of the game is timing and a player can decide the length of the game in many different ways... so the timing itself is the interaction, and it is not a small one, IMHO.

UPDATE January 2009
I like the game less lately. And, even without considering the heavy games that I prefer, there are better light games that appeared lately which I would prefer to play (i.e. Dominion, Giants, Steel Driver).

UPDATE
After the appearance of Hansa Teutonica I think it is very unlikely that I will play this game again. So rating further decreased.

UPDATE March 2013
After the appearance of games like Terra Mystica or The Great Zimbabwe my wish to play this game is further decreased.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="33261" subtype="boardgame" collid="6722620">
	<name sortindex="1">Thurn and Taxis: All Roads Lead to Rome</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic308930.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic308930_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="2071" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="610" />			<average value="6.37946" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.898" />			<stddev value="1.37891" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2009-01-21 05:13:17" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>It makes the game a bit more fiddly and more luck dependent. I prefer the game without this expansion.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="9209" subtype="boardgame" collid="3694900">
	<name sortindex="1">Ticket to Ride</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic38668.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic38668_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="46150" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="38928" />			<average value="7.49812" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.41026" />			<stddev value="1.28277" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:20:21" />
	<numplays>10</numplays>			<comment>Good &quot;family&quot; game. It will replace for me Carcassone when I play with non gamers.

UPDATE
My tastes have changed a bit with the years passing, so I am much less attracted to play games like this at the moment, not even as a family game.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="42" subtype="boardgame" collid="1084513">
	<name sortindex="1">Tigris &amp; Euphrates</name>
		<yearpublished>1997</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2338267.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2338267_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="19339" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="18241" />			<average value="7.75222" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.63662" />			<stddev value="1.49063" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 13:56:21" />
	<numplays>7</numplays>			<comment>The best game by Reiner Knizia. An absolute masterpiece. Maybe only a gamers&#039; game, though.

UPDATE
Even if with some very strange feeling of time passing (this game used to be one of my top favorites), I think honestly I can&#039;t give this game a ten any more. There are games that I like more now. Maybe my tastes have changed a bit too, read my profile :)</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="54" subtype="boardgame" collid="1085242">
	<name sortindex="1">Tikal</name>
		<yearpublished>1999</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic178078.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic178078_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="14155" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="12247" />			<average value="7.35043" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.22571" />			<stddev value="1.19246" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-01-03 02:34:17" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Choices are quite obvious. You have just to calculate a bit and let ... other people wait for your move.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="35570" subtype="boardgame" collid="7226822">
	<name sortindex="1">Tinners&#039; Trail</name>
		<yearpublished>2008</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic464133.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic464133_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="3338" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="3205" />			<average value="7.34938" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.00196" />			<stddev value="1.15719" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2012-08-09 09:30:02" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>Not a bad game, but a bit flat. Also a bit complicated to play compared to what it gives you in terms of choices. Choices are in any case mostly tactical, no big strategies allowed. So playable, but there are better games.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="103" subtype="boardgame" collid="1085119">
	<name sortindex="1">Titan</name>
		<yearpublished>1980</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1083237.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1083237_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="240"																	playingtime="240"																	numowned="4717" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="3372" />			<average value="6.9881" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.6676" />			<stddev value="1.76898" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-10-31 15:31:16" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>A good AH classic. Just too long.

UPDATE
Really there are so many games that I would play instead of this at the moment: it is so unlikely that I will play it again, so I decreased the rating accordingly.
</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="42215" subtype="boardgame" collid="9098139">
	<name sortindex="1">Tobago</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic596625.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic596625_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="7889" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="7135" />			<average value="7.1329" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.97094" />			<stddev value="1.15391" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-04-01 01:48:47" />
	<numplays>21</numplays>			<comment>Nice light family game. I bought it because I wanted my 6 years old daughter to play, but it is still just a bit too difficult for her age. Nevertheless she wants to play and she likes it. 

Beautiful map and components! </comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="15510" subtype="boardgame" collid="3746996">
	<name sortindex="1">Tower of Babel</name>
		<yearpublished>2005</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic311199.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic311199_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="2325" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="2054" />			<average value="6.68942" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.37644" />			<stddev value="1.22071" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-11-18 07:47:01" />
	<numplays>7</numplays>			<comment>Not fun at all. The game is a cold collection of victory points. One of the worst Knizia&#039;s game IMO.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="73439" subtype="boardgame" collid="11641026">
	<name sortindex="1">Troyes</name>
		<yearpublished>2010</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic750583.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic750583_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="9449" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="9285" />			<average value="7.73632" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.56744" />			<stddev value="1.33321" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-11-08 02:16:31" />
	<numplays>13</numplays>			<comment>Beautiful and exciting game. 

High re-playability. Each time it is almost like a new game, since only some of the cards enter in play. 

It has dice, but luck is balanced by the many ways the players have to influence the dice rolls.

It is quite original and it requires a way to play that requires 3 games or more to appreciate it fully.

I would rate it higher if it were not for the still too much luck (e.g. the events can damage more a player than another) and that the clever tactical moves are more important than the strategy.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="12333" subtype="boardgame" collid="5453749">
	<name sortindex="1">Twilight Struggle</name>
		<yearpublished>2005</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic361592.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic361592_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="27969" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="21228" />			<average value="8.3208" />
			<bayesaverage value="8.20082" />			<stddev value="1.6453" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2008-11-18 02:44:30" />
	<numplays>5</numplays>			<comment>Fun and exciting game. Only reasons it doesn&#039;t score higher for me is that it is to much card- (and game-) driven. I prefer player-driven games. It is also a bit too long.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="134352" subtype="boardgame" collid="24975737">
	<name sortindex="1">Two Rooms and a Boom</name>
		<yearpublished>2013</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2335221.png</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2335221_t.png</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="6"																	maxplayers="30"																	minplaytime="15"																	maxplaytime="15"																	playingtime="15"																	numowned="2149" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="1218" />			<average value="7.13281" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.50704" />			<stddev value="1.72247" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-10-29 11:42:35" />
	<numplays>7</numplays>			<comment>In my opinion this game is more similar to Space Alert than to Werewolf (and The Resistance etc.). In the latter games one is never sure about who is foe or friend and so one plays by and for himself during the game, even if having common objectives. Instead in this game when one is certain that a player is of the same team, one can work together, really working cooperatively towards the same objective (unless it is a spy, one has to be careful even in this game). This feeling of team work is very beautiful.

It is true that this is common with other cooperative games. But there are some important differences: in this game one has to discover the allies; besides the team is divided in two rooms and there are added difficulties in communication because of this; last but not least, there is time pressure, there is a timer going on, so there is no possibility for a stronger player to influence the team strategy, as in other cooperative games, simply because there is no time for it. This is what this games has in common with Space Alert. But here there is another important difference: the cooperating team is not working against the game, but against another team, people that react to your plan in intelligent ways.

The way one can form the set of cards to be used in each play allows huge variations: each set of cards is almost like building a new game (there are very nice strange characters, some of them having personal objectives and changing completely the way the game is played). I find this very nice.

My rating is still temporary, I have to play other times for a preciser rating  (not always easy, because the game is best with large numbers of players, difficult to organize). I have played in one evening with a group and it was wonderful. Then I played a second time with another group and it was a bit less nice: I think that the mood and abilities of the people playing can greatly influence the enjoyment one can have in the game, but I want to play more to give more precise opinions.

What I can surely say already now is: this is a very nice game!</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="31999" subtype="boardgame" collid="7107802">
	<name sortindex="1">TZAAR</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic425478.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic425478_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="2486" >
				<rating value="8">			<usersrated value="1773" />			<average value="7.65683" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.02882" />			<stddev value="1.34921" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-01-02 07:15:39" />
	<numplays>53</numplays>			<comment>My preferred game of the project GIPF.

New strategies are discovered with more playing: there are layers and layers of strategies that are discovered with more experience, and the new strategies become &quot;bricks&quot; on which you can build new ones. 

Some strategies can be explained, some are subtle, belonging more to intuition than reasoning.

There are no fixed patterns in the game, any game is completely different from the other.

It is incredible that all this is packed in a game that usually lasts less than 15 minutes.

If you like abstracts (but even if you don&#039;t like them) you should try this. It is the masterpiece of Mr. Burm, IMHO.

UPDATE 5th November 2011
I lowered a bit the rating of this game, since any time  I want to play an abstract game at this moment I play Go. It is still a very good game if you want to play an abstract game other than Go.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="126163" subtype="boardgame" collid="16395460">
	<name sortindex="1">Tzolk&#039;in: The Mayan Calendar</name>
		<yearpublished>2012</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1413480.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1413480_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="90"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="15041" >
				<rating value="9">			<usersrated value="13214" />			<average value="7.97249" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.82241" />			<stddev value="1.26542" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-01-21 11:02:34" />
	<numplays>17</numplays>			<comment>Beautiful and original game. I don&#039;t agree with the criticisms I have read here on BGG, i.e. the game being yet-another worker placement game, with a new mechanic. The gears and the whole timing strategy ARE original and not only on the mechanical level, the entire game is different because of them.

Even without considering its &quot;originality&quot; factor, the game manages to integrate already seen mechanics in a beautiful whole.

The map and the components, and the way the gears are used, increase the WOW factor: this game is somehow an event in the hobby.

It is highly replayable. There are many paths to victory, and I like that one can try out different strategies every time one plays, and see how they work, as funny experiments.

It scales well (in 3 and 4 players at least, I have not tried the game in two, but I guess that it is also good in two).

The only reason it does not get a &quot;10&quot; from me is that I miss a bit the strategic depth and tension that I appreciate in my preferred games (e.g. Ora et Labora). Sometimes it seems that the small tactical moves and calculations have a bigger impact than I would like for the &quot;perfect&quot; strategy game.

In any case this game should be present in any collection, also because it is somehow a middle-weight game (possibly as middle weight game my preferred one) and so approachable to less &quot;hard&quot; gamers, with a short playing time (another plus, it seems that so much happens in approx. 90 minutes). So very easy to find occasions to play it.

Recommended.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="41002" subtype="boardgame" collid="9324011">
	<name sortindex="1">Vasco da Gama</name>
		<yearpublished>2009</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic495883.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic495883_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="3687" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="3409" />			<average value="7.34757" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.00781" />			<stddev value="1.3132" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-07-29 06:13:50" />
	<numplays>14</numplays>			<comment>Very original and beautiful game that requires a kind of reasoning different from any game I have played before. Surely worth trying, whatever your taste.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="27173" subtype="boardgame" collid="7265026">
	<name sortindex="1">Vikings</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1904581.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1904581_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="5743" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="6078" />			<average value="7.32259" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.11651" />			<stddev value="1.18921" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-10-31 13:36:41" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Good, but not great. Some very original mechanics.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="104006" subtype="boardgame" collid="15467006">
	<name sortindex="1">Village</name>
		<yearpublished>2011</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1115193.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic1115193_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="90"																	playingtime="90"																	numowned="12854" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="10512" />			<average value="7.59833" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.44377" />			<stddev value="1.17146" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-10-13 02:36:18" />
	<numplays>3</numplays>			<comment>Nice game with a nice theme, but too tactical and maybe too light for my current tastes. I would surely play it, but I would prefer a lot of other games to it.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="3307" subtype="boardgame" collid="3786194">
	<name sortindex="1">Wallenstein (first edition)</name>
		<yearpublished>2002</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic358092.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic358092_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="150"																	maxplaytime="150"																	playingtime="150"																	numowned="2561" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="3172" />			<average value="7.54734" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.15462" />			<stddev value="1.45754" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2009-11-11 09:51:11" />
	<numplays>12</numplays>			<comment>A very good mix of German style game and wargame. I liked it a lot when it came out, but I prefer other games now (e.g. Antike and Imperial).</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="9609" subtype="boardgame" collid="6709752">
	<name sortindex="1">War of the Ring (first edition)</name>
		<yearpublished>2004</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic725882.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic725882_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="10760" >
				<rating value="5">			<usersrated value="8416" />			<average value="7.84426" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.62384" />			<stddev value="1.6004" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-08-28 05:04:43" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>			<comment>Very good ideas and design, it catches the spirit of Tolkien books, BUT... it is not a user-friendly game to play: too long (especially the set-up), too much event cards driven (looking at the cards in your hands and deciding their use takes time and slows down playing: I prefer games in which variation is obtained through elegance of design instead of event cards), somehow &quot;heavy&quot; to play without such significant strategical choices that repays for the effort. When I discovered euro-games some years ago the first thing I appreciated was that their little playing time, elegant simple rules allow more strategic choices than wargames I used to play. And I stopped playing wargames simply because I found euro games funnier to play and at the same time more rewarding. I think that WofR is an hybrid between wargames and euro-games (a very good thing in itself), but too much pending towards the wargame kind for my tastes</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="490" subtype="boardgame" collid="1314121">
	<name sortindex="1">Warangel</name>
		<yearpublished>2000</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic477996.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic477996_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="294" >
				<rating value="4">			<usersrated value="223" />			<average value="7.68549" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.77607" />			<stddev value="1.94763" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-12-08 15:23:58" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>&quot;Old-fashioned&quot; game. In my opinion there are better games nowadays</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="620" subtype="boardgame" collid="1086451">
	<name sortindex="1">We the People</name>
		<yearpublished>1994</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic289191.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic289191_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="120"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="1451" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="1022" />			<average value="7.34911" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.56627" />			<stddev value="1.44418" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:10:02" />
	<numplays>0</numplays>							</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="491" subtype="boardgame" collid="1086452">
	<name sortindex="1">Web of Power</name>
		<yearpublished>2000</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic209855.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic209855_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="3"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="50"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="2610" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="2927" />			<average value="7.32509" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.94277" />			<stddev value="1.3378" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-06-26 12:23:32" />
	<numplays>18</numplays>			<comment>So much going on in such a short game. Strategy and not luck determines the winner. 

UPDATE march 2013
My tastes have changed a bit, also because new games are appeared, which have learned and improved from their ancestors... now I would play other games instead of this, so I decreased the rating</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="925" subtype="boardgame" collid="5132435">
	<name sortindex="1">Werewolf</name>
		<yearpublished>1986</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2453810.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2453810_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="8"																	maxplayers="24"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="60"																	playingtime="60"																	numowned="3442" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="3549" />			<average value="6.71932" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.47957" />			<stddev value="1.93694" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2014-10-13 02:55:40" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>One of the very few (if not the only) party game that I appreciate.

UPDATE
I have lowered the rating after playing The Resistance: Avalon that is a better game and that I would always prefer to this.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="165401" subtype="boardgame" collid="25616833">
	<name sortindex="1">Wir sind das Volk!</name>
		<yearpublished>2014</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2239210.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2239210_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="150"																	maxplaytime="150"																	playingtime="150"																	numowned="1426" >
				<rating value="6">			<usersrated value="629" />			<average value="8.0197" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.65781" />			<stddev value="1.14458" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-10-25 11:26:57" />
	<numplays>2</numplays>			<comment>I wanted so much to like this game, I was almost sure that it would be great, considering that one of the authors has designed Maria, which I consider a masterpiece.

I had only one fear: the cards. I don&#039;t like games that are guided by cards. I don&#039;t like Twilight Struggle too much for this reason. I hoped that this game would have been different. Instead... sadly while playing it I had the same feeling: cards are guiding players. There is not the huge decision space that I search in games. I like when players are in control of their destiny and can make up creative paths to victory. Here it seems to me that strategy is guided by the tactical choices related to the  available cards, while I prefer games in which strategy is leading, games in which players are in full control.

This is a tentative rating, I have to play it more. But I am not so eager to bring it to the table. It is a good game (as twilight Struggle is), but I prefer other games.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="310" subtype="boardgame" collid="1325044">
	<name sortindex="1">Wizard&#039;s Quest</name>
		<yearpublished>1979</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic157002.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic157002_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="6"																	minplaytime="180"																	maxplaytime="180"																	playingtime="180"																	numowned="2649" >
				<rating value="3">			<usersrated value="1172" />			<average value="6.14284" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.87032" />			<stddev value="1.37857" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2007-11-06 12:06:28" />
	<numplays>1</numplays>			<comment>Similar to Risk, with a fantasy theme. Lightly better that Risk, but I don&#039;t like it.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="7854" subtype="boardgame" collid="3141048">
	<name sortindex="1">YINSH</name>
		<yearpublished>2003</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic178413.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic178413_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="5293" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="4554" />			<average value="7.6531" />
			<bayesaverage value="7.35596" />			<stddev value="1.34209" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2009-01-21 05:05:15" />
	<numplays>84</numplays>			<comment>Good abstract game. It seems to me to be more tactical than strategical.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="528" subtype="boardgame" collid="4614782">
	<name sortindex="1">ZÈRTZ</name>
		<yearpublished>1999</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic205477.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic205477_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="2"																	minplaytime="30"																	maxplaytime="30"																	playingtime="30"																	numowned="3961" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="3033" />			<average value="7.32011" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.94686" />			<stddev value="1.32417" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2011-12-26 02:34:48" />
	<numplays>105</numplays>			<comment>The game I most like of the project GIPF, and one of the best abstract I have ever played. It is different any time. New strategies are discovered, even after tens of games. I have played it more than 80 times now, and I am still discovering something new. Very tense game play.
UPDATE 16 oct 2007: I still like this game, but GIPF is at the moment my preferred game of the Project GIPF
UPDATE 8 sep 2008: my preferred GIPF game is now TZAAR (but I still like ZÈRTZ a lot)</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="160495" subtype="boardgame" collid="25294351">
	<name sortindex="1">ZhanGuo</name>
		<yearpublished>2014</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2242246.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic2242246_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="4"																	minplaytime="60"																	maxplaytime="120"																	playingtime="120"																	numowned="1548" >
				<rating value="7">			<usersrated value="1058" />			<average value="7.69848" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.7932" />			<stddev value="1.23041" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="1" prevowned="0" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2015-03-08 06:57:54" />
	<numplays>8</numplays>			<comment>Even if the rules are not difficult, it could be hard to play because there are so many interrelated ways to collect VP. One can think for a very long time if searching the optimum path. Fortunately in a finite normal time it is virtually impossible to calculate everything (which would make the game more puzzle-like and less interesting for me), and one has to count on broader strategic choices.

What I like a bit less is that some tactical moves are still too important and that the luck of the draw may have some weight. 

What I dislike is the mechanic of the card numbers (one has to compare the number of the played card with the number of the previously played card to see if they get the bonus): fortunately this mechanic has a much lower impact than I was expecting after reading the rules (but it is still the only thing of this game that I actively dislike). 

What I like most is the interaction, to arrive first to get something or the area control fights with the governors and so on. It is really tense and interesting, especially  with 4 players.</comment>				</item>
		<item objecttype="thing" objectid="27588" subtype="boardgame" collid="7107804">
	<name sortindex="1">Zooloretto</name>
		<yearpublished>2007</yearpublished>			<image>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic187388.jpg</image>
		<thumbnail>//cf.geekdo-images.com/images/pic187388_t.jpg</thumbnail>
		<stats minplayers="2"																	maxplayers="5"																	minplaytime="45"																	maxplaytime="45"																	playingtime="45"																	numowned="12669" >
				<rating value="2">			<usersrated value="10573" />			<average value="6.89201" />
			<bayesaverage value="6.77888" />			<stddev value="1.17278" />
			<median value="0" />		</rating>
			</stats>	<status own="0" prevowned="1" fortrade="0" want="0" wanttoplay="0" wanttobuy="0" wishlist="0"  preordered="0" lastmodified="2013-03-30 14:21:54" />
	<numplays>13</numplays>			<comment>A game with little choices and too luck dependent, so not the sort of game I prefer. But its &quot;disadvantages&quot; have a nice side effect: even my small daughter can play it! This is the only reason I play it, even too much (it is getting really boring).</comment>				</item>
		
</items>